<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.1.2//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.1.2/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY accordion SYSTEM "accordion.xml">
<!ENTITY agnes SYSTEM "agnes.xml">
<!ENTITY athena SYSTEM "athena.xml">
<!ENTITY auld-lang-syne SYSTEM "auld_lang_syne.xml">
<!ENTITY aunt-mary SYSTEM "aunt_mary.xml">
<!ENTITY backbone SYSTEM "backbone.xml">
<!ENTITY bakers-dozen SYSTEM "bakers_dozen.xml">
<!ENTITY bakers-game SYSTEM "bakers_game.xml">
<!ENTITY beleaguered-castle SYSTEM "beleaguered_castle.xml">
<!ENTITY block-ten SYSTEM "block_ten.xml">
<!ENTITY bristol SYSTEM "bristol.xml">
<!ENTITY camelot SYSTEM "camelot.xml">
<!ENTITY canfield SYSTEM "canfield.xml">
<!ENTITY carpet SYSTEM "carpet.xml">
<!ENTITY chessboard SYSTEM "chessboard.xml">
<!ENTITY clock SYSTEM "clock.xml">
<!ENTITY cover SYSTEM "cover.xml">
<!ENTITY cruel SYSTEM "cruel.xml">
<!ENTITY diamond-mine SYSTEM "diamond_mine.xml">
<!ENTITY doublets SYSTEM "doublets.xml">
<!ENTITY eagle-wing SYSTEM "eagle-wing.xml">
<!ENTITY easthaven SYSTEM "easthaven.xml">
<!ENTITY eight-off SYSTEM "eight_off.xml">
<!ENTITY elevator SYSTEM "elevator.xml">
<!ENTITY escalator SYSTEM "escalator.xml">
<!ENTITY first-law SYSTEM "first_law.xml">
<!ENTITY fortress SYSTEM "fortress.xml">
<!ENTITY fortunes SYSTEM "fortunes.xml">
<!ENTITY forty-thieves SYSTEM "forty_thieves.xml">
<!ENTITY fourteen SYSTEM "fourteen.xml">
<!ENTITY freecell SYSTEM "freecell.xml">
<!ENTITY gaps SYSTEM "gaps.xml">
<!ENTITY gay-gordons SYSTEM "gay_gordons.xml">
<!ENTITY giant SYSTEM "giant.xml">
<!ENTITY glenwood SYSTEM "glenwood.xml">
<!ENTITY gold-mine SYSTEM "gold_mine.xml">
<!ENTITY golf SYSTEM "golf.xml">
<!ENTITY gypsy SYSTEM "gypsy.xml">
<!ENTITY helsinki SYSTEM "helsinki.xml">
<!ENTITY hopscotch SYSTEM "hopscotch.xml">
<!ENTITY isabel SYSTEM "isabel.xml">
<!ENTITY jumbo SYSTEM "jumbo.xml">
<!ENTITY jamestown SYSTEM "jamestown.xml">
<!ENTITY kansas SYSTEM "kansas.xml">
<!ENTITY king-albert SYSTEM "king_albert.xml">
<!ENTITY kings-audience SYSTEM "kings_audience.xml">
<!ENTITY klondike SYSTEM "klondike.xml">
<!ENTITY labyrinth SYSTEM "labyrinth.xml">
<!ENTITY lady-jane SYSTEM "lady_jane.xml">
<!ENTITY maze SYSTEM "maze.xml">
<!ENTITY monte-carlo SYSTEM "monte_carlo.xml">
<!ENTITY napoleons-tomb SYSTEM "napoleons_tomb.xml">
<!ENTITY neighbor SYSTEM "neighbor.xml">
<!ENTITY odessa SYSTEM "odessa.xml">
<!ENTITY osmosis SYSTEM "osmosis.xml">
<!ENTITY peek SYSTEM "peek.xml">
<!ENTITY pileon SYSTEM "pileon.xml">
<!ENTITY plait SYSTEM "plait.xml">
<!ENTITY poker SYSTEM "poker.xml">
<!ENTITY quatorze SYSTEM "quatorze.xml">
<!ENTITY royal-east SYSTEM "royal_east.xml">
<!ENTITY saratoga SYSTEM "saratoga.xml">
<!ENTITY scorpion SYSTEM "scorpion.xml">
<!ENTITY scuffle SYSTEM "scuffle.xml">
<!ENTITY seahaven SYSTEM "seahaven.xml">
<!ENTITY sir-tommy SYSTEM "sir_tommy.xml">
<!ENTITY spider SYSTEM "spider.xml">
<!ENTITY spider-three-decks SYSTEM "spider_three_decks.xml">
<!ENTITY spiderette SYSTEM "spiderette.xml">
<!ENTITY straight-up SYSTEM "straight_up.xml">
<!ENTITY streets-and-alleys SYSTEM "streets_and_alleys.xml">
<!ENTITY ten-across SYSTEM "ten_across.xml">
<!ENTITY terrace SYSTEM "terrace.xml">
<!ENTITY thieves SYSTEM "thieves.xml">
<!ENTITY thirteen SYSTEM "thirteen.xml">
<!ENTITY thumb-and-pouch SYSTEM "thumb_and_pouch.xml">
<!ENTITY treize SYSTEM "treize.xml">
<!ENTITY triple-peaks SYSTEM "triple_peaks.xml">
<!ENTITY union-square SYSTEM "union_square.xml">
<!ENTITY valentine SYSTEM "valentine.xml">
<!ENTITY westhaven SYSTEM "westhaven.xml">
<!ENTITY whitehead SYSTEM "whitehead.xml">
<!ENTITY will-o-the-wisp SYSTEM "will_o_the_wisp.xml">
<!ENTITY yield SYSTEM "yield.xml">
<!ENTITY yukon SYSTEM "yukon.xml">
<!ENTITY zebra SYSTEM "zebra.xml">
<!ENTITY definitions SYSTEM "definitions.xml">
<!ENTITY legal SYSTEM "legal.xml">
<!ENTITY appversion "2.12">
<!ENTITY manrevision "2.12">
<!ENTITY date "July 2005">
<!ENTITY app "<application>AisleRiot</application>">
<!ENTITY appname "AisleRiot">
]>
<!--
      (Do not remove this comment block.)
  Maintained by the GNOME Documentation Project
  http://developer.gnome.org/projects/gdp
  Template version: 2.0 beta
  Template last modified Feb 12, 2002
-->
<!-- =============Document Header ============================= -->
<book id="index" lang="el">
<!-- please do not change the id; for translations, change lang to -->
<!-- appropriate code -->
  <bookinfo>
    <title>Εγχειρίδιο του <application>AisleRiot</application></title>

    <abstract role="description">
      <para>Η πασιέντζα AisleRiot είναι μια συλλογή περισσότερων από 80 παιχνιδιών με χαρτιά, γραμμένη στη Scheme, τη γλώσσα σεναρίων του GNOME.</para>
    </abstract>

    <copyright>
      <year>2001</year>
      <holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
    </copyright>
<!-- translators: uncomment this:

  <copyright>
   <year>2002</year>
   <holder>ME-THE-TRANSLATOR (Latin translation)</holder>
  </copyright>

   -->
<!-- An address can be added to the publisher information.  If a role is
     not specified, the publisher/author is the same for all versions of the
     document.  -->
    <publisher>
      <publishername>Έργο Τεκμηρίωσης GNOME</publishername>
    </publisher>

     <legalnotice id="legalnotice">
	<para>Δίνεται άδεια για αντιγραφή, διανομή και/ή τροποποίηση του εγγράφου υπό τους όρους της GNU Free Documentation License (GFDL), Έκδοση 1.1 ή μεταγενέστερη εκδιδόμενη από το Ίδρυμα Ελεύθερου Λογισμικού χωρίς Σταθερά Εδάφια, χωρίς Εξώφυλλα Κειμένου, και χωρίς Οπισθόφυλλα Κειμένου. Μπορείτε να βρείτε ένα αντίγραφο της GFDL σε αυτόν τον <ulink type="help" url="ghelp:fdl">σύνδεσμο</ulink> ή στο αρχείο COPYING-DOCS που διανεμήθηκε με αυτόν τον οδηγό.</para>
         <para>Αυτή η τεκμηρίωση είναι μέρος της συλλογής τεκμηρίωσης του GNOME όπως διανέμεται υπό τους όρους της GFDL. Εάν επιθυμείτε να διανείμετε αυτή την τεκμηρίωση ξεχωριστά από την συλλογή, μπορείτε να το κάνετε εάν η τεκμηρίωση συνοδεύεται από αντίγραφο της άδειας (GFDL) όπως περιγράφεται στον τομέα 6 της άδειας.</para>

	<para>Πολλά από τα ονόματα που χρησιμοποιούνται από εταιρίες για να ξεχωρίσουν τα προϊόντα και τις υπηρεσίες είναι σήματα κατατεθέν. Όπου αυτά τα ονόματα εμφανίζονται στην τεκμηρίωση GNOME, και τα μέλη της ομάδας τεκμηρίωσης GNOME έχουν γνώση αυτών, τότε αυτά αναγράφονται με κεφαλαίους χαρακτήρες ή με αρχικούς κεφαλαίους χαρακτήρες.</para>

	<para>ΤΟ ΈΓΓΡΑΦΟ ΚΑΙ ΤΡΟΠΟΠΟΙΗΜΕΝΕΣ ΕΚΔΟΣΕΙΣ ΑΥΤΟΥ ΠΑΡΕΧΟΝΤΑΙ ΥΠΟ ΤΟΥΣ ΟΡΟΥΣ ΤΗΣ GNU FREE DOCUMENTATION LICENSE ΜΕ ΤΗΝ ΠΕΡΑΙΤΕΡΩ ΔΙΕΥΚΡΙΝΙΣΗ ΟΤΙ: <orderedlist>
		<listitem>
		  <para>Η ΤΕΚΜΗΡΙΩΣΗ ΑΥΤΗ ΠΑΡΕΧΕΤΑΙ "ΩΣ ΕΧΕΙ", ΧΩΡΙΣ ΚΑΜΙΑ ΕΓΓΥΗΣΗ ΟΤΙ ΜΠΟΡΕΙ ΝΑ ΕΞΥΠΗΡΕΤΗΣΕΙ ΚΑΠΟΙΟ ΣΚΟΠΟ Η ΟΤΙ ΕΙΝΑΙ ΧΩΡΙΣ ΣΦΑΛΜΑ. ΟΛΟΚΛΗΡΗ Η ΕΥΘΥΝΗ ΓΙΑ ΤΗΝ ΠΟΙΟΤΗΤΑ, ΑΚΡΙΒΕΙΑ ΚΑΙ ΛΕΙΤΟΥΡΓΙΚΟΤΗΤΑ ΤΗΣ ΤΕΚΜΗΡΙΩΣΗΣ Ή ΠΑΡΑΛΛΑΓΩΝ ΑΥΤΗΣ ΑΝΗΚΕΙ ΣΕ ΕΣΑΣ. ΕΑΝ Η ΤΕΚΜΗΡΙΩΣΗ ΑΥΤΗ Ή ΠΑΡΑΛΛΑΓΗ ΑΥΤΗΣ ΕΙΝΑΙ ΛΑΘΟΣ ΚΑΤΑ ΚΑΠΟΙΟ ΤΡΟΠΟ ΕΣΕΙΣ ΑΝΑΛΑΜΒΑΝΕΤΕ ΤΗΝ ΕΥΘΥΝΗ ΤΗΣ ΔΙΟΡΘΩΣΗΣ. Η ΑΠΑΛΛΑΓΗ ΕΥΘΥΝΗΣ ΠΟΥ ΣΥΝΟΔΕΥΕΙ ΑΥΤΗ ΤΗΝ ΤΕΚΜΗΡΙΩΣΗ ΕΙΝΑΙ ΑΝΑΠΟΣΠΑΣΤΟ ΚΟΜΜΑΤΙ ΑΥΤΗΣ. ΚΑΜΙΑ ΧΡΗΣΗ ΤΗΣ ΤΕΚΜΗΡΙΩΣΗΣ Ή ΠΑΡΑΛΛΑΓΩΝ ΑΥΤΗΣ ΔΕΝ ΕΠΙΤΡΕΠΕΤΑΙ ΠΑΡΑ ΜΟΝΟ ΕΑΝ ΣΥΝΟΔΕΥΕΤΑΙ ΑΠΟ ΤΗΝ ΑΠΑΛΛΑΓΗ ΕΥΘΥΝΗΣ.</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
		  <para>ΣΕ ΚΑΜΙΑ ΠΕΡΙΠΤΩΣΗ ΚΑΙ ΥΠΟ ΚΑΜΙΑ ΝΟΜΙΚΗ ΣΥΝΘΗΚΗ, ΕΙΤΕ ΜΕΣΩ ΣΥΜΒΟΛΑΙΩΝ Ή ΑΛΛΙΩΣ, ΔΕΝ ΕΥΘΥΝΟΝΤΑΙ Ο ΣΥΓΓΡΑΦΕΑΣ, Ο ΔΙΑΝΟΜΕΑΣ, Η ΑΛΛΟΣ ΣΥΝΥΠΕΥΘΥΝΟΣ ΓΙΑ ΤΗΝ ΣΥΓΓΡΑΦΗ ΤΗΣ ΤΕΚΜΗΡΙΩΣΗΣ, ΓΙΑ ΕΜΜΕΣΕΣ Η ΑΜΕΣΕΣ, ΤΥΧΑΙΕΣ Ή ΜΗ ΖΗΜΙΕΣ ΠΑΝΤΩΣ ΦΥΣΕΩΣ ΠΟΥ ΠΡΟΕΡΧΟΝΤΑΙ ΑΠΟ ΤΗΝ ΧΡΗΣΗ ΤΗΣ ΤΕΚΜΗΡΙΩΣΗΣ ΚΑΙ/Ή ΠΑΡΑΛΛΑΓΩΝ ΑΥΤΗΣ ΑΚΟΜΑ ΚΑΙ ΕΑΝ ΕΧΕΙ ΥΠΑΡΞΕΙ ΠΡΟΕΙΔΟΠΟΙΗΣΗ ΓΙΑ ΤΗΝ ΠΙΘΑΝΟΤΗΤΑ ΥΠΑΡΞΗΣ ΤΕΤΟΙΩΝ ΖΗΜΙΩΝ.</para>
		</listitem>
	  </orderedlist></para>
  </legalnotice>


   <!-- This file  contains link to license for the documentation (GNU FDL), and
        other legal stuff such as "NO WARRANTY" statement. Please do not change
	any of this. -->

    <authorgroup>
      <author role="maintainer">
	<firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
	<surname>Yuen</surname>
	<affiliation>
          <orgname>Έργο Τεκμηρίωσης GNOME</orgname>
          <address> <email>zana@webwynk.net</email> </address>
	</affiliation>
      </author>
      <othercredit role="additional material">
        <firstname>Telsa</firstname>
        <surname>Gwynne</surname>
        <affiliation>
          <address><email>hobbit@aloss.ukuu.org.uk</email></address>
        </affiliation>
      </othercredit>

<!-- This is appropriate place for other contributors: translators,
      maintainers,  etc. Commented out by default.
       <othercredit role="translator">
	<firstname>Latin</firstname>
	<surname>Translator 1</surname>
	<affiliation>
	  <orgname>Latin Translation Team</orgname>
	  <address> <email>translator@gnome.org</email> </address>
	</affiliation>
	<contrib>Latin translation</contrib>
      </othercredit>
-->
    </authorgroup>
	
	<releaseinfo revision="2.26" role="review"/>

    <revhistory>
      <revision>
	<revnumber>Εγχειρίδιο του AisleRiot V2.12</revnumber>
	<date>Ιούλιος 2005</date>
	<revdescription>
	  <para role="author">Rosanna Yuen <email>zana@webwynk.net</email></para>
	  <para role="publisher">Έργο Τεκμηρίωσης GNOME</para>
	</revdescription>
      </revision>
    </revhistory>

    <releaseinfo>Αυτό το εγχειρίδιο περιγράφει την έκδοση 2.12 του AisleRiot.</releaseinfo>
    <!-- The following feedback information only applies to appliactions
    listed in bugzilla.gnome.org and bugzilla.ximian.com. For other
    applications, please provide your own feedback info or remove thsi
    section altogether -->
    <legalnotice>
      <title>Ανάδραση</title>
      <para>Για να αναφέρετε ένα σφάλμα ή να κάνετε μια πρόταση σχετικά με την εφαρμογή <application>AisleRiot</application> ή αυτό το εγχειρίδιο, ακολουθήστε τις οδηγίες στη σελίδα <ulink url="ghelp:gnome-feedback" type="help">Σελίδα ανάδρασης του GNOME</ulink>.</para>
<!-- Translators may also add here feedback address for translations -->
    </legalnotice>
  </bookinfo>

<!-- ============= Document Body ============================= -->
<!-- ============= Introduction ============================== -->
<chapter id="intro">
    <title>Εισαγωγή</title>

    <indexterm zone="index">
      <primary>AisleRiot</primary>
    </indexterm>

    <para>Η πασιέντζα <application>AisleRiot</application> (γνωστή και ως Solitaire) είναι μια συλλογή παιχνιδιών με χαρτιά που παίζονται εύκολα με το ποντίκι. Για τη δική σας ψυχαγωγία γράψαμε τα παιχνίδια στη Scheme, τη γλώσσα σεναρίων του GNOME.</para>
</chapter>

<chapter id="general-information">
<!--  <sect1info>
    <copyright>
      <year>2002</year>
      <holder>Telsa Gwynne</holder>
    </copyright>
    <author>
      <firstname>Telsa</firstname>
      <surname>Gwynne</surname>
    </author>
    <address>
      <email>hobbit@aloss.ukuu.org.uk</email>
    </address>
  </sect1info> -->



 <title>Παίζοντας <application>AisleRiot</application></title>

 <para>Χρησιμοποιήστε το ποντίκι για να μετακινείτε τα φύλλα. Κάντε κλικ σε ένα φύλλο και σύρτε το. Αφήστε το πλήκτρο του ποντικιού για να τοποθετήσετε το φύλλο όπου επιθυμείτε.</para>
 <para>Εναλλακτικά, μπορείτε να μετακινήσετε ένα φύλλο αν κάνετε μία φορά κλικ πάνω του για να το επιλέξετε, και κάνετε δεύτερη φορά κλικ για να το τοποθετήσετε. Για να ενεργοποιήσετε αυτή τη μέθοδο μετακίνησης των φύλλων, επιλέξτε <menuchoice><guimenu>Έλεγχος</guimenu><guimenuitem>Κλικ για μετακίνηση</guimenuitem></menuchoice>. Η μέθοδος αυτή ίσως αποδειχθεί ταχύτερη και λιγότερο κουραστική για το χέρι σας, καθώς δε θα χρειάζεται να κρατάτε πατημένα τα πλήκτρα του ποντικιού. Μπορεί όμως να σας πάρει λίγο καιρό μέχρι να τη συνηθίσετε.</para>
 <para>Αν ένα φύλλο μπορεί να μετακινηθεί στις βάσεις, δε χρειάζεται να το σύρετε. Αν κάνετε διπλό κλικ πάνω του, θα μετακινηθεί αυτόματα. Αν υπάρχει μία σειρά από φύλλα που μπορούν να μετακινηθούν στις βάσεις, συνήθως μετακινούνται όλα με μία κίνηση.</para>
 <para>Αν κάνετε διπλό κλικ σε ένα φύλλο, θα το στείλετε στις βάσεις, αν είναι δυνατή αυτή η κίνηση. Αυτή η δυνατότητα είναι ιδιαίτερα χρήσιμη αν βρίσκεστε στο τέλος του παιχνιδιού και θέλετε να καθαρίσετε γρήγορα το ταμπλό.</para>
 <para>Σε παιχνίδια όπου μοιράζονται φύλλα από τη μάνα, όταν τελειώσουν τα φύλλα, μπορείτε να κάνετε κλικ στην κενή στοίβα της μάνας για να ξαναρχίσετε να τα μοιράζετε. Θυμηθείτε ότι σε ορισμένα παιχνίδια ο αριθμός των φορών που επιτρέπεται να ξαναμοιράσετε αυτά τα φύλλα είναι περιορισμένος. Σε αυτές τις περιπτώσεις, στο κάτω μέρος του παραθύρου εμφανίζεται το μήνυμα <guilabel>Μοιρασιές που απομένουν</guilabel>.</para>
 <para>Είναι επίσης χρήσιμο να γνωρίζετε ότι, αν ένα ανοιχτό φύλλο δε φαίνεται καλά επειδή το καλύπτει το επόμενο φύλλο της στήλης, τότε μπορείτε να κάνετε δεξί κλικ πάνω του για να το φέρετε στο προσκήνιο.</para>
 <para>Σε ορισμένα παιχνίδια υπάρχουν επιλογές που σας επιτρέπουν να αλλάξετε τον τρόπο παιχνιδιού. Για παράδειγμα, στο Κλόνταϊκ (κλασική πασιέντζα του εφτά) η μάνα μπορεί να ανοίγει είτε ένα ένα όλα τα φύλλα, είτε κάθε τρίτο φύλλο. Σε αυτά τα παιχνίδια υπάρχει ένα επιπλέον μενού, με τίτλο το όνομα του παιχνιδιού. Οι κανόνες του παιχνιδιού μπορούν να αλλάξουν μόνο στην αρχή μιας παρτίδας. Κατά τη διάρκεια της παρτίδας, το μενού αυτό παραμένει απενεργοποιημένο.</para>
 <para>Μπορείτε να δείτε στατιστικές για το πόσο καλά τα πηγαίνετε σε συγκεκριμένο παιχνίδι αν επιλέξετε <guimenuitem>Στατιστικά</guimenuitem> στο μενού <guimenu>Παιχνίδι</guimenu>. Για να προσμετρηθεί μία παρτίδα στα στατιστικά, θα πρέπει ο παίκτης να έχει κάνει τουλάχιστον μία κίνηση. Οι στατιστικές παρέχονται για καθαρά ψυχαγωγικούς λόγους. Επειδή υπάρχουν πολλοί τρόποι για να κλέψει κανείς, καλύτερα να μην κάνετε συγκρίσεις.</para>
</chapter>

<chapter id="games">
    <title>Τα παιχνίδια</title>

  <sect1 id="Accordion"><!--<sect1info>
		<copyright>
			<year>2008</year>
			<holder>Ed Sirett</holder>
		</copyright>
		<author>
			<firstname>Ed</firstname>
			<surname>Sirett</surname>
		</author>
		<address><email>ed @makewrite.demon.co.uk</email></address>
	</sect1info>-->

	<title>Ακορντεόν</title>

  <para>Γράφτηκε από τον Ed Sirett</para>

          <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


	<informaltable>
		<tgroup cols="2">
			<tbody>
	<row>
		<entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
		<entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>

	<row>
		<entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
		<entry>Πενήντα τέσσερις θέσεις. Πέντε γραμμές με εννέα και μία με εφτά θέσεις. Τα φύλλα που μοιράζονται τοποθετούνται ανοιχτά, ένα ανά θέση. Ουσιαστικά, οι θέσεις υποτίθεται ότι είναι όλες συνεχόμενες· οι γραμμές απλά σας επιτρέπουν να χωρέσετε όλα τα φύλλα στο ταμπλό. Δηλαδή, η θέση στο δεξί άκρο μιας γραμμής υποτίθεται ότι βρίσκεται στα αριστερά της θέσης στο αριστερό άκρο της από κάτω γραμμής.</entry>
	</row>
			</tbody>
		</tgroup>
	</informaltable>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

  <para>Απομάκρυνση όλων των φύλλων εκτός από ένα.</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

  <para>Τα φύλλα μετακινούνται ένα ένα. Ένα φύλλο μπορεί να μετακινηθεί μία ή τρεις θέσεις αριστερά, αν στις θέσεις αυτές βρίσκεται φύλλο της ίδιας αξίας ή φυλής. Το φύλλο που καλύπτεται κατ' αυτόν τον τρόπο βγαίνει από το παιχνίδι. Για να καλυφθεί το κενό που (ενδεχομένως) δημιουργείται, όλα τα φύλλα στα δεξιά του κενού μετακινούνται αυτόματα μία θέση αριστερά. Αν κάνετε διπλό κλικ σε ένα φύλλο, θα μετακινηθεί  τρεις θέσεις αριστερά, ή, αν δεν επιτρέπεται αυτή η κίνηση, μία θέση αριστερά.</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

  <para>
    Each card removed scores 1 point. 
  </para>
  <para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 51</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

  <para>Το παιχνίδι αυτό είναι δύσκολο. Προσπαθήστε να βρείτε δύο ή τρία φύλλα της ίδιας αξίας στην τελευταία ή προτελευταία γραμμή. Προσπαθήστε να μη μετακινήσετε κανένα φύλλο αυτής της αξίας. Στο τέλος, τοποθετήστε αυτά τα φύλλα το ένα πάνω στο άλλο για να κερδίσετε την παρτίδα.</para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Agnes"><!--<sect1info>
  	<copyright>
  	 <year>2001</year>
  	 <holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
  	</copyright>
  	<author>
  	 <firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
  	 <surname>Yuen</surname>
  	</author>
  	<address><email>zana@webwynk.net</email></address>
	</sect1info>-->

	<title>Αγνή</title>

  <para>Γράφτηκε από τη Rosanna Yuen</para>

  <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>

  <informaltable>
    <tgroup cols="2">
      <tbody>
	<row>
	  <entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
	  <entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Μάνα</entry>
	  <entry>Η στοίβα πάνω αριστερά. Όταν ολοκληρωθεί η μοιρασιά, τα υπόλοιπα φύλλα τοποθετούνται εδώ. Τα φύλλα μοιράζονται ανά εφτά, ένα για κάθε στήλη.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Βάσεις</entry>
	  <entry>Οι τέσσερις στοίβες πάνω δεξιά, μία για κάθε φυλή. Τα φύλλα μπαίνουν με αριθμητική σειρά και, αν χρειαστεί, ο Άσσος ακολουθεί το Ρήγα. Στην αρχή της παρτίδας μοιράζεται ένα φύλλο στην πρώτη βάση. Στις υπόλοιπες στοίβες μπαίνουν τα άλλα τρία φύλλα της ίδιας αξίας.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
    <entry>Εφτά στήλες. Αρχικά, στην πρώτη στήλη μοιράζεται ένα φύλλο ανοιχτό και στις υπόλοιπες από ένα φύλλο κλειστό. Στη συνέχεια μοιράζεται ένα φύλλο ανοιχτό στη δεύτερη στήλη και κλειστά φύλλα στις υπόλοιπες. Η διαδικασία επαναλαμβάνεται μέχρις ότου η τελευταία στήλη αποκτήσει εφτά φύλλα. Οι στήλες συμπληρώνονται με φύλλα ίδιου χρώματος σε φθίνουσα σειρά. Μπορείτε να μετακινείτε ομάδες φύλλων. Οι στήλες που αδειάζουν μπορούν να γεμίσουν μόνο με την επόμενη μοιρασιά από τη μάνα.</entry>
	</row>
      </tbody>
    </tgroup>
  </informaltable>
  </sect2>

  <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>
  <para>Μετακίνηση όλων των φύλλων στις βάσεις</para>
  </sect2>
  <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>
  <para>Τα φύλλα στο ταμπλό τοποθετούνται ανά χρώμα και σε αύξουσα σειρά. Φύλλα που έχουν μπει στη σωστή σειρά μπορούν να μετακινηθούν όλα μαζί ως ενιαίο σύνολο.</para>
  <para>Σε κάθε νέα μοιρασιά, η μάνα μοιράζει ένα φύλλο σε κάθε στήλη του ταμπλό. Αν τελειώσουν τα φύλλα της μάνας, δεν μπορεί να γίνει νέα μοιρασιά.</para>
  <para>Στις βάσεις τα φύλλα τοποθετούνται ανά φυλή και με αύξουσα σειρά· αν χρειαστεί, ο Άσσος ακολουθεί το Ρήγα. Τα φύλλα στις βάσεις παραμένουν στο παιχνίδι. Αν κάνετε διπλό κλικ σε ένα φύλλο στο ταμπλό, το φύλλο θα ανέβει στις βάσεις, εφόσον επιτρέπεται η κίνηση.</para>
</sect2>
  <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>
  <para>Κάθε φύλλο που μπαίνει στις βάσεις αντιστοιχεί σε 1 βαθμό.</para>
  <para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 52</para>
</sect2>

  <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>
  <para>Όπου είναι δυνατόν, προσπαθήστε να συμπληρώνετε τις στήλες ανά φυλή. Προσπαθήστε να πετύχετε όσο το δυνατόν υψηλότερη βαθμολογία, γιατί είναι πολύ δύσκολο να κερδίσετε την παρτίδα.</para>
</sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Athena">
<!--<sect1info>
    <copyright>
      <year>2001</year>
      <holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
    </copyright>
    <author>
      <firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
      <surname>Yuen</surname>
    </author>
    <address><email>zana@webwynk.net</email></address>
  </sect1info>-->

  <title>Αθηνά</title>

  <para>Γράφτηκε από τον Alan Horkan, με βάση το έργο του Jonathan Blandford</para>
  <!-- Also documented by Alan Horkan (2005)
  based on documentation by Rosann Yuen -->
  <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>

  <informaltable>
    <tgroup cols="2"><tbody>
	<row>
	  <entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
	  <entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Μάνα</entry>
	  <entry>Η στοίβα πάνω αριστερά. Όταν ολοκληρωθεί η μοιρασιά, τα υπόλοιπα φύλλα τοποθετούνται εδώ. Τα φύλλα της μάνας ανοίγουν ένα ένα και τοποθετούνται στο σωρό. Ο παίκτης δύο επιπλέον μοιρασιές.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Σωρός</entry>
	  <entry>Προέρχονται από τη μάνα. Μπορείτε να παίξετε το πάνω φύλλο.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Βάσεις</entry>
	  <entry>Οι τέσσερις στοίβες πάνω δεξιά. Τα φύλλα τοποθετούνται ανά φυλή και σε αύξουσα σειρά, από τον Άσσο στο Ρήγα. Σε κάθε βάση, το πάνω φύλλο μπορεί να παιχθεί στο ταμπλό.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
	  <entry>Εφτά στήλες και τέσσερις γραμμές. Τα χαρτιά της πρώτης γραμμής είναι κλειστά, της δεύτερης ανοιχτά, της τρίτης κλειστά και της τέταρτης και τελευταίας, ανοιχτά. Ουσιαστικά η Αθηνά έχει τους ίδιους κανόνες με το Κλόνταϊκ (κλασική πασιέντζα του εφτά). Τα φύλλα στο ταμπλό τοποθετούνται με φθίνουσα σειρά και σε εναλλασσόμενο χρώμα. Μπορείτε να μετακινείτε ομάδες φύλλων. Αν μία στήλη είναι κενή, μπορείτε να τοποθετήσετε μόνο Ρήγα ή ομάδα φύλλων που ξεκινάει με Ρήγα.</entry>
	</row>
      </tbody>
    </tgroup>
  </informaltable>
  </sect2>
  <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>
  <para>Μετακίνηση όλων των φύλλων στις βάσεις</para>
  </sect2>
  <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>
  <para>Μπορείτε να τοποθετείτε φύλλα στο ταμπλό με φθίνουσα σειρά και σε εναλλασσόμενο χρώμα. Μπορείτε να μετακινείτε ομάδες φύλλων. Αν μία στήλη είναι κενή, μπορείτε να τοποθετήσετε μόνο Ρήγα ή ομάδα φύλλων που ξεκινάει με Ρήγα.</para>
  <para>Τα φύλλα της μάνας μοιράζονται ένα ένα και τοποθετούνται στο σωρό. Μπορείτε να παίζετε το πάνω φύλλο στο σωρό. Αν αδειάσει η μάνα, όλα τα φύλλα του σωρού μετακινούνται στη μάνα, χωρίς να αλλάξει η σειρά. Συνολικά επιτρέπονται τρεις μοιρασιές.</para>
  <para>Στις βάσεις τα φύλλα μπαίνουν ανά φυλή και σε αύξουσα σειρά από τον Άσσο στο Ρήγα. Τα φύλλα στις βάσεις δε βγαίνουν από το παιχνίδι. Αν κάνετε διπλό κλικ σε ένα φύλλο, το φύλλο αυτό θα ανέβει στις βάσεις, εφόσον επιτρέπεται η κίνηση.</para>

<!-- TODO 
  <sect2><title>Options</title>
  <para>
    Three card deals: If checked, the Stock will deal three each time.
    Otherwise, the Stock will deal singly into the Waste.
  </para>
  <para>
    King Only: If checked empty space may be filled with Kings or 
    groups of cards starting with a King only.  
  </para>
-->
  </sect2>
  <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>
  <para>Κάθε φύλλο που τοποθετείται στις βάσεις αντιστοιχεί σε 1 βαθμό.</para>
  <para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 52</para>
  </sect2>
  <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>
  <para>Μην εγκαταλείπετε εύκολα! Αν κινδυνεύετε να χάσετε, δοκιμάστε όλες τις πιθανές κινήσεις με τη σειρά. Ορισμένες φορές μπορείτε να χρησιμοποιήσετε φύλλα από τις βάσεις σε συνδυασμό με την αναδιάταξη φύλλων στο ταμπλό για να αποκαλύψετε επιπλέον κλειστά φύλλα.</para>
  </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Auld_Lang_Syne">  <!--<sect1info>
    <copyright>
      <year>1999</year>
      <holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
    </copyright>
    <author>
      <firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
      <surname>Yuen</surname></author>
    <address><email>zana@webwynk.net</email></address>
  </sect1info>-->

  <title>Auld Lang Syne</title>

  <para>Γράφτηκε από τη Rosanna Yuen</para>

          <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


  <informaltable>
    <tgroup cols="2">
      <tbody>
	<row>
	  <entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
	  <entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Μάνα</entry>
	  <entry>Η στοίβα πάνω αριστερά. Στην αρχή της παρτίδας περιλαμβάνει όλα τα φύλλα εκτός από τους Άσσους. Αν κάνετε κλικ στη μάνα, θα μοιραστεί ένα φύλλο σε κάθε στοίβα της ρεζέρβας.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Βάσεις</entry>
	  <entry>Οι τέσσερις στοίβες στο πάνω μέρος, δεξιά από τη μάνα. Τοποθετήστε έναν Άσσο σε καθεμιά από τις βάσεις για να ξεκινήσετε την παρτίδα. Στις βάσεις τα φύλλα τοποθετούνται με αύξουσα σειρά ανεξαρτήτως φυλής.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Ρεζέρβα</entry>
	  <entry>Οι τέσσερις στοίβες κάτω από τις βάσεις. Κάθε φορά που κάνετε κλικ στη μάνα, μοιράζεται ένα φύλλο σε κάθε μία στοίβα της ρεζέρβας. Παίζετε πάντα το πάνω φύλλο κάθε στοίβας. Τα φύλλα της ρεζέρβας επιτρέπεται να τοποθετούνται μόνο στις βάσεις.</entry>
	</row>
      </tbody>
    </tgroup>
  </informaltable>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

  <para>Μετακίνηση όλων των φύλλων στις βάσεις.</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

  <para>Η παρτίδα ξεκινά με το μοίρασμα τεσσάρων φύλλων στη ρεζέρβα. Αν μπορείτε, μετακινήστε τα φύλλα αυτά στις βάσεις. Επαναλάβετε τη διαδικασία μέχρι να τελειώσουν τα φύλλα της μάνας και να εξαντληθούν οι διαθέσιμες κινήσεις. Ένα παρόμοιο, αλλά πιο εύκολο, παιχνίδι είναι το Scuffle.</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

  <para>Κάθε φύλλο που απομακρύνεται αντιστοιχεί σε 1 βαθμό.</para>
  <para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 52</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

  <para>Πιστεύετε στη θεά Τύχη; Αν και αυτό το παιχνίδι απαιτεί περισσότερη δεξιοτεχνία σε σχέση με το Ρολόι, η μόνη απαιτούμενη δεξιότητα είναι η προσοχή σας. Ο,τι πρέπει για χάζεμα.</para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Aunt_Mary"><!--<sect1info>
    <copyright>
      <year>2005</year>
      <holder>Alan Horkan</holder>
    </copyright>
    <author>
      <firstname>Alan</firstname>
      <surname>Horkan</surname>
    </author>
  </sect1info>-->

  <title>Θεία Μαίρη</title>

          <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


  <informaltable>
    <tgroup cols="2"><tbody>
	<row>
	  <entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
	  <entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Μάνα</entry>
	  <entry>Η στοίβα πάνω αριστερά. Όταν ολοκληρωθεί η μοιρασιά, τα υπόλοιπα φύλλα τοποθετούνται εδώ. Τα φύλλα της μάνας ανοίγουν ένα ένα και τοποθετούνται στο σωρό. Ο παίκτης δύο επιπλέον μοιρασιές.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Σωρός</entry>
	  <entry>Προέρχονται από τη μάνα. Μπορείτε να παίξετε το πάνω φύλλο.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Βάσεις</entry>
	  <entry>Οι τέσσερις στοίβες πάνω δεξιά. Τα φύλλα τοποθετούνται ανά φυλή και σε αύξουσα σειρά, από τον Άσσο στο Ρήγα. Σε κάθε βάση, το πάνω φύλλο μπορεί να παιχθεί στο ταμπλό.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
	  <entry>Έξι στήλες. Αρχικά, μοιράζεται ένα φύλλο ανοιχτό στην πρώτη στήλη και από ένα κλειστό φύλλο στις υπόλοιπες. Στη συνέχεια, μοιράζεται ένα ανοιχτό φύλλο στις δύο πρώτες στήλες και κλειστά στις υπόλοιπες. Μετά, ανοιχτά φύλλα στις τρεις πρώτες στήλες και κλειστά στις υπόλοιπες, κ.ο.κ. Επαναλάβετε μέχρι την έκτη γραμμή, όπου θα έχετε έξι ανοιχτά φύλλα. Μπορείτε να τοποθετείτε φύλλα στο ταμπλό με φθίνουσα σειρά και σε εναλλασσόμενο χρώμα. Μπορείτε να μετακινείτε ομάδες φύλλων. Αν μία στήλη είναι κενή, μπορείτε να τοποθετήσετε μόνο Ρήγα ή ομάδα φύλλων που ξεκινάει με Ρήγα.</entry>
	</row>
      </tbody>
    </tgroup>
  </informaltable>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

  <para>Μετακίνηση όλων των φύλλων στις βάσεις</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

  <para>Μπορείτε να τοποθετείτε φύλλα στο ταμπλό με φθίνουσα σειρά και σε εναλλασσόμενο χρώμα. Μπορείτε να μετακινείτε ομάδες φύλλων. Αν μία στήλη είναι κενή, μπορείτε να τοποθετήσετε μόνο Ρήγα ή ομάδα φύλλων που ξεκινάει με Ρήγα.</para>
  <para>Τα φύλλα της μάνας μοιράζονται ένα ένα και τοποθετούνται στο σωρό. Μπορείτε να παίζετε το πάνω φύλλο στο σωρό. Αν αδειάσει η μάνα, όλα τα φύλλα του σωρού μετακινούνται στη μάνα, χωρίς να αλλάξει η σειρά. Συνολικά επιτρέπονται τρεις μοιρασιές.</para>
  <para>Στις βάσεις τα φύλλα μπαίνουν ανά φυλή και σε αύξουσα σειρά από τον Άσσο στο Ρήγα. Τα φύλλα στις βάσεις δε βγαίνουν από το παιχνίδι. Αν κάνετε διπλό κλικ σε ένα φύλλο, το φύλλο αυτό θα ανέβει στις βάσεις, εφόσον επιτρέπεται η κίνηση.</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

  <para>Κάθε φύλλο που τοποθετείται στις βάσεις αντιστοιχεί σε 1 βαθμό.</para>
  <para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 52</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

  <para>Η Θεία Μαίρη είναι εξαιρετικά δύσκολο παιχνίδι και βγαίνει σπάνια. Η πρόκληση εδώ δεν είναι να κερδίσετε, αλλά να δείτε μέχρι πού μπορείτε να φτάσετε.</para>
  </sect2>
</sect1>

<!-- TODO Aunt Mary is a Klondike variation, refernce and crosslink them -->

  <sect1 id="Backbone"><!--<sect1info>
    <copyright>
      <year>2005</year>
      <holder>Vincent Povirk</holder>
    </copyright>
    <author>
      <firstname>Vincent</firstname>
      <surname>Povirk</surname>
    </author>
    <address><email>madewokherd@gmail.com</email></address>
  </sect1info>-->

  <title>Ραχοκοκαλιά</title>

  <para>Γράφτηκε από το Vincent Povirk</para>

          <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


  <informaltable>
    <tgroup cols="2"><tbody>
	<row>
	  <entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
	  <entry>Δύο τράπουλες</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Μάνα</entry>
	  <entry>Η στοίβα κάτω από τις βάσεις, αριστερά. Αφού μοιραστούν φύλλα στο ταμπλό και τη ρεζέρβα, τα υπόλοιπα φύλλα τοποθετούνται στη μάνα. Τα φύλλα της μάνας ανοίγουν ένα ένα και τοποθετούνται στο σωρό. Ο παίκτης δικαιούται μία επιπλέον μοιρασιά.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Σωρός</entry>
	  <entry>Η στοίβα δεξιά της μάνας. Τα φύλλα στο σωρό προέρχονται από τη μάνα. Μπορείτε να παίξετε το πάνω φύλλο.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Βάσεις</entry>
	  <entry>Οι οχτώ στοίβες πάνω δεξιά. Τα φύλλα τοποθετούνται ανά φυλή και σε αύξουσα σειρά, από τον Άσσο στο Ρήγα.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Ρεζέρβα</entry>
	  <entry>Δύο στήλες με εννέα φύλλα η καθεμία και ένα φύλλο ανάμεσα στις δύο στήλες. Τα ελεύθερα φύλλα μπορούν να τοποθετηθούν οπουδήποτε, αλλά όχι σε κενές θέσεις του ταμπλό.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
	  <entry>Οχτώ στοίβες, τέσσερις σε κάθε πλευρά της ρεζέρβας. Στην αρχή της παρτίδας μοιράζεται ένα φύλλο σε κάθε στοίβα. Στο ταμπλό μπορείτε να τοποθετείτε φύλλα ανά φυλή και σε φθίνουσα σειρά. Αν μία στήλη είναι κενή, μπορείτε να τοποθετήσετε όποιο φύλλο θέλετε. Μπορείτε να μετακινείτε μόνο ένα φύλλο κάθε φορά.</entry>
	</row>
      </tbody>
    </tgroup>
  </informaltable>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

  <para>Μετακίνηση όλων των φύλλων στις βάσεις</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

  <para>Στο ταμπλό μπορείτε να τοποθετείτε φύλλα ανά φυλή και σε φθίνουσα σειρά. Μπορείτε να μετακινείτε μόνο ένα φύλλο κάθε φορά. Αν μία στήλη είναι κενή, μπορείτε να τοποθετήσετε όποιο φύλλο θέλετε, εκτός από τα φύλλα της ρεζέρβας. </para>
  <para>Τα φύλλα της μάνας ανοίγουν ένα ένα και τοποθετούνται στο σωρό. Μπορείτε να παίζετε το πάνω φύλλο του σωρού. Αν αδειάσει η μάνα, όλα τα φύλλα του σωρού μετακινούνται στη μάνα, χωρίς να αλλάξει η σειρά. Συνολικά επιτρέπονται δύο μοιρασιές.</para>
  <para>Στις βάσεις τα φύλλα μπαίνουν ανά φυλή και σε αύξουσα σειρά, από τον Άσσο στο Ρήγα. Τα φύλλα που τοποθετούνται στις βάσεις βγαίνουν από το παιχνίδι. Αν κάνετε διπλό κλικ σε ένα φύλλο, το φύλλο θα ανέβει στις βάσεις, εφόσον επιτρέπεται η κίνηση.</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

  <para>Κάθε φύλλο που τοποθετείται στις βάσεις αντιστοιχεί σε 1 βαθμό.</para>
  <para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 104</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

  <para>Αν υπάρχουν κενές θέσεις στο ταμπλό, μπορείτε να τις εκμεταλλευτείτε για να μετακινήσετε στοίβες πολλαπλών φύλλων. Προσοχή, αν υπάρχουν Ρήγες στη ρεζέρβα, ο μόνος τρόπος να τους απομακρύνετε είναι να τους τοποθετήσετε σε μία από τις βάσεις, πάνω από Ντάμα.</para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Bakers_Dozen"><!--<sect1info>
	  <copyright>
	   <year>2001</year>
	   <holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
	  </copyright>
	  <author>
	   <firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
	   <surname>Yuen</surname>
	  </author>
	  <address><email>zana@webwynk.net</email></address>
	</sect1info>-->

	<title>Δώδεκα καρβέλια</title>

  <para>Γράφτηκε από τη Rosanna Yuen</para>

          <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


  <informaltable>
    <tgroup cols="2">
      <tbody>
	<row>
	  <entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
	  <entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Βάσεις</entry>
	  <entry>Οι τέσσερις στοίβες στο πάνω μέρος. Τα φύλλα τοποθετούνται ανά φυλή και σε αύξουσα σειρά, από τον Άσσο στο Ρήγα. Σε κάθε βάση, το πάνω φύλλο μπορεί να παιχθεί στο ταμπλό.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
    <entry>Δεκατρείς στήλες. Τέσσερα φύλλα ανοιχτά σε κάθε στήλη. Οι Ρήγες μετακινούνται αυτόματα στην κορυφή της αντίστοιχης στήλης.</entry>
	</row>
      </tbody>
    </tgroup>
  </informaltable>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

  <para>Μετακίνηση όλων των φύλλων στις βάσεις</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

  <para>Σε κάθε στήλη του ταμπλό το πάνω φύλλο μπορεί να μετακινηθεί σε άλλη στήλη αν η αξία του είναι μικρότερη κατά ένα από το πάνω φύλλο της νέας στήλης. Η φυλή δεν παίζει ρόλο εδώ. Αν μία στήλη του ταμπλό αδειάσει, δεν μπορεί να ξαναγεμίσει.</para>
  <para>Στις βάσεις τα φύλλα τοποθετούνται ανά φυλή και με αύξουσα σειρά, από τον Άσσο στο Ρήγα. Τα φύλλα στις βάσεις παραμένουν στο παιχνίδι. Αν κάνετε διπλό κλικ σε ένα φύλλο στο ταμπλό, το φύλλο θα ανέβει στις βάσεις, εφόσον επιτρέπεται η κίνηση.</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

  <para>Κάθε φύλλο που μπαίνει στις βάσεις αντιστοιχεί σε 1 βαθμό.</para>
  <para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 52</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

  <para>Προσπαθήστε να μη "θάβετε" τα φύλλα μικρής αξίας και να μην αφήνετε τις στήλες του ταμπλό να αδειάσουν.</para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Bakers_Game"><!--<sect1info>
	  <copyright>
	   <year>2001</year>
	   <holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
	  </copyright>
	  <author>
	   <firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
	   <surname>Yuen</surname>
	  </author>
	  <address><email>zana@webwynk.net</email></address>
	</sect1info>-->

	<title>Φούρναρης</title>

  <para>Γράφτηκε από τη Rosanna Yuen</para>

          <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


  <informaltable>
    <tgroup cols="2">
      <tbody>
	<row>
	  <entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
	  <entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Βάσεις</entry>
	  <entry>Τέσσερις στοίβες πάνω δεξιά. Τα φύλλα τοποθετούνται ανά φυλή και σε αύξουσα σειρά, από τον Άσσο στο Ρήγα.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Ρεζέρβες</entry>
	  <entry>Τέσσερις θέσεις πάνω αριστερά. Κάθε ρεζέρβα μπορεί να περιέχει ένα μόνο φύλλο.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
	  <entry>Οχτώ στήλες στο χώρο κάτω από τις βάσεις και τις ρεζέρβες. Τα φύλλα του ταμπλό μοιράζονται ανοιχτά, από εφτά στις πρώτες τέσσερις γραμμές και από έξι στις τέσσερις τελευταίες.</entry>
	</row>
      </tbody>
    </tgroup>
  </informaltable>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

  <para>Μετακίνηση όλων των φύλλων στις βάσεις</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

  <para>Τα φύλλα στο ταμπλό τοποθετούνται ανά φυλή και σε φθίνουσα σειρά. Μπορείτε να μετακινείτε μόνο το πάνω φύλλο ή ομάδα φύλλων κάθε στήλης. Για να μετακινηθεί μια ομάδα φύλλων, ο αριθμός των φύλλων της δεν πρέπει να είναι μεγαλύτερος από τον αριθμό των ελεύθερων θέσεων της ρεζέρβας συν ένα. Οι κενές θέσεις του ταμπλό μπορούν να συμπληρωθούν μόνο με Ρήγα ή με ομάδα που ξεκινά με Ρήγα.</para>
  <para>Τα φύλλα στις βάσεις τοποθετούνται ανά φυλή και σε αύξουσα σειρά, από τον Άσσο στο Ρήγα. Αν και τα φύλλα των βάσεων θεωρητικά παραμένουν στο παιχνίδι, η χρήση τους δεν βοηθάει σε κάτι.</para>
  <para>Το πάνω φύλλο κάθε στήλης του ταμπλό μπορεί να τοποθετηθεί σε μια ελεύθερη θέση της ρεζέρβας. Τα φύλλα αυτά παραμένουν διαθέσιμα και μπορούν να μετακινηθούν στο ταμπλό ή τις βάσεις.</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

  <para>Κάθε φύλλο που τοποθετείται στις βάσεις αντιστοιχεί σε 1 βαθμό.</para>
  <para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 52</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

  <para>Μετακινήστε τα φύλλα στις βάσεις το συντομότερο δυνατόν. Η διατήρησή τους στο ταμπλό απλά δυσχεραίνει τις κινήσεις σας.</para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Beleaguered_Castle">  <!--<sect1info>
    <copyright>
      <year>2001</year>
      <holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
    </copyright>
    <author>
      <firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
      <surname>Yuen</surname>
    </author>
    <address><email>zana@webwynk.net</email></address>
  </sect1info>-->

  <title>Πολιορκημένο κάστρο</title>

  <para>Γράφτηκε από τη Rosanna Yuen</para>

          <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


  <informaltable>
    <tgroup cols="2">
      <tbody>
	<row>
	  <entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
	  <entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Βάσεις</entry>
	  <entry>Τέσσερις στοίβες στη μεσαία στήλη. Εδώ τοποθετούνται οι τέσσερις Άσσοι πριν το ανακάτεμα των φύλλων. Στις βάσεις τοποθετούνται φύλλα ανά φυλή και σε αύξουσα σειρά, από τον Άσσο στο Ρήγα. Το πάνω φύλλο κάθε βάσης μπορεί να επιστρέψει στο ταμπλό.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
	  <entry>Οχτώ ομάδες (τέσσερις αριστερά και τέσσερις δεξιά από τις βάσεις). Τα φύλλα μοιράζονται ανοιχτά και κατά τέτοιο τρόπο ώστε όλα τα φύλλα να είναι ορατά και κάθε μία από τις οχτώ ομάδες να περιέχει έξι φύλλα.</entry>
	</row>
      </tbody>
    </tgroup>
  </informaltable>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

  <para>Μετακίνηση όλων των φύλλων στις βάσεις</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

  <para>Στο ταμπλό μπορείτε να τοποθετείτε φύλλα σε φθίνουσα σειρά ανεξαρτήτως φυλής. Μπορείτε να μετακινείτε μόνο ένα φύλλο κάθε φορά. Αν μία θέση είναι κενή, μπορείτε να την καλύψετε με όποιο φύλλο θέλετε.</para>
  <para>Τα φύλλα στις βάσεις τοποθετούνται ανά φυλή και με αύξουσα σειρά.</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

  <para>Κάθε φύλλο που τοποθετείται στις βάσεις (εκτός από τους Άσσους) αντιστοιχεί σε 1 βαθμό.</para>
  <para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 48</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

  <para>Φροντίστε να προχωρείτε εξίσου όλες τις βάσεις. Προσπαθήστε να αδειάσετε μία από τις ομάδες του ταμπλό.</para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Block_Ten"><!--<sect1info>
	  <copyright>
	   <year>2001</year>
	   <holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
	  </copyright>
	  <author>
	   <firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
	   <surname>Yuen</surname>
	  </author>
	  <address><email>zana@webwynk.net</email></address>
	</sect1info>-->

	<title>Μπλοκ στο δέκα</title>

  <para>Γράφτηκε από τη Rosanna Yuen</para>

          <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


  <informaltable>
    <tgroup cols="2">
      <tbody>
	<row>
	  <entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
	  <entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Μάνα</entry>
	  <entry>Η στοίβα πάνω αριστερά. Στην αρχή της παρτίδας όλα τα φύλλα τοποθετούνται εδώ.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
	  <entry>Εννέα στοίβες που σχηματίζουν ένα τετράγωνο 3Χ3. Σε κάθε στοίβα του ταμπλό μοιράζεται από ένα ανοιχτό φύλλο.</entry>
	</row>
      </tbody>
    </tgroup>
  </informaltable>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

  <para>Απομάκρυνση όλων των φύλλων.</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

  <para>Απομακρύνετε όλα τα ζεύγη φύλλων με άθροισμα δέκα. Απομακρύνετε τις όμοιες φιγούρες (Βαλέδες, Ντάμες, Ρήγες) ανά ζεύγη. Τα δεκάρια δεν επιτρέπεται να απομακρυνθούν. Οι στοίβες που αδειάζουν συμπληρώνονται αυτόματα από τη μάνα.</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

  <para>Κάθε ζεύγος που απομακρύνεται αντιστοιχεί σε δύο βαθμούς.</para>
  <para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 48</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

  <para>Πρόκειται για καθαρό παιχνίδι τύχης. Οπότε, οι μόνες στρατηγικές που μπορείτε να χρησιμοποιήσετε είναι στρατηγικές για να αυξήσετε την τύχη σας.</para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Bristol">  <!--<sect1info>
    <copyright>
      <year>2001</year>
      <holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
    </copyright>
    <author>
      <firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
      <surname>Yuen</surname>
    </author>
    <address><email>zana@webwynk.net</email></address>
  </sect1info>-->

  <title>Μπρίστολ</title>

  <para>Γράφτηκε από τη Rosanna Yuen</para>

          <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


  <informaltable>
    <tgroup cols="2">
      <tbody>
	<row>
	  <entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
	  <entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Μάνα</entry>
	  <entry>Η στοίβα πάνω αριστερά. Όταν ολοκληρωθεί η μοιρασιά, τα υπόλοιπα φύλλα τοποθετούνται εδώ. Αν τελειώσουν τα φύλλα της μάνας, δεν μπορεί να γίνει νέα μοιρασιά.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Ρεζέρβα</entry>
	  <entry>Οι τρεις στοίβες δεξιά της μάνας. Κάθε φορά που κάνετε κλικ στη μάνα μοιράζεται από ένα φύλλο στις ρεζέρβες.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Βάσεις</entry>
	  <entry>Οι τέσσερις στοίβες πάνω δεξιά. Τα φύλλα στις βάσεις τοποθετούνται σε αύξουσα σειρά ανεξαρτήτως φυλής.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
	  <entry>Οχτώ στοίβες με τρία ανοιχτά φύλλα η καθεμία.</entry>
	</row>
      </tbody>
    </tgroup>
  </informaltable>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

  <para>Μετακίνηση όλων των φύλλων στις βάσεις</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

  <para>Τα φύλλα στο ταμπλό τοποθετούνται σε φθίνουσα σειρά ανεξαρτήτως φυλής. Επιτρέπεται η μετακίνηση ενός μόνο φύλλου κάθε φορά. Οι άδειες στοίβες του ταμπλό δεν μπορούν να ξαναγεμίσουν.</para>
  <para>Σε κάθε μοιρασιά η μάνα μοιράζει από ένα φύλλο σε καθεμιά από τις τρεις στοίβες της ρεζέρβας. Μπορείτε να παίζετε το πάνω φύλλο κάθε ρεζέρβας. Αν μια στοίβα της ρεζέρβας αδειάσει, μπορεί να γεμίσει μόνο με την επόμενη μοιρασιά από τη μάνα.</para>
  <para>Τα φύλλα τοποθετούνται στις βάσεις ανεξαρτήτως φυλής και με αύξουσα σειρά, από τον Άσσο στο Ρήγα. Τα φύλλα των βάσεων βγαίνουν από το παιχνίδι.</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

  <para>Κάθε φύλλο που τοποθετείται στις βάσεις αντιστοιχεί σε 1 βαθμό.</para>
  <para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 52</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

  <para>Τα φύλλα δεν πρέπει να κοιτάνε ανάποδα. Άρα, το πρώτο σας μέλημα πρέπει να είναι τα φύλλα σε ανάποδη σειρά. Μετακινήστε όσο περισσότερα φύλλα μπορείτε από τις ρεζέρβες στο ταμπλό, γιατί οι Ρήγες είναι δύσκολο να μετακινηθούν.</para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Camelot"><!--<sect1info>
		<copyright>
			<year>1998</year>
			<holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
		</copyright>
		<author>
			<firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
			<surname>Yuen</surname>
		</author>
		<address><email>rwsy@mit.edu</email></address>
	</sect1info>-->

	<title>Κάμελοτ</title>

	<para>Γράφτηκε από τη Rosanna Yuen</para>

	        <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


	<informaltable>
		<tgroup cols="2">
			<tbody>
	<row>
		<entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
		<entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Μάνα</entry>
		<entry>Στην αρχή της παρτίδας όλα τα φύλλα τοποθετούνται στη μάνα. Η μάνα μοιράζει τα φύλλα ένα ένα και τα τοποθετεί στο σωρό. Αν τελειώσουν τα φύλλα της μάνας, δεν μπορεί να γίνει νέα μοιρασιά.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Σωρός</entry>
		<entry>Τα φύλλα προέρχονται από τη μάνα. Κάθε φύλλο που τοποθετείται στο σωρό πρέπει αμέσως να μετακινηθεί στο ταμπλό.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
		<entry>Ένα πλαίσιο 4Χ4. Κάθε θέση μπορεί να καλυφθεί από ένα μόνο φύλλο. Οι Ρήγες τοποθετούνται πάντα στις γωνίες. Οι Ντάμες στις δύο μεσαίες θέσεις τις πρώτης και της τελευταίας γραμμής. Οι Βαλέδες στις δύο μεσαίες θέσεις της πρώτης και της τελευταίας στήλης.</entry>
	</row>
			</tbody>
		</tgroup>
	</informaltable>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

	<para>Να απομακρυνθούν όλα τα φύλλα εκτός από τις φιγούρες (Βαλέδες, Ντάμες, Ρήγες). Έχετε κερδίσει, αν το ταμπλό σας μοιάζει με αυτό --</para>
	<screenshot>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata fileref="figures/camelot-goal.png" format="PNG"/>
			</imageobject>
			<textobject>
				<phrase>Ο συνδυασμός που κερδίζει.</phrase>
			</textobject>
		</mediaobject>
	</screenshot>
	<para>-- και η μάνα και ο σωρός έχουν αδειάσει. Οι φυλές δεν παίζουν ρόλο.</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

	<para>Αυτό το παιχνίδι παίζεται σε δύο φάσεις. Θα πρέπει να εναλλάσσεστε από τη μία φάση στην άλλη μέχρι τη λήξη της παρτίδας. Ξεκινήστε με την πρώτη φάση μέχρι να γεμίσει το ταμπλό. Στη συνέχεια περάστε στη δεύτερη φάση. Σημειώστε ότι δεν επιτρέπεται να περάσετε στη δεύτερη φάση αν δεν έχει γεμίσει το ταμπλό. Επιστρέφετε στην πρώτη φάση όποτε θέλετε, αλλά θυμηθείτε ότι αν θέλετε να περάσετε ξανά στη δεύτερη φάση θα πρέπει να γεμίσετε και πάλι το ταμπλό. Εξαιρούνται οι περιπτώσεις όπου έχουν αδειάσει η μάνα και ο σωρός.</para>
	<para>Πρώτη φάση -- Κάντε κλικ στη μάνα για να τοποθετήσετε ένα φύλλο στην άδεια στοίβα του σωρού. Αν το φύλλο σας είναι:</para>
	<itemizedlist>
		<listitem>
			<para>Ρήγας: Τοποθετήστε τον σε μία από τις άδειες θέσεις στις γωνίες.</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>Ντάμα: Τοποθετήστε την σε μία από τις δύο μεσαίες θέσεις της πρώτης ή της τελευταίας γραμμής.</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>Βαλές: Τοποθετήστε τον σε μία από τις δύο μεσαίες θέσεις της αριστερής ή της δεξιάς στήλης.</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>Άλλο φύλλο: Τοποθετήστε το σε όποια κενή θέση επιθυμείτε.</para>
		</listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
	<para>Δεύτερη φάση -- Απομακρύνετε τα δεκάρια κάνοντας κλικ πάνω τους. Απομακρύνετε ζεύγη φύλλων με άθροισμα δέκα, σέρνοντας το ένα φύλλο πάνω στο ζευγάρι του.</para>
	<para>Χάνετε την παρτίδα αν δεν υπάρχουν άλλες κενές θέσεις για να τοποθετήσετε τη φιγούρα που έχετε στο χέρι σας. Επίσης, αν έχετε καλύψει όλο το ταμπλό, αλλά δεν υπάρχουν φύλλα που μπορείτε να απομακρύνετε.</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

	<para>Κάθε φύλλο που απομακρύνεται αντιστοιχεί σε 1 βαθμό.</para>
	<para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 40</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

	<para>Στο μέσο είστε πιο ασφαλείς. Κατά την πρώτη φάση του παιχνιδιού τοποθετείτε τα φύλλα πρώτα στο μέσο και μετά στις άκρες. Αν εντοπίσετε ένα πιθανό ζεύγος, τοποθετείστε το φύλλο στην άκρη. Έτσι, στη δεύτερη φάση θα μπορείτε και πάλι να απελευθερώσετε αυτή τη θέση.</para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Canfield"><!--<sect1info>
		<copyright>
			<year>1998</year>
			<holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
		</copyright>
		<author>
			<firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
			<surname>Yuen</surname>
		</author>
		<address><email>rwsy@mit.edu</email></address>
	</sect1info>-->

	<title>Κονσερβοκούτια</title>

	<para>Γράφτηκε από τη Rosanna Yuen</para>

	        <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


	<informaltable>
		<tgroup cols="2">
			<tbody>
	<row>
		<entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
		<entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Μάνα</entry>
		<entry>Η στοίβα πάνω αριστερά. Όταν ολοκληρωθεί η μοιρασιά, τα υπόλοιπα φύλλα τοποθετούνται εδώ. Η μάνα μοιράζει τα φύλλα ανά τρία και τα τοποθετεί στο σωρό. Επιτρέπονται απεριόριστες επιπλέον μοιρασιές.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Σωρός</entry>
		<entry>Η στοίβα δεξιά της μάνας. Τα φύλλα στο σωρό προέρχονται από τη μάνα. Μπορείτε να παίξετε το πάνω φύλλο.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Ρεζέρβα</entry>
		<entry>Αριστερά, κάτω από τη μάνα. Εδώ μοιράζονται δεκατρία φύλλα, με το πάνω φύλλο ανοιχτό. Μπορείτε να παίξετε το πάνω φύλλο είτε στις βάσεις είτε στο ταμπλό.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
		<entry>Τέσσερις στοίβες κάτω από τις βάσεις. Σε κάθε στοίβα μοιράζεται ένα φύλλο ανοιχτό. Τα φύλλα στο ταμπλό τοποθετούνται με φθίνουσα σειρά και σε εναλλασσόμενο χρώμα. Μπορείτε να μετακινείτε ομάδες φύλλων.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Βάσεις</entry>
		<entry>Οι τέσσερις στοίβες πάνω δεξιά. Μοιράστε ένα φύλλο ανοιχτό στην πρώτη στοίβα της βάσης. Αυτό θα είναι το βασικό φύλλο. Τα υπόλοιπα φύλλα τοποθετούνται ανά φυλή και σε αύξουσα σειρά.</entry>
	</row>
			</tbody>
		</tgroup>
	</informaltable>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

	<para>Μετακίνηση όλων των φύλλων στις βάσεις</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

	<para>Τα φύλλα στο ταμπλό τοποθετούνται με φθίνουσα σειρά και σε εναλλασσόμενο χρώμα. Μπορείτε να μετακινείτε ομάδες φύλλων. Οι κενές θέσεις του ταμπλό συμπληρώνονται αυτόματα από τη ρεζέρβα. Αν η ρεζέρβα έχει αδειάσει, η κενή θέση μπορεί να συμπληρωθεί από οποιοδήποτε φύλλο ή ομάδα φύλλων.</para>
	<para>Η μάνα μοιράζει τα φύλλα στο σωρό τρία τρία (εκτός από τα τελευταία φύλλα, οπότε μοιράζονται όσα έχουν απομείνει). Αν η μάνα αδειάσει, τοποθετήστε και πάλι στη μάνα όλα τα φύλλα του σωρού, χωρίς να αλλάξετε τη σειρά.</para>
	<para>Τα φύλλα στις βάσεις τοποθετούνται ανά φυλή και με αύξουσα σειρά, ξεκινώντας από το βασικό φύλλο (το πρώτο φύλλο της πρώτης βάσης). Για να ξεκινήσετε νέα στοίβα βάσης, πρέπει να βρείτε ένα φύλλο με την ίδια αξία με το βασικό φύλλο και να το τοποθετήσετε σε μία από τις κενές βάσεις. Οι Άσσοι ακολουθούν τους Ρήγες, τα δυάρια τους Άσσους. Τα φύλλα των βάσεων παραμένουν στο παιχνίδι. Αν επιτρέπεται η κίνηση, μπορείτε να τοποθετήσετε ένα φύλλο στις βάσεις κάνοντας διπλό κλικ πάνω του.</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

	<para>Κάθε φύλλο στις βάσεις αντιστοιχεί σε ένα βαθμό. Αυτό το παιχνίδι παιζόταν παλιά στα καζίνο. Για να μείνει κάποιος στα λεφτά του, έπρεπε η βαθμολογία του να είναι 10.</para>
	<para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 52</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

	<para>Κάλλιο ένα και στο χέρι, παρά δέκα και καρτέρι. Αυτό το παιχνίδι είναι δύσκολο. Οι περισσότεροι το παίζουν με βάση τους κανόνες του καζίνο και προσπαθούν να κερδίσουν όσους περισσότερους βαθμούς μπορούν. Γι' αυτό το λόγο πρέπει να μετακινείτε τα φύλλα στις βάσεις αμέσως μόλις σας δίνεται η δυνατότητα.</para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Carpet"><!--<sect1info>
    <copyright>
      <year>2001</year>
      <holder>Vincent Povirk</holder>
    </copyright>
    <author>
      <firstname>Vincent</firstname>
      <surname>Povirk</surname>
    </author>
    <address><email>madewokherd@gmail.com</email></address>
  </sect1info>-->

  <title>Χαλί</title>

  <para>Γράφτηκε από το Vincent Povirk</para>

          <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


  <informaltable>
    <tgroup cols="2"><tbody>
	<row>
	  <entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
	  <entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Μάνα</entry>
	  <entry>Η στοίβα πάνω αριστερά. Όταν ολοκληρωθεί η μοιρασιά, τα υπόλοιπα φύλλα τοποθετούνται εδώ. Τα φύλλα της μάνας ανοίγουν ένα ένα και τοποθετούνται στο σωρό. Αν τελειώσουν τα φύλλα της μάνας, δεν μπορεί να γίνει νέα μοιρασιά.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Σωρός</entry>
	  <entry>Προέρχονται από τη μάνα. Μπορείτε να παίξετε το πάνω φύλλο.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Βάσεις</entry>
	  <entry>Οι τέσσερις στοίβες πάνω δεξιά. Τα φύλλα τοποθετούνται ανά φυλή και σε αύξουσα σειρά, από τον Άσσο στο Ρήγα. Οι Άσσοι αφαιρούνται πριν το μοίρασμα και τοποθετούνται στις βάσεις.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
	  <entry>Το "Χαλί". Τέσσερις γραμμές με πέντε ανοιχτά φύλλα η καθεμία. Μπορείτε να μετακινήσετε οποιοδήποτε φύλλο του ταμπλό, αλλά μόνο προς τις βάσεις. Οι κενές θέσεις συμπληρώνονται αυτόματα, είτε από το σωρό (αν είναι δυνατόν), είτε από τη μάνα.</entry>
	</row>
      </tbody>
    </tgroup>
  </informaltable>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

  <para>Μετακίνηση όλων των φύλλων στις βάσεις</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

  <para>Τα φύλλα του ταμπλό είναι μέσα στο παιχνίδι.</para>
  <para>Η μάνα ανοίγει τα φύλλα της ένα ένα και τα τοποθετεί στο σωρό. Μπορείτε να παίξετε το πρώτο φύλλο του σωρού. Αν τελειώσουν τα φύλλα της μάνας, δεν μπορεί να γίνει νέα μοιρασιά.</para>
  <para>Στις βάσεις τα φύλλα μπαίνουν ανά φυλή και σε αύξουσα σειρά από τον Άσσο στο Ρήγα. Τα φύλλα στις βάσεις δε βγαίνουν από το παιχνίδι. Αν κάνετε διπλό κλικ σε ένα φύλλο, το φύλλο αυτό θα ανέβει στις βάσεις, εφόσον επιτρέπεται η κίνηση.</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

  <para>Κάθε φύλλο που τοποθετείται στις βάσεις αντιστοιχεί σε 1 βαθμό.</para>
  <para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 48</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

  <para>Απλά μετακινήστε στις βάσεις ό,τι μπορείτε.</para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Chessboard">  <!--<sect1info>
    <copyright>
      <year>2001</year>
      <holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
    </copyright>
    <author>
      <firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
      <surname>Yuen</surname></author>
    <address><email>zana@webwynk.net</email></address>
  </sect1info>-->

  <title>Σκακιέρα</title>

  <para>Γράφτηκε από τη Rosanna Yuen</para>

          <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


  <informaltable>
    <tgroup cols="2">
      <tbody>
	<row>
	  <entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
	  <entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Βάσεις</entry>
	  <entry>Τέσσερις στοίβες στο κέντρο. Τα φύλλα τοποθετούνται ανά φυλή και σε αύξουσα σειρά, ξεκινώντας από αρχικό φύλλο της αρεσκείας σας. Όπου χρειάζεται, ο Άσσος ακολουθεί το Ρήγα. Τα φύλλα των βάσεων βγαίνουν από το παιχνίδι.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
	  <entry>Πέντε στοίβες σε κάθε πλευρά των βάσεων. Σε κάθε στοίβα του ταμπλό μοιράζονται πέντε φύλλα ανοιχτά. Στις δύο στοίβες της κορυφής μοιράζεται από ένα φύλλο επιπλέον. Μπορείτε να παίζετε το πάνω φύλλο κάθε στοίβας του ταμπλό.</entry>
	</row>
      </tbody>
    </tgroup>
  </informaltable>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

  <para>Μετακίνηση όλων των φύλλων στις βάσεις</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

  <para>Τα φύλλα στις στοίβες του ταμπλό τοποθετούνται ανά φυλή είτε σε αύξουσα είτε σε φθίνουσα σειρά. Μόνο το πάνω φύλλο κάθε στοίβας επιτρέπεται να μετακινείται. Τυχόν κενές θέσεις μπορούν να συμπληρωθούν με οποιοδήποτε διαθέσιμο φύλλο.</para>
  <para>Στις βάσεις τα φύλλα τοποθετούνται ανά φυλή και σε αύξουσα σειρά, ξεκινώντας από το αρχικό φύλλο της αρεσκείας σας. Όπου χρειάζεται, ο Άσσος ακολουθεί το Ρήγα. Τα φύλλα των βάσεων βγαίνουν από το παιχνίδι.</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

  <para>Κάθε φύλλο που τοποθετείται στις βάσεις αντιστοιχεί σε 1 βαθμό.</para>
  <para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 52</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

  <para>Επιλέξτε πολύ προσεκτικά το αρχικό φύλλο των βάσεων. Οι εύκολες επιλογές μπορεί να σας οδηγήσουν σε αδιέξοδο.</para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Clock"><!--<sect1info>
		<copyright>
			<year>1998</year>
			<holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
		</copyright>
		<author>
			<firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
			<surname>Yuen</surname>
		</author>
		<address><email>rwsy@mit.edu</email></address>
	</sect1info>-->

	<title>Ρολόι</title>

	<para>Γράφτηκε από τη Rosanna Yuen</para>

	        <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


	<informaltable>
		<tgroup cols="2">
			<tbody>
	<row>
		<entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
		<entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
		<entry>Η διάταξη των φύλλων θυμίζει ρολόι. Περιλαμβάνει δώδεκα στοίβες με τέσσερα φύλλα για την καθεμία.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Μάνα</entry>
		<entry>Τα τέσσερα τελευταία φύλλα τοποθετούνται στο σωρό (στο κέντρο του ταμπλό). Το πάνω φύλλο είναι ανοιχτό.</entry>
	</row>
			</tbody>
		</tgroup>
	</informaltable>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

	<para>Κάθε στοίβα να περιέχει τέσσερα όμοια φύλλα, η αξία των οποίων αντιστοιχεί στην "ώρα" που θα αντιπροσώπευαν σε ένα καντράν ρολογιού.</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

	<para>Μετακινήστε το πάνω χαρτί από το κέντρο στην κατάλληλη στοίβα. Το ταμπλό έχει σχήμα ρολογιού, άρα τα φύλλα με αριθμούς τοποθετούνται στις θέσεις των αντίστοιχων "ωρών" ενός αναλογικού ρολογιού. Οι Βαλέδες και οι Ντάμες αντιστοιχούν στις έντεκα και δώδεκα, ενώ οι Άσσοι στη μία. Για όσους δεν είχαν ποτέ τους αναλογικό ρολόι, εδώ βλέπετε την κατάλληλη διάταξη:</para>
	<screenshot>
	 <mediaobject>
	    <imageobject>
			  <imagedata fileref="figures/clock-rules.png" format="PNG"/>
	    </imageobject>
	    <textobject>
	      <phrase>Διάταξη ρολογιού</phrase>
	    </textobject>
	  </mediaobject>
	</screenshot>
	<para>Οι Ρήγες τοποθετούνται στη στοίβα του κέντρου. Όταν ένα φύλλο μετακινείται σε νέα στοίβα (ή παραμένει στην ίδια αν πρόκειται για Ρήγα), το κάτω χαρτί της νέας στοίβας τοποθετείται ανοιχτό στη στοίβα του κέντρου. Το παιχνίδι συνεχίζεται με αυτό το νέο φύλλο. Για να μετακινήσετε ένα χαρτί σε μία άλλη στοίβα, μπορείτε να το σύρετε ή να κάνετε διπλό κλικ στη στοίβα που επιθυμείτε να το τοποθετήσετε.</para>
	<para>Το παιχνίδι τελειώνει όταν η στοίβα του κέντρου αποκτήσει τέσσερις Ρήγες. Θεωρείται ότι κερδίσατε, αν επιτευχθεί ο στόχος του παιχνιδιού. Σημειώστε ότι δεν παίζει ρόλο αν ένα φύλλο παραμένει κλειστό, από τη στιγμή που βρίσκεται στη σωστή στοίβα.</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

	<para>Κάθε χαρτί που τοποθετείται στη σωστή στοίβα του ρολογιού αντιστοιχεί σε ένα βαθμό. (Με την εξαίρεση του Ρήγα, γιατί τα κανονικά ρολόγια δεν έχουν Ρήγες.)</para>
	<para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 48</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

	<para>Βρείτε έναν τρόπο να αυτοματοποιήσετε το παιχνίδι, γιατί δε χρειάζεται να λάβετε κανενός είδους αποφάσεις. Αν χάσετε, δεν φταίτε εσείς. (Παρομοίως, αν κερδίσετε, απλά σας χαμογέλασε η τύχη!)</para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Cover"><!--<sect1info>
	  <copyright>
	   <year>2001</year>
	   <holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
	  </copyright>
	  <author>
	   <firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
	   <surname>Yuen</surname>
	  </author>
	  <address><email>zana@webwynk.net</email></address>
	</sect1info>-->

	<title>Κάλυψη</title>

  <para>Γράφτηκε από τη Rosanna Yuen</para>

          <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


  <informaltable>
    <tgroup cols="2">
      <tbody>
	<row>
	  <entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
	  <entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Μάνα</entry>
	  <entry>Η στοίβα πάνω αριστερά. Εδώ τοποθετούνται τα χαρτιά που απομένουν μετά το μοίρασμα.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
    <entry>Τέσσερις στοίβες. Στην αρχή της παρτίδας μοιράζεται από ένα φύλλο στην καθεμία. Οι στοίβες που αδειάζουν συμπληρώνονται αμέσως από τη μάνα.</entry>
	</row>
      </tbody>
    </tgroup>
  </informaltable>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

  <para>Να αδειάσει η μάνα.</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

  <para>Δύο οποιαδήποτε φύλλα του ταμπλό μπορούν να απομακρυνθούν, εφόσον ανήκουν στην ίδια φυλή. Τα κενά που σχηματίζονται συμπληρώνονται αμέσως από τα φύλλα της μάνας. Το παιχνίδι τελειώνει όταν το ταμπλό καταλήγει να περιέχει ένα φύλλο από κάθε διαφορετική φυλή.</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

  <para>Κάθε ζευγάρι που απομακρύνεται αντιστοιχεί σε δύο βαθμούς.</para>
  <para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 48</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

  <para>Γρήγορο και σύντομο παιχνίδι που δεν απαιτεί ιδιαίτερη κρίση. Η καλύτερη προσέγγιση είναι γρήγορα αντανακλαστικά και ελάχιστη σκέψη.</para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Cruel"><!--<sect1info>
    <copyright>
      <year>2005</year>
      <holder>Zach Keene</holder>
    </copyright>
    <author>
      <firstname>Zach</firstname>
      <surname>Keene</surname>
    </author>
    <address><email>zjkeene@bellsouth.net</email></address>
  </sect1info>-->

  <title>Σκληρό</title>

  <para>Γράφτηκε από τον Zach Keen</para>

          <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


  <informaltable>
    <tgroup cols="2"><tbody>
	<row>
	  <entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
	  <entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Μάνα</entry>
	  <entry>Η θέση πάνω αριστερά. Επειδή τα χαρτιά που απομένουν μοιράζονται στο ταμπλό, παραμένει πάντα άδεια. Επιτρέπονται απεριόριστες επιπλέον μοιρασιές.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Βάσεις</entry>
	  <entry>Οι δεξιές στοίβες της πάνω γραμμής. Στην αρχή της παρτίδας εδώ τοποθετούνται οι Άσσοι. Τα υπόλοιπα φύλλα τοποθετούνται ανά φυλή και σε αύξουσα σειρά, από τον Άσσο στο Ρήγα.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
	  <entry>Μέχρι δώδεκα στοίβες. Κάθε φορά μοιράζονται τέσσερα φύλλα, μέχρι να τελειώσουν τα φύλλα της μάνας. Οι στοίβες του ταμπλό συμπληρώνονται με φύλλα της ίδιας φυλής σε φθίνουσα σειρά.</entry>
	</row>
      </tbody>
    </tgroup>
  </informaltable>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

  <para>Μετακίνηση όλων των φύλλων στις βάσεις.</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

  <para>Τοποθετήστε φύλλα της ίδιας φυλής σε φθίνουσα σειρά στις βάσεις και σε αύξουσα σειρά στο ταμπλό. Αν δεν απομένουν άλλες κινήσεις (ή απλά επειδή έτσι θέλετε), κάντε κλικ στην κενή θέση πάνω αριστερά για να ζητήσετε νέα μοιρασιά.</para>
  <para>Μια νέα μοιρασιά σημαίνει ότι οι στοίβες του ταμπλό τοποθετούνται η μία πάνω στην άλλη με τη σειρά, ξεκινώντας από την τελευταία στοίβα. Στη συνέχεια η μάνα αναποδογυρίζει την τράπουλα και ξαναμοιράζει τα φύλλα στο ταμπλό, τέσσερα για κάθε στοίβα. Αν δεν είχε γίνει καμία κίνηση προηγουμένως, η διάταξη των φύλλων δεν αλλάζει μετά τη νέα μοιρασιά. Άρα, χάνετε το παιχνίδι, αν δεν υπάρχει καμία κίνηση διαθέσιμη μετά από νέα μοιρασιά.</para>
  <para>Σημείωση: Υπάρχει μία περίπτωση εκφυλισμού όπου, μετά από νέα μοιρασιά, η τελευταία στοίβα του ταμπλό περιέχει ένα μόνο χαρτί και η μονή δυνατή σας κίνηση είναι να μετακινήσετε αυτό το τελευταίο χαρτί στην προτελευταία στοίβα. Αν κάνετε αυτή την κίνηση και ξαναμοιράσετε τα χαρτιά, θα καταλήξετε πάλι στην αρχική διάταξη των φύλλων. Όποτε προκύπτει αυτό το πρόβλημα, το AisleRiot τερματίζει την παρτίδα.</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

  <para>Κάθε φύλλο που τοποθετείται στις βάσεις αντιστοιχεί σε ένα βαθμό.</para>
  <para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 48</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

  <para>Αν μπορείτε να μετακινήσετε περισσότερα από ένα φύλλα, μετακινήστε πρώτα το φύλλο με τη μεγαλύτερη αξία.</para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Diamond_Mine">  <!--<sect1info>
		<copyright>
			<year>2001</year>
			<holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
		</copyright>
		<author>
			<firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
			<surname>Yuen</surname>
		</author>
		<address><email>zana@webwynk.net</email></address>
	</sect1info>-->

	<title>Αδαμαντωρυχείο</title>

  <para>Γράφτηκε από τη Rosanna Yuen</para>

          <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


  <informaltable>
    <tgroup cols="2">
      <tbody>
	<row>
	  <entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
	  <entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Βάσεις</entry>
	  <entry>Μία στοίβα στην κορυφή. Εδώ τοποθετούνται όλα τα Καρό (Διαμάντια) με τη σειρά, ξεκινώντας από όποιο θέλετε.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
	  <entry>Δεκατρείς στήλες. Σε κάθε στήλη μοιράζονται τρία φύλλα κλειστά και ένα ανοιχτό.</entry>
	</row>
      </tbody>
    </tgroup>
  </informaltable>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

  <para>Τοποθέτηση όλων των Καρό στη βάση και ταξινόμηση όλων των υπολοίπων χαρτιών ανά φυλή και σε φθίνουσα σειρά, με τους Άσσους στο τέλος.</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

  <para>Τα φύλλα (όλα εκτός από τα Καρό) τοποθετούνται σε φθίνουσα σειρά ανεξαρτήτως φυλής. Μπορείτε να μετακινείτε μαζί όλα τα χαρτιά μιας ομάδας φύλλων. Αν μια στήλη αδειάσει, μπορείτε να καλύψετε το κενό με οποιοδήποτε φύλλο ή ομάδα φύλλων (αρκεί να μην είναι Καρό).</para>
  <para>Τα Καρό επιτρέπεται να μετακινούνται μόνο προς τις βάσεις. Στη βάση τα Καρό τοποθετούνται με αύξουσα σειρά, ξεκινώντας από τον αριθμό της αρεσκείας σας.</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

  <para>Κάθε Καρό που τοποθετείται στη βάση αντιστοιχεί σε αριθμό βαθμών ίσο με την αξία του φύλλου. Ο Άσσος δίνει ένα βαθμό, ο Βαλές έντεκα, η Ντάμα δώδεκα και ο Ρήγας δεκατρείς.</para>
  <para>Κάθε στήλη με φύλλα της ίδιας φυλής τοποθετημένα στη σειρά (από το Ρήγα στον Άσσο) αντιστοιχεί σε τρεις βαθμούς.</para>
  <para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 100</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

  <para>Η δουλειά του αδαμαντωρύχου είναι σκληρή. Θυμηθείτε ότι όλα τα διαμάντια (Καρό) δεν αξίζουν το ίδιο. Μην ξεχάσετε να καθαρίσετε το ορυχείο στο τέλος της μέρας, τοποθετώντας με τη σειρά τα χαρτιά των υπόλοιπων φυλών.</para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Doublets">  <!--<sect1info>
    <copyright>
      <year>1998</year>
      <holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
    </copyright>
    <author>
      <firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
      <surname>Yuen</surname>
    </author>
    <address>
      <email>rwsy@mit.edu</email>
    </address>
  </sect1info>-->

  <title>Doublets</title>
  <para>Γράφτηκε από τη Rosanna Yuen</para>
          <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


  <informaltable>
    <tgroup cols="2">
      <tbody>
	<row>
	  <entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
	  <entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Μάνα</entry>
	  <entry>
	    Top left pile.  The rest of the deck is placed here after
	    dealing.  Cards are turned over one at a time to Waste.  Two
	    redeals.
	  </entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Σωρός</entry>
	  <entry>Η στοίβα δεξιά της μάνας. Τα φύλλα στο σωρό προέρχονται από τη μάνα. Μπορείτε να παίξετε το πάνω φύλλο.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Ρεζέρβα</entry>
	  <entry>
	    Seven piles, forming an arch shape (upside down U) to the
	    right.  Deal one card face up on each pile.  During this
	    deal, if a King is dealt, remove the King and place it on
	    the bottom of the deck.  Deal another card into this pile.
	    Each Reserve pile can only hold one card.  When a Reserve
	    pile is empty, it is automatically filled by the Waste, or,
	    if the Waste is empty, from the Stock.  Once original deal
	    is over, when a King is placed in a pile of the Reserve,
	    this pile is frozen as Kings cannot be moved.
	  </entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Βάσεις</entry>
	  <entry>
	    One pile, the center pile on the bottom row of the Reserve
	    slots.  To be built on from original card by doubling,
	    regardless of suit or color.
	  </entry>
	</row>
      </tbody>
    </tgroup>
  </informaltable>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

  <para>
    Move all cards to the Foundation pile.
  </para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

  <para>
    Cards can be put in the Foundation pile if they are twice the value
    of the card currently on top of the Foundation.  Jacks and Queens
    are eleven and twelve, respectively.  If the doubled number exceeds
    thirteen, subtract thirteen to find next needed card.  The series
    goes:
  </para>
  <para>
    A, 2, 4, 8, 3, 6, Q, J, 9, 5, 10, 7, repeat...
  </para>
  <para>
    Cards are flipped from the Stock to the Waste by one.  When the
    Stock is empty, move all cards in Waste back to the Stock,
    maintaining order.  You can go through the deck three times.
  </para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

  <para>
    Each card in the Foundation pile scores one point.
  </para>
  <para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 48</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

  <para>
    Without a King, you can't have regicide.  Avoid them.
  </para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Eagle_Wing">  <!--<sect1info>
    <copyright>
      <year>2001</year>
      <holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
    </copyright>
    <author>
      <firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
      <surname>Yuen</surname>
    </author>
    <address><email>zana@webwynk.net</email></address>
  </sect1info>-->

  <title>Eagle Wing</title>

  <para>Γράφτηκε από τη Rosanna Yuen</para>

          <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


  <informaltable>
    <tgroup cols="2">
      <tbody>
	<row>
	  <entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
	  <entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Μάνα</entry>
	  <entry>
	    Top left pile.  The rest of the deck is placed here after
	    dealing the Tableau.  Cards are turned over one at a time to
	    Waste.  Two redeals.
	  </entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Σωρός</entry>
	  <entry>Η στοίβα δεξιά της μάνας. Τα φύλλα στο σωρό προέρχονται από τη μάνα. Μπορείτε να παίξετε το πάνω φύλλο.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Βάσεις</entry>
	  <entry>
	    Four piles top right.
	    One card is dealt in the first Fondation at the start of the game,
	    this is the base card.
	    Other Fondations must be started with a card of the same rank as the
	    base card.
	    To be built up in suit from the base card.
	  </entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Ρεζέρβα</entry>
	  <entry>
	    Middle (and lowest) slot.  Deal thirteen cards face down
	    here.  Flip card to fill any spaces in the Tableau.  When
	    only one card is left in the Reserve, it will flip up and
	    can be played on Foundation or a Tableau pile.
	  </entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
	  <entry>
	    Eight slots (four to the left and four to the right of
	    Reserve.)  Deal one card face up per slot.  Tableau can be
	    built down by suit.  Cards can be moved singly to other
	    slots on the Tableau, or in a group on to the Foundation.
	    Each Tableau slot can hold a maximum of three cards.
	  </entry>
	</row>
      </tbody>
    </tgroup>
  </informaltable>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

  <para>Μετακίνηση όλων των φύλλων στις βάσεις</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

  <para>
    Cards in the tableau are built down by suit.  Cards can only be
    moved singly to another Tableau pile.  However, to ease monotony,
    groups of cards can be moved to Foundation.  An empty slot in the
    Tableau is filled automatically from the Reserve.  If the Reserve is
    empty, an empty slot can be filled by a card from the Waste or from
    another Tableau pile.
  </para>
  <para>
    The Reserve exists mainly to deal cards into empty slots of the
    Tableau.  However, when there is only one card left in the Reserve,
    it will become visible and is in play.
  </para>
  <para>
    Cards are flipped from the Stock to the Waste singly.  When the
    Stock is empty, move all cards in Waste back to the Stock,
    maintaining order.  You can go through the deck three times.
  </para>
  <para>
    Foundations are built up in suit from the base card (first card
    dealt to first Foundation). New Foundations are started when a card
    of the same rank as the first card placed during the dealing period
    are placed on empty Foundation piles.  Aces are placed on Kings, and
    twos on Aces.  Cards in Foundations are not in play.
  </para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

  <para>Κάθε φύλλο που τοποθετείται στις βάσεις αντιστοιχεί σε 1 βαθμό.</para>
  <para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 52</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

  <para>
    A little planning goes a long way.  Check before piling cards in a
    Tableau.  Remember the three card in a slot rule.
  </para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Easthaven">  <!--<sect1info>
    <copyright>
      <year>2001</year>
      <holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
    </copyright>
    <author>
      <firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
      <surname>Yuen</surname>
    </author>
    <address><email>zana@webwynk.net</email></address>
  </sect1info>-->

  <title>Easthaven</title>

  <para>Γράφτηκε από τη Rosanna Yuen</para>

          <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


  <informaltable>
    <tgroup cols="2">
      <tbody>
	<row>
	  <entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
	  <entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Μάνα</entry>
	  <entry>
	    Top left pile.  Deck is placed here after dealing on to the
	    Tableau.
	  </entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Βάσεις</entry>
	  <entry>
	    Four piles top right.  To be built up in suit from Ace to
	    King.
	  </entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
	  <entry>
	    Seven piles on the bottom.  Deal two cards face down and one
	    card face up for every pile.
	  </entry>
	</row>
      </tbody>
    </tgroup>
  </informaltable>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

  <para>Απομάκρυνση όλων των φύλλων.</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

  <para>
    The Tableau is built down by alternate color.  Builds of cards in
    sequence and alternating color can be moved as a unit.  Empty
    Tableau piles can be filled by Kings or builds starting with a King.
  </para>
  <para>
    Any empty Tableau slots must be filled if possible before dealing
    more cards.  Clicking on the Stock deals one card face up on to each
    Tableau pile.  The last deal places one card face up on the first
    three piles.  There are no redeals.
  </para>
  <para>
    The Foundation is built up in suit from Ace to King.  Cards in the
    Foundation are no longer in play.
  </para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

  <para>
    Each card placed on to a Foundation scores one point.
  </para>
  <para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 52</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

  <para>
    Move cards up to the Foundation when you can because the next deal
    may block it.  However since cards in the Foundation are no longer
    in play, you may get stuck later needing that card.  Hopefully this
    conundrum will be the most difficult one facing you today.
  </para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Eight_Off"><!--<sect1info>
		<copyright>
			<year>2001</year>
			<holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
		</copyright>
		<author>
			<firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
			<surname>Yuen</surname>
		</author>
		<address><email>zana@webwynk.net</email></address>
	</sect1info>-->

	<title>Eight Off</title>

  <para>Γράφτηκε από τη Rosanna Yuen</para>

          <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


  <informaltable>
    <tgroup cols="2">
      <tbody>
	<row>
	  <entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
	  <entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Βάσεις</entry>
	  <entry>
		  Four piles on the left.  Built from Ace to King in suit.
		</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Ρεζέρβες</entry>
	  <entry>
	  	Eight piles at top.  Each reserve can only
	  	hold one card.  The first four Reserve piles are each dealt
	  	one card at the beginning of the game.
	  </entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
	  <entry>
	  	Eight piles underneath the Reserves.
	  	The cards are dealt face up on to the Tableau, with
	  	six cards in each of the
	  	slots.
	  </entry>
	</row>
      </tbody>
    </tgroup>
  </informaltable>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

  <para>Μετακίνηση όλων των φύλλων στις βάσεις</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

  <para>Τα φύλλα στο ταμπλό τοποθετούνται ανά φυλή και σε φθίνουσα σειρά. Μπορείτε να μετακινείτε μόνο το πάνω φύλλο ή ομάδα φύλλων κάθε στήλης. Για να μετακινηθεί μια ομάδα φύλλων, ο αριθμός των φύλλων της δεν πρέπει να είναι μεγαλύτερος από τον αριθμό των ελεύθερων θέσεων της ρεζέρβας συν ένα. Οι κενές θέσεις του ταμπλό μπορούν να συμπληρωθούν μόνο με Ρήγα ή με ομάδα που ξεκινά με Ρήγα.</para>
  <para>Τα φύλλα στις βάσεις τοποθετούνται ανά φυλή και σε αύξουσα σειρά, από τον Άσσο στο Ρήγα. Αν και τα φύλλα των βάσεων θεωρητικά παραμένουν στο παιχνίδι, η χρήση τους δεν βοηθάει σε κάτι.</para>
  <para>Το πάνω φύλλο κάθε στήλης του ταμπλό μπορεί να τοποθετηθεί σε μια ελεύθερη θέση της ρεζέρβας. Τα φύλλα αυτά παραμένουν διαθέσιμα και μπορούν να μετακινηθούν στο ταμπλό ή τις βάσεις.</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

  <para>Κάθε φύλλο που τοποθετείται στις βάσεις αντιστοιχεί σε 1 βαθμό.</para>
  <para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 52</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

  <para>Μετακινήστε τα φύλλα στις βάσεις το συντομότερο δυνατόν. Η διατήρησή τους στο ταμπλό απλά δυσχεραίνει τις κινήσεις σας.</para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Elevator"><!--<sect1info>
		<copyright>
			<year>1999</year>
			<holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
		</copyright>
		<author>
			<firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
			<surname>Yuen</surname>
		</author>
		<address><email>rwsy@mit.edu</email></address>
	</sect1info>-->

	<title>Elevator</title>

	<para>Γράφτηκε από τη Rosanna Yuen</para>

	        <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


	<informaltable>
		<tgroup cols="2">
			<tbody>
	<row>
		<entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
		<entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Μάνα</entry>
		<entry>
			Top left pile.  The rest of the deck is placed here after dealing on
			to the Tableau.  Cards are turned over one at a time to Waste.  No
			redeals.
		</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Σωρός</entry>
		<entry>
			To be taken from Stock.
		</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
		<entry>
			Deal face down seven overlapping rows starting with one card on the
			first row, increasing by one per row and staggering the piles as to
			achieve a pyramid.  Flip bottom row.
		</entry>
	</row>
			</tbody>
		</tgroup>
	</informaltable>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

	<para>
		Move all cards to Waste.
	</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

	<para>
		All exposed cards in the pyramid are available for play.  Build on to
		the Waste from these available cards whenever possible by playing a
		card with a rank immediately above or immediately below the rank of
		the top card in the Waste.  Aces are both above Kings and below Deuces.
	</para>
	<para>
		Cards can be flipped singly from the Stock to the Waste.  There is no redeal.
	</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

	<para>
		Each card removed from the pyramid scores one point.
	</para>
	<para>
		Maximum possible score:  28
	</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

	<para>
		Every pyramid needs a strong foundation.  Get rid of the lower cards
		first, with an eye out to try to expose as many cards as possible.
	</para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Escalator"><!--<sect1info>
		<copyright>
			<year>2001</year>
			<holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
		</copyright>
		<author>
			<firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
			<surname>Yuen</surname>
		</author>
		<address><email>zana@webwynk.net</email></address>
	</sect1info>-->

	<title>Escalator</title>

  <para>Γράφτηκε από τη Rosanna Yuen</para>

          <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


  <informaltable>
    <tgroup cols="2">
      <tbody>
	<row>
	  <entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
	  <entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Μάνα</entry>
	  <entry>
		  Top left pile.  The rest of the deck is placed here after
		  dealing on to the Tableau.  Cards are turned over one at a
		  time to Waste.  No redeals
	  </entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Σωρός</entry>
	  <entry>
		  To be taken from Stock.
	  </entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
	  <entry>
		  Deal face up seven overlapping rows starting with one card on
		  the first row, increasing by one per row and staggering the
		  piles as to achieve a pyramid.
	  </entry>
	</row>
      </tbody>
    </tgroup>
  </informaltable>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

  <para>
    Move all cards to Waste.
  </para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

  <para>
	  All exposed cards in the pyramid are available for play.  Build on to
	  the Waste from these available cards whenever possible by playing a
	  card with a rank immediately above or immediately below the rack of
	  the top card in the Waste.  Aces are both above Kings and below
	  Deuces.
  </para>
  <para>
	  Cards are flipped singly from the Stock to the Waste.  There is no redeal.
  </para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

  <para>
    Each card removed from the Tableau scores one point.
  </para>
  <para>
    Maximum possible score:  28
  </para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

  <para>
	  Try to plan ahead so that you can make runs in the future.
  </para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="First_Law">  <!--<sect1info>
    <copyright>
      <year>2001</year>
      <holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
    </copyright>
    <author>
      <firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
      <surname>Yuen</surname>
    </author>
    <address><email>zana@webwynk.net</email></address>
  </sect1info>-->

  <title>First Law</title>

  <para>Γράφτηκε από τη Rosanna Yuen</para>

          <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


  <informaltable>
    <tgroup cols="2">
      <tbody>
	<row>
	  <entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
	  <entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Μάνα</entry>
	  <entry>
	    Top left pile.  All cards are placed here in beginning.
	    When emptied, cards are brought back from Tableau and put
	    back in the Stock.
	  </entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
	  <entry>
	    Four piles on the right.  Each deal from Stock will
	    deal one card to each Tableau pile.
	  </entry>
	</row>
      </tbody>
    </tgroup>
  </informaltable>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

  <para>Απομάκρυνση όλων των φύλλων.</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

  <para>
    Clicking on the Stock will deal one card to each of the Tableau
    piles.  If any of the cards showing in the Tableau are of the same
    rank, move the others on to the leftmost of the like cards.  Empty
    piles can only be filled by an ensuing deal from Stock.
  </para>
  <para>
    If at any point, all four cards showing are the same rank, they are
    removed.
  </para>
  <para>
    When Stock is empty, the Tableau piles are gathered, right pile on
    left, and placed back into stock.  The first card dealt will always
    be the first card dealt until it is removed.  There are unlimited
    redeals.
  </para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

  <para>
    Each set of four cards removed scores one point.
  </para>
  <para>
    Maximum possible score:  13
  </para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

  <para>
    Don't forget to use the brakes!  This game might never end unless
    you decide carefully whether or not to make a move.
  </para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Fortress">  <!--<sect1info>
    <copyright>
      <year>2001</year>
      <holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
    </copyright>
    <author>
      <firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
      <surname>Yuen</surname></author>
    <address><email>zana@webwynk.net</email></address>
  </sect1info>-->

  <title>Fortress</title>

  <para>Γράφτηκε από τη Rosanna Yuen</para>

          <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


  <informaltable>
    <tgroup cols="2">
      <tbody>
	<row>
	  <entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
	  <entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Βάσεις</entry>
	  <entry>
	    Four piles in the middle.  To be built up in suit from Ace
	    to King.  Cards in Foundation piles are no longer in play.
	  </entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
	  <entry>Πέντε στοίβες σε κάθε πλευρά των βάσεων. Σε κάθε στοίβα του ταμπλό μοιράζονται πέντε φύλλα ανοιχτά. Στις δύο στοίβες της κορυφής μοιράζεται από ένα φύλλο επιπλέον. Μπορείτε να παίζετε το πάνω φύλλο κάθε στοίβας του ταμπλό.</entry>
	</row>
      </tbody>
    </tgroup>
  </informaltable>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

  <para>Μετακίνηση όλων των φύλλων στις βάσεις</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

  <para>Τα φύλλα στις στοίβες του ταμπλό τοποθετούνται ανά φυλή είτε σε αύξουσα είτε σε φθίνουσα σειρά. Μόνο το πάνω φύλλο κάθε στοίβας επιτρέπεται να μετακινείται. Τυχόν κενές θέσεις μπορούν να συμπληρωθούν με οποιοδήποτε διαθέσιμο φύλλο.</para>
  <para>
    The Foundations are built up from Ace to King in suit.  Cards in
    Foundation piles are no longer in play.
  </para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

  <para>Κάθε φύλλο που τοποθετείται στις βάσεις αντιστοιχεί σε 1 βαθμό.</para>
  <para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 52</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

  <para>
    Safeguard any empty Tableau slots you may create.  They are the key
    to a successful game.
  </para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Fortunes">  <!--<sect1info>
    <copyright>
      <year>1998</year>
      <holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
    </copyright>
    <author>
      <firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
      <surname>Yuen</surname>
    </author>
    <address><email>zana@webwynk.net</email></address>
  </sect1info>-->

  <title>Fortunes</title>

  <para>Γράφτηκε από τη Rosanna Yuen</para>

          <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


  <informaltable>
    <tgroup cols="2">
      <tbody>
	<row>
	  <entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
	  <entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Μάνα</entry>
	  <entry>
	    Top left pile.  Deals a card to each Tableau pile when
	    clicked.
	  </entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
	  <entry>
	    Four piles on right.  Groups of cards can be moved on to
	    empty piles.
	  </entry>
	</row>
      </tbody>
    </tgroup>
  </informaltable>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

  <para>
    To remove all cards except the four Aces.
  </para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

  <para>
    Aces are high cards.  When two cards of the same suit are available,
    the one with the lower rank can be removed.  When an empty slot
    appears, it can be filled with an group of cards.
  </para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

  <para>Κάθε φύλλο που απομακρύνεται αντιστοιχεί σε 1 βαθμό.</para>
  <para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 48</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

  <para>
    There is no reason to have an empty slot when dealing another batch
    of cards.  However, when you have an empty slot, try to keep it
    empty as long as possible, as this is a great way to get rid of
    buried cards.
  </para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Forty_Thieves"><!--<sect1info>
		<copyright>
			<year>2008</year>
			<holder>Ed Sirett</holder>
		</copyright>
		<author>
			<firstname>Ed Sirett</firstname>
			<surname>Sirett</surname>
		</author>
		<address><email>ed@makewrite.demon.co.uk</email></address>
	</sect1info>-->

	<title>Forty Thieves</title>

  <para>Γράφτηκε από τον Ed Sirett</para>

          <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


  <informaltable>
    <tgroup cols="2">
      <tbody>
	<row>
	  <entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
	  <entry>Δύο τράπουλες</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Μάνα</entry>
	  <entry>
	  	Top left pile.  The rest of the deck is placed here after
	    dealing the Tableau.  Cards are dealt singly to the waste,
	    The top card of the waste is available for play. 
	  </entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Βάσεις</entry>
	  <entry>
	  	Eight piles top right.  To be built in suit from Ace to
	    King. 
	  </entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
    <entry>
    	Ten piles.  Deal four rows face up to start.  Tableau can 
    	be built down in suit.  Cards are moved singly.  Empty 
    	piles can be filled with any card. 
     </entry>
	</row>
      </tbody>
    </tgroup>
  </informaltable>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

  <para>Μετακίνηση όλων των φύλλων στις βάσεις</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

  <para>
    Cards in Tableau are built down in the same suit.  Cards can only
    be moved singly. An empty pile in the Tableau can 
    be filled with any card. As a short cut you can move more than one if
    there are enough empty spaces. Cards can also be moved in groups to the 
    Foundation piles.
  </para>
  <para>
    Cards are played singly from the Stock to the waste pile, whose 
    top card is available for play. There are no redeals.
  </para>
  <para>
    Foundations are built up in suit from Ace to King. Double clicking
    on a foundation will autoplay cards. Double clicking on a card in 
    the Tableau or waste will move it to the appropriate Foundation pile
    if such a move is possible, or to the tableau if possible.
  </para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

  <para>
    Each card in the Foundation scores 5 points.  When a Foundation pile
    is complete (from Ace to King), 60 more points are scored. 
  </para>
  <para>
    Maximum possible score:  1000
  </para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

  <para>
    Refrain from bringing cards to the tableau in order to obtain an empty
    space as soon as possible. Then balance the requirements to maintain
    empty spaces against the need to save low cards from being buried in
    the waste. 
  </para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Fourteen">  <!--<sect1info>
    <copyright>
      <year>1999</year>
      <holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
    </copyright>
    <author>
      <firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
      <surname>Yuen</surname></author>
    <address><email>zana@webwynk.net</email></address>
  </sect1info>-->

  <title>Fourteen</title>

  <para>Γράφτηκε από τη Rosanna Yuen</para>

          <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


  <informaltable>
    <tgroup cols="2">
      <tbody>
	<row>
	  <entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
	  <entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
	  <entry>
	    Deal all cards face up evenly on to twelve piles.  The first
	    four piles will each have five cards while the other piles
	    will all have four cards.  The exposed card in each pile is
	    in play.  Empty piles cannot be filled.
	  </entry>
	</row>
      </tbody>
    </tgroup>
  </informaltable>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

  <para>Απομάκρυνση όλων των φύλλων.</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

  <para>
    Cards can be removed in pairs that add up to fourteen.  Aces are
    worth one and Jacks, Queens, and Kings are worth 11, 12, and 13
    respectively.
  </para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

  <para>Κάθε φύλλο που απομακρύνεται αντιστοιχεί σε 1 βαθμό.</para>
  <para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 52</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

  <para>
    Watch your step!  Try to move cards that are resting on matching
    pairs as otherwise you might get stuck.
  </para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Freecell"><!--<sect1info>
		<copyright>
			<year>1999</year>
			<holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
		</copyright>
		<author>
			<firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
			<surname>Yuen</surname>
		</author>
		<address><email>rwsy@mit.edu</email></address>
	</sect1info>-->

	<title>Freecell</title>

	<para>Written by Changwoo Ryu</para>

	        <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


	<informaltable>
		<tgroup cols="2">
			<tbody>
	<row>
		<entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
		<entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Ρεζέρβες</entry>
		<entry>
			Four left piles on top row.  Each Reserve pile can only hold one card.
		</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Βάσεις</entry>
		<entry>
			Four piles top right.  To be built up in suit from Ace to
			King.  Cards in Foundations are no longer in play.
		</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
		<entry>
			Eight piles.  Deal all cards face up on to these eight piles, ending
			up with seven cards in each of the first four piles and six cards in
			the last four piles.  Tableau can be built down in alternating
			colors.  Cards can only be moved singly, but as a shortcut, if there
			are enough Reserve piles free to allow it, cards in sequence can be
			moved together.
		</entry>
	</row>
			</tbody>
		</tgroup>
	</informaltable>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

	<para>Μετακίνηση όλων των φύλλων στις βάσεις</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

	<para>
		Cards in the Tableau are built down by alternating color.  Groups of
		cards can be moved if there are enough Reserve piles free to allow the
		move if the cards were moved singly.  An empty pile in the Tableau can
		be filled with any card or group of cards.
	</para>
	<para>
		Foundations are built up in suit from Ace to King.  Cards in Foundations
		are not in play.  Double clicking on a card will move it to the
		appropriate Foundation pile if such a move is possible.
	</para>
	<para>
		Cards in Reserve piles can be played back on to Tableau or on to the
		Foundation.
	</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

	<para>Κάθε φύλλο που τοποθετείται στις βάσεις αντιστοιχεί σε 1 βαθμό.</para>
	<para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 52</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

	<para>
		Space is a valuable commodity.  Keep as many of the Reserve piles free
		as possible.
	</para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Gaps"><!--<sect1info>
    <copyright>
      <year>2005</year>
      <holder>Zach Keene</holder>
    </copyright>
    <author>
      <firstname>Zach</firstname>
      <surname>Keene</surname>
    </author>
    <address><email>zjkeene@bellsouth.net</email></address>
  </sect1info>-->

  <title>Gaps</title>

  <para>Γράφτηκε από τον Zach Keen</para>

          <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


  <informaltable>
    <tgroup cols="2"><tbody>
	<row>
	  <entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
	  <entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Μάνα</entry>
	  <entry>
	    All cards are dealt into four rows of 13 cards each; the aces
	are then discarded to leave four gaps. Two redeals are allowed.
	  </entry>
	</row>
      </tbody>
    </tgroup>
  </informaltable>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

  <para>
    To place all cards in sequence from 2 to king, in suit.
  </para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

  <para>
    Gaps in the leftmost column may be filled by moving a 2 of any suit
  there. A gap to the right of any non-King card may be filled by placing
  the card with the same suit but one rank higher into the gap. Gaps
  following Kings or other gaps may not be filled.
  </para>
  <para>
    Once a card is placed in a sequence starting with a 2 in the leftmost
  slot, it can no longer be moved.
  </para>
  <para>
    If no moves are possible (i.e., all gaps follow Kings),
  double-clicking any card will cause a redeal. Any cards not in sequence
  will be removed, shuffled, and redealt. Only two redeals are allowed.
  </para>

            </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Options</title>

    <para>
     Randomly Placed Gaps on Redeal: Check this to have randomly placed gaps 
 after a redeal. If unchecked, the gaps will always be placed directly to the 
 right of any cards already in sequence after redealing.
    </para>


          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

  <para>
    Each card placed in sequence, starting with a two in the leftmost slot,
    is worth one point.
  </para>
  <para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 48</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

  <para>
    Put off making any move that will add a gap after a king for as long as possible.
  </para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Gay_Gordons"><!--<sect1info>
		<copyright>
			<year>2001</year>
			<holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
		</copyright>
		<author>
			<firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
			<surname>Yuen</surname>
		</author>
		<address><email>zana@webwynk.net</email></address>
	</sect1info>-->

	<title>Gay Gordons</title>

  <para>Γράφτηκε από τη Rosanna Yuen</para>

          <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


  <informaltable>
    <tgroup cols="2">
      <tbody>
	<row>
	  <entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
	  <entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Ρεζέρβα</entry>
	  <entry>
	    Top left pile.  Deal two cards face up here.  The top card
	    is in play.  Cannot be refilled or built on.
	  </entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
	  <entry>
	    Ten piles.  Deal five cards face up in each pile.  The top
	    card in each pile is in play.  Empty piles cannot be filled.
	  </entry>
	</row>
      </tbody>
    </tgroup>
  </informaltable>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

  <para>Απομάκρυνση όλων των φύλλων.</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

  <para>
    Remove cards in pairs that add up to eleven.  Kings are paired off
    with Queens.  Jacks are paired off with other Jacks.
  </para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

  <para>
    Each pair of cards removed scores two points.
  </para>
  <para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 52</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

  <para>
    Try to uncover cards that are buried under their pair-mate.
  </para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Giant"><!--<sect1info>
		<copyright>
			<year>2009</year>
			<holder>Ed Sirett</holder>
		</copyright>
		<author>
			<firstname>Ed</firstname>
			<surname>Sirett</surname>
		</author>
		<address><email>ed@makewrite.demon.co.uk</email></address>
	</sect1info>-->

	<title>Giant</title>

  <para>Γράφτηκε από τον Ed Sirett</para>

          <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


  <informaltable>
    <tgroup cols="2">
      <tbody>
	<row>
	  <entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
	  <entry>Δύο τράπουλες</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Μάνα</entry>
	  <entry>
	    Top left pile.  All cards are placed here after dealing on
	    the Tableau.  Cards are dealt a row at a time onto the tableau piles.
	    No redeals.
	  </entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Βάσεις</entry>
	  <entry>
	    Eight piles top right.  To be built up in suit from Ace to
	    King.  Topmost card in each Foundation can be played back on
	    to the Tableau.
	  </entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
	  <entry>
	    Eight piles.  Deal one card face up to all eight piles.
	  </entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Ρεζέρβα</entry>
	  <entry>
	    To the right of the Tableau. Initially empty. May contain any single card.
	  </entry>
	</row>
      </tbody>
    </tgroup>
  </informaltable>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

  <para>Μετακίνηση όλων των φύλλων στις βάσεις</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

  <para>
    Cards in the Tableau are built down by alternating-colors. Cards are
    moved singly or in groups.  An empty slot in the Tableau can be filled with any card. There is an option to restrict the movement to
    only cards of the same suit. See below.
  </para>
  <para>
    Cards are dealt from the Stock to the Tableau in complete rows. The reserve may be empty or
    occupied as you wish.
  </para>
  <para>
    Foundations are built up from suit from Ace to King.  Top cards in
    Foundations are still in play.  Double clicking on a card will move
    it to the appropriate Foundation pile if such a move is possible. Double clicking on a Foundation
    will automatically move as many cards as possible to the Foundations.
  </para>
          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Options</title>

  <para>
    There are two ways to play. The difference between them
    is in how the cards may be built in the tableau.
  </para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry><term>Same suit</term>
      <listitem>
      <para>Cards must be of the same suit to be moved as a group and must be placed on a card of the same suit.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry><term>Alternating colors</term>
      <listitem>
         <para>To be moved as a gorup cards must be in a sequence of alternaing colors. The top card must be placed on a card of
               the opposite color.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

  <para>Κάθε φύλλο που τοποθετείται στις βάσεις αντιστοιχεί σε 1 βαθμό.</para>
  <para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 104</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

  <para>
    Avoid leaving small cards buried in the tableau. Use the Reserve wisely.
  </para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Glenwood"><!--<sect1info>
		<copyright>
			<year>2001</year>
			<holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
		</copyright>
		<author>
			<firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
			<surname>Yuen</surname>
		</author>
		<address><email>zana@webwynk.net</email></address>
	</sect1info>-->

	<title>Glenwood</title>

  <para>Γράφτηκε από τη Rosanna Yuen</para>

          <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


  <informaltable>
    <tgroup cols="2">
      <tbody>
	<row>
	  <entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
	  <entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Μάνα</entry>
	  <entry>
	  	Top left pile.  The rest of the deck is placed here after
	    dealing the Tableau and Reserves.  Cards are turned over one at a
	    time to Waste.  One redeal.
	  </entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Σωρός</entry>
	  <entry>Προέρχονται από τη μάνα. Μπορείτε να παίξετε το πάνω φύλλο.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Βάσεις</entry>
	  <entry>
	  	Four piles top right.  First Foundation pile is started by
	    player selecting a card from the Reserves.  Built up by suit,
	    wrapping from King to Ace when necessary.
	  </entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Ρεζέρβες</entry>
	  <entry>
	 		Four piles of three cards each on the left hand side
	  	dealt face up.  The top card in each Reserve is available for
	  	play.  No cards can be put in empty Reserve piles.
	  </entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
	  <entry>
	  	Four piles below Foundations.  Deal one card face up on to
	  	each pile.  Tableau can be built down in alternating color.
	  	Top card can be played on to Foundation.  Whole piles can be
	  	played on to another Tableau.
	  </entry>
	</row>
      </tbody>
    </tgroup>
  </informaltable>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

  <para>Μετακίνηση όλων των φύλλων στις βάσεις</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

  <para>
    The first item of play is to select an available card for the first
    Foundation.  Once selected, all other Foundations must also start
    with this value.
  </para>
  <para>
    Foundations are built up by suit, wrapping from King to Ace where
    necessary.  Once a card is placed on a Foundation pile, it is out of
    play.
  </para>
  <para>
    Cards in the Tableau are built down by alternating color.  Whole
    piles of cards can be moved on to another Tableau pile.  Empty slots
    in the Tableau can be filled by any available card in the Reserves
    or, if all the Reserves are empty, from the Waste.
  </para>
  <para>
    Cards are flipped singly from Stock to Waste.  There is one redeal.
  </para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

  <para>Κάθε φύλλο που τοποθετείται στις βάσεις αντιστοιχεί σε 1 βαθμό.</para>
  <para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 52</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

  <para>
    Be careful when selecting your first Foundation pile.  Try to get
    the cards out of the Reserves as early as possible.  Sometimes
    keeping cards in play is more important than moving them to the
    Foundation.
  </para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Gold_Mine"><!--<sect1info>
    <copyright>
      <year>2005</year>
      <holder>Alan Horkan</holder>
    </copyright>
    <author>
      <firstname>Alan</firstname>
      <surname>Horkan</surname>
    </author>
  </sect1info>-->

  <title>Gold Mine</title>

  <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>

  <informaltable>
    <tgroup cols="2"><tbody>
	<row>
	  <entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
	  <entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Μάνα</entry>
	  <entry>
	    Top left pile.  The rest of the deck is placed here after
	    dealing on to the Tableau.  Cards are turned over three at a
	    time to Waste.  
	    No redeals.
	  </entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Σωρός</entry>
	  <entry>Προέρχονται από τη μάνα. Μπορείτε να παίξετε το πάνω φύλλο.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Βάσεις</entry>
	  <entry>Οι τέσσερις στοίβες πάνω δεξιά. Τα φύλλα τοποθετούνται ανά φυλή και σε αύξουσα σειρά, από τον Άσσο στο Ρήγα. Σε κάθε βάση, το πάνω φύλλο μπορεί να παιχθεί στο ταμπλό.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
	  <entry>
	    Seven piles, all empty to start.  
        Gold Mine is a variation of <ulink type="help" url="ghelp:aisleriot#Klondike">Klondike</ulink>.  
	    Tableau can be built down in alternating colors.  Groups of
	    cards can be moved.  Empty piles can be filled with any card. 
	  </entry>
	</row>
      </tbody>
    </tgroup>
  </informaltable>

  </sect2>

  <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>
  <para>Μετακίνηση όλων των φύλλων στις βάσεις</para>
  </sect2>

  <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>
  <para>
    Cards in the Tableau are built down by alternating color.  Groups of
    cards can be moved.  An empty pile in the Tableau can be filled with
    any card.  
  </para>
  <para>
    Cards are flipped from the Stock to the Waste three at a time.  Top
    card in Waste is in play.  When Stock is empty, game over.  
    Only one chance to get it right and establish your gold mine.  
  </para>
  <para>Στις βάσεις τα φύλλα μπαίνουν ανά φυλή και σε αύξουσα σειρά από τον Άσσο στο Ρήγα. Τα φύλλα στις βάσεις δε βγαίνουν από το παιχνίδι. Αν κάνετε διπλό κλικ σε ένα φύλλο, το φύλλο αυτό θα ανέβει στις βάσεις, εφόσον επιτρέπεται η κίνηση.</para>
  </sect2>

  <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>
  <para>Κάθε φύλλο που τοποθετείται στις βάσεις αντιστοιχεί σε 1 βαθμό.</para>
  <para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 52</para>
  </sect2>

  <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>
  <para>
    Be careful how you fill the empty foundation piles.  
    With skill it is possible to win Gold Mine most of the time.  
    If at first you do not succeed restart and try again.  
  </para>
  </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Golf"><!--<sect1info>
    <copyright>
      <year>2001</year>
      <holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
    </copyright>
    <author>
      <firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
      <surname>Yuen</surname>
    </author>
    <address>
      <email>zana@webwynk.net</email>
    </address>
  </sect1info>-->

  <title>Golf</title>

  <para>Γράφτηκε από τη Rosanna Yuen</para>

          <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


  <informaltable>
    <tgroup cols="2">
      <tbody>
	<row>
	  <entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
	  <entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Μάνα</entry>
	  <entry>
	    Place all remaining cards here.  Cards are turned over one
	    at a time to Waste.  No redeals.
	  </entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Σωρός</entry>
	  <entry>Προέρχονται από τη μάνα. Μπορείτε να παίξετε το πάνω φύλλο.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
	  <entry>
	    Seven piles.  Deal five cards face up on every pile.
	  </entry>
	</row>
      </tbody>
    </tgroup>
  </informaltable>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

  <para>
    Move all cards to Waste.
  </para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

  <para>
    The Waste can be built up or down from the available cards on the
    Tableau.  Only Deuces can be placed on Aces and nothing can be
    played on to a King.
  </para>
  <para>
    Cards are dealt singly from Stock to Waste.  There are no redeals.
  </para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

  <para>
    Every card moved from Tableau to Waste scores one point.
  </para>
  <para>
    Maximum possible score:  35
  </para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

  <para>
    Remember that nothing can be played on to a King.  Try to generate
    sequences where many cards can be removed without a new card from
    Stock.
  </para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Gypsy"><!--<sect1info>
		<copyright>
			<year>2001</year>
			<holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
		</copyright>
		<author>
			<firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
			<surname>Yuen</surname>
		</author>
		<address><email>zana@webwynk.net</email></address>
	</sect1info>-->

	<title>Gypsy</title>

  <para>Γράφτηκε από τη Rosanna Yuen</para>

          <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


  <informaltable>
    <tgroup cols="2">
      <tbody>
	<row>
	  <entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
	  <entry>Δύο τράπουλες</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Μάνα</entry>
	  <entry>
	  	Top left pile.  The rest of the deck is placed here after
	    dealing the Tableau.  Cards are dealt in batches of eight,
	    one on every Tableau.
	  </entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Βάσεις</entry>
	  <entry>
	  	Eight piles top right.  To be built in suit from Ace to
	    King.  Topmost card in each Foundation can be played back on
	    to the Tableau.
	  </entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
    <entry>
    	Eight piles.  Deal two rows face down and one row face
      up to start.  Tableau can be built down in alternating
      colors.  Builds of cards can be moved.  Empty piles can be
      filled with any card or build.
     </entry>
	</row>
      </tbody>
    </tgroup>
  </informaltable>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

  <para>Μετακίνηση όλων των φύλλων στις βάσεις</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

  <para>
    Cards in Tableau are built down by alternating color.  Builds of
    cards can be  moved.  An empty pile in the Tableau can be filled
    with any card or build of cards.
  </para>
  <para>Σε κάθε νέα μοιρασιά, η μάνα μοιράζει ένα φύλλο σε κάθε στήλη του ταμπλό. Αν τελειώσουν τα φύλλα της μάνας, δεν μπορεί να γίνει νέα μοιρασιά.</para>
  <para>Στις βάσεις τα φύλλα τοποθετούνται ανά φυλή και με αύξουσα σειρά, από τον Άσσο στο Ρήγα. Τα φύλλα στις βάσεις παραμένουν στο παιχνίδι. Αν κάνετε διπλό κλικ σε ένα φύλλο στο ταμπλό, το φύλλο θα ανέβει στις βάσεις, εφόσον επιτρέπεται η κίνηση.</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

  <para>
    Each card in the Foundation scores 5 points.  When a Foundation pile
    is complete (from Ace to King), 60 more points are scored.  Each
    card pair on the Tableau in alternating order scores 2 points.
  </para>
  <para>
    Maximum possible score:  1000
  </para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

  <para>
    Try and expose new cards in the Tableau whenever possible.  Remember
    you can always bring cards from the Foundation back into play.
  </para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Helsinki">  <!--<sect1info>
    <copyright>
      <year>2001</year>
      <holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
    </copyright>
    <author>
      <firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
      <surname>Yuen</surname></author>
    <address><email>zana@webwynk.net</email></address>
  </sect1info>-->

  <title>Helsinki</title>

  <para>Γράφτηκε από τη Rosanna Yuen</para>

          <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


  <informaltable>
    <tgroup cols="2">
      <tbody>
	<row>
	  <entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
	  <entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Μάνα</entry>
	  <entry>
	    Top left pile.  The rest of the deck is placed here after
	    dealing the Tableau.  Cards are automatically placed on to
	    the Tableau whenever a space opens up.
	  </entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
	  <entry>
	    Ten piles.  Deal a card face up in every pile.
	  </entry>
	</row>
      </tbody>
    </tgroup>
  </informaltable>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

  <para>Απομάκρυνση όλων των φύλλων.</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

  <para>
    Remove cards in pairs that add up to thirteen with Aces being one,
    Jacks being eleven, and Queens being twelve.  Kings are removed
    singly.
  </para>
  <para>
    Empty Tableau piles are automatically filled from the Stock.
  </para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

  <para>Κάθε φύλλο που απομακρύνεται αντιστοιχεί σε 1 βαθμό.</para>
  <para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 52</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

  <para>
    Go as fast as you can.
  </para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Hopscotch"><!--<sect1info>
		<copyright>
			<year>1999</year>
			<holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
		</copyright>
		<author>
			<firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
			<surname>Yuen</surname>
		</author>
		<address><email>rwsy@mit.edu</email></address>
	</sect1info>-->

	<title>Hopscotch</title>

	<para>Γράφτηκε από τη Rosanna Yuen</para>

	        <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


	<informaltable>
		<tgroup cols="2">
			<tbody>
	<row>
		<entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
		<entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Μάνα</entry>
		<entry>
			Top left pile.  All cards except the Ace to four of clubs are placed
			here at beginning of play.  Cards are dealt singly to Waste.
		</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Σωρός</entry>
		<entry>
			Directly to the right of Stock.  Can only hold one card at a time.
			Card must immediately be placed on either a Foundation pile or on to
			the Reserve pile of your choice.
		</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Βάσεις</entry>
		<entry>
			Four piles on top, to the right of Stock.  Place an Ace on the first
			pile, a two on the second pile, a three on the third pile, and a four
			on the fourth pile.  The first Foundation pile is built up by one,
			the second is built up by two, the third by three, and the fourth by
			four, all of which wrap around to Ace when it reaches past thirteen.
			cards in Foundations are no longer in play.  Suits do not matter.
		</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Ρεζέρβα</entry>
		<entry>
			Four piles placed underneath Foundations.  Cards in Reserve can only
			be played on to Foundation piles.  Cards moved from Waste can be
			placed on any of the Reserve piles.
		</entry>
	</row>
			</tbody>
		</tgroup>
	</informaltable>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

	<para>Μετακίνηση όλων των φύλλων στις βάσεις.</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

	<para>
		Build on to Foundations by ones, twos, threes, and fours for piles
		one, two, three, and four respectively.  Cards are dealt singly in to
		the Waste from the Stock.  However, as the Waste pile can only hold
		one card, this card must immediately be played on to a Foundation pile
		or on to any of the four Reserve piles.  Cards in the Reserve piles
		cannot be rearranged.
	</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

	<para>
		Each card moved to Foundations scores one point.
	</para>
	<para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 48</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

	<para>
		Hone your skills for this game.  Luck will not get you very far here.
		Try not to cover cards you might need sooner.  Consider saving a
		column just for kings (as they are the last card to be played on each
		Foundation).
	</para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Isabel"><!--<sect1info>
		<copyright>
			<year>2001</year>
			<holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
		</copyright>
		<author>
			<firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
			<surname>Yuen</surname>
		</author>
		<address><email>zana@webwynk.net</email></address>
	</sect1info>-->

	<title>Isabel</title>

  <para>Γράφτηκε από τη Rosanna Yuen</para>

          <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


  <informaltable>
    <tgroup cols="2">
      <tbody>
	<row>
	  <entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
	  <entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
	  <entry>Δεκατρείς στήλες. Σε κάθε στήλη μοιράζονται τρία φύλλα κλειστά και ένα ανοιχτό.</entry>
	</row>
      </tbody>
    </tgroup>
  </informaltable>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

  <para>Απομάκρυνση όλων των φύλλων.</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

  <para>
    Remove cards in pairs of equal rank.  Every time a card is removed,
    the card underneath is flipped face up and becomes playable.  Empty
    slots are not filled.
  </para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

  <para>
    Each pair of cards removed scores two points.
  </para>
  <para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 52</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

  <para>
    Each pile starts with four cards.  The trick is to remember how many
    cards each slot has left at any given time so that you can try to
    remove cards evenly.
  </para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Jamestown"><!--<sect1info>
		<copyright>
			<year>2001</year>
			<holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
		</copyright>
		<author>
			<firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
			<surname>Yuen</surname>
		</author>
		<address><email>zana@webwynk.net</email></address>
	</sect1info>-->

	<title>Jamestown</title>

  <para>Γράφτηκε από τη Rosanna Yuen</para>

          <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


  <informaltable>
    <tgroup cols="2">
      <tbody>
	<row>
	  <entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
	  <entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Μάνα</entry>
	  <entry>Η στοίβα πάνω αριστερά. Στην αρχή της παρτίδας όλα τα φύλλα τοποθετούνται εδώ.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
	  <entry>Εννέα στοίβες που σχηματίζουν ένα τετράγωνο 3Χ3. Σε κάθε στοίβα του ταμπλό μοιράζεται από ένα ανοιχτό φύλλο.</entry>
	</row>
      </tbody>
    </tgroup>
  </informaltable>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

  <para>Απομάκρυνση όλων των φύλλων.</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

  <para>
    Remove pairs of cards with the same rank.  Empty piles are
    automatically filled from the Stock.
  </para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

  <para>Κάθε ζεύγος που απομακρύνεται αντιστοιχεί σε δύο βαθμούς.</para>
  <para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 52</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

  <para>
    Remove pairs of cards as fast as possible.  That is the only challenge.
  </para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Jumbo"><!--<sect1info>
		<copyright>
			<year>2001</year>
			<holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
		</copyright>
		<author>
			<firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
			<surname>Yuen</surname>
		</author>
		<address><email>zana@webwynk.net</email></address>
	</sect1info>-->

	<title>Jumbo</title>

  <para>Γράφτηκε από τη Rosanna Yuen</para>

          <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


  <informaltable>
    <tgroup cols="2">
      <tbody>
	<row>
	  <entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
	  <entry>Δύο τράπουλες</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Μάνα</entry>
	  <entry>
	    Top left pile.  All cards are placed here after dealing on
	    the Tableau.  Cards are turned over one at a time to Waste.
	    One redeal.
	  </entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Σωρός</entry>
	  <entry>
	    Directly to the right of the Stock.  Cards to be dealt from
	    the Stock during play one at a time.  Top card available for
	    play.
	  </entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Βάσεις</entry>
	  <entry>
	    Eight piles top right.  To be built up in suit from Ace to
	    King.  Topmost card in each Foundation can be played back on
	    to the Tableau.
	  </entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
	  <entry>
	    Nine piles.  Deal one card face down to all nine piles, then
	    one card to first eight piles, followed by one card to first
	    seven piles, etc. until there are nine cards in the first
	    pile.  Flip the last card dealt on each pile.
	  </entry>
	</row>
      </tbody>
    </tgroup>
  </informaltable>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

  <para>Μετακίνηση όλων των φύλλων στις βάσεις</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

  <para>Μπορείτε να τοποθετείτε φύλλα στο ταμπλό με φθίνουσα σειρά και σε εναλλασσόμενο χρώμα. Μπορείτε να μετακινείτε ομάδες φύλλων. Αν μία στήλη είναι κενή, μπορείτε να τοποθετήσετε μόνο Ρήγα ή ομάδα φύλλων που ξεκινάει με Ρήγα.</para>
  <para>
    Cards are flipped from the Stock to the Waste individually.  Top
    card in Waste is in play.  When Stock is empty, move all cards in
    Waste back to the Stock, maintaining order.  There is one redeal.
  </para>
  <para>
    Foundations are built up from suit from Ace to King.  Cards in
    Foundations are still in play.  Double clicking on a card will move
    it to the appropriate Foundation pile if such a move is possible.
  </para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

  <para>Κάθε φύλλο που τοποθετείται στις βάσεις αντιστοιχεί σε 1 βαθμό.</para>
  <para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 104</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

  <para>

  </para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Kansas"><!--<sect1info>
		<copyright>
			<year>1999</year>
			<holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
		</copyright>
		<author>
			<firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
			<surname>Yuen</surname>
		</author>
		<address><email>rwsy@mit.edu</email></address>
	</sect1info>-->

	<title>Kansas</title>

	<para>Γράφτηκε από τη Rosanna Yuen</para>

	        <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


	<informaltable>
		<tgroup cols="2">
			<tbody>
	<row>
		<entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
		<entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Μάνα</entry>
		<entry>
			Top left pile.  The rest of the deck is placed here after
			dealing the Tableau.  Cards are turned over one at a time to Waste.  No
			redeals.
		</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Σωρός</entry>
		<entry>Προέρχονται από τη μάνα. Μπορείτε να παίξετε το πάνω φύλλο.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Βάσεις</entry>
		<entry>
			Four piles on top right.  Deal one card on first Foundation pile to
			start.  Other Foundation piles are to be started with the other three
			cards with the same rank as this base card.  All four piles are to be
			built up, with the ranks continuous.
		</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Ρεζέρβα</entry>
		<entry>
			Pile under Stock.  Deal twelve cards here to begin.  Top card available
			for play on to Tableau or Foundation piles.
		</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
		<entry>
			Three piles bottom right.  Deal one card on each pile to start.  Piles
			can be built down regardless of suit.  Spaces are automatically filled
			from Reserve.  Once Reserve is empty, Tableau spaces can be filled from
			the Waste at your leisure.
		</entry>
	</row>
			</tbody>
		</tgroup>
	</informaltable>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

	<para>
		Move all cards on to Foundation piles.
	</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

	<para>
		Cards in the Tableau are built down regardless of suit.  Groups of cards
		can be moved.  An empty slot in the Tableau is filled automatically from
		the Reserve.  If the Reserve is empty, an empty slot can be filled by the
		top card of the Waste at your leisure.
	</para>
	<para>
		Cards can be flipped singly from the Stock to the Waste.  Top
		card is available for play.  There is no redeal.
	</para>
	<para>
		Foundations are built up in suit from the base card (first card dealt to
		first Foundation).  New Foundations are started when a card of the same
		rank as this base card is placed on an empty Foundation pile.  Aces are
		built on Kings, and twos on Aces.  Cards in Foundations are no longer in
		play.  Double clicking on a card will move it to the appropriate
		Foundation pile if such a move is possible.
	</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

	<para>Κάθε φύλλο που τοποθετείται στις βάσεις αντιστοιχεί σε 1 βαθμό.</para>
	<para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 52</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

	<para>
		You can't go digging through junkyards.  Once a card is buried in the
		waste, it is hard to get back.  Try and move as many cards from the
		Waste to the Tableau as possible.
	</para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="King_Albert">  <!--<sect1info>
    <copyright>
      <year>2001</year>
      <holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
    </copyright>
    <author>
      <firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
      <surname>Yuen</surname>
    </author>
    <address><email>zana@webwynk.net</email></address>
  </sect1info>-->

  <title>King Albert</title>

  <para>Γράφτηκε από τη Rosanna Yuen</para>

          <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


  <informaltable>
    <tgroup cols="2">
      <tbody>
	<row>
	  <entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
	  <entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Βάσεις</entry>
	  <entry>
	    Four piles on the top.  Foundations are built up in both
	    suit and sequence from Ace to King.
	  </entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Ρεζέρβα</entry>
	  <entry>
	    Seven piles on the right.  One card is dealt face up on each
	    Reserve pile at the start.  There is no building on the
	    Reserves.  Empty Reserve piles can not be filled.
	  </entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
	  <entry>
	    Nine piles of cards, with nine cards in the first pile,
	    eight in the second, and so on to the one card in the last
	    pile.  These cards are dealt face down.  The top card in
	    every pile is then flipped up.
	  </entry>
	</row>
      </tbody>
    </tgroup>
  </informaltable>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

  <para>Μετακίνηση όλων των φύλλων στις βάσεις</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

  <para>
    Cards in the Tableau are built down by alternating color.  Empty
    Tableau slots can be filled by any card or build of cards.
  </para>
  <para>
    Cards in the Reserve can be played on to the Tableau or the
    Foundation.  Empty Reserve piles cannot be filled.
  </para>
  <para>
    Foundation piles are built up in suit from Ace to King.  Cards in
    Foundation are still in play.
  </para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

  <para>Κάθε φύλλο που τοποθετείται στις βάσεις αντιστοιχεί σε 1 βαθμό.</para>
  <para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 52</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

  <para>
    Remember that any card can be placed on an empty Tableau slot.
    Exposing new cards is the top priority in this game.
  </para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Kings_Audience"><!--<sect1info>
    <copyright>
      <year>2005</year>
      <holder>Zach Keene</holder>
    </copyright>
    <author>
      <firstname>Zach</firstname>
      <surname>Keene</surname>
    </author>
    <address><email>zjkeene@bellsouth.net</email></address>
  </sect1info>-->

  <title>King's Audience</title>

  <para>Γράφτηκε από τον Zach Keen</para>

          <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


  <informaltable>
    <tgroup cols="2"><tbody>
	<row>
	  <entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
	  <entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
        <row>
          <entry>Reserves (Antechamber)</entry>
          <entry>
            The outer rectangle of sixteen cards. Cards in the reserve are
            available to play, and are replenished from the Waste 
            (or the Stock if no cards are currently in the Waste.)
          </entry>
        </row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Μάνα</entry>
	  <entry>
	    Left slot in the center row. Cards are dealt one at a time to the
            Waste. There is no redeal.
	  </entry>
	</row>
        <row>
          <entry>Σωρός</entry>
          <entry>
            Slot to the right of the Stock. The top card of the Waste is
            available to play.
          </entry>
        </row>
        <row>
          <entry>"Thrones"</entry>
          <entry>
            Top four slots in the "audience chamber" (the area inside the 
            surrounding sixteen cards.) Whenever a King and Queen of the same
            suit are available, they can be move to one of these
	    slots.
	  </entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Βάσεις</entry>
	  <entry>
            Bottom four slots in the audience chamber. Whenever a Jack and an 
            Ace of the same suit are available, they can be moved to an empty
            Foundation slot, with the Jack on top. The foundation then may be
            built down in suit.
	  </entry>
	</row>
      </tbody>
    </tgroup>
  </informaltable>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

  <para>
    Move all cards to the foundation piles or thrones.
  </para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

  <para>
    Deal cards one at a time from Stock to Waste. Whenever a King and Queen of
  the same suit are available, they can be moved into a throne slot by either
  by dragging the King onto the Queen (or vice versa) or double clicking either
  card. Whenever a Jack and Ace of the same suit are available, they can be 
  moved into a foundation slot in the same manner.
  </para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

  <para>
    Each card placed in the audience chamber receives one point.
  </para>
  <para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 52</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

  <para>
    None; King's Audience is pretty much entirely based on luck.
  </para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Klondike"><!--<sect1info>
    <copyright>
      <year>2001</year>
      <holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
    </copyright>
    <author>
      <firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
      <surname>Yuen</surname>
    </author>
    <address><email>zana@webwynk.net</email></address>
  </sect1info>-->

  <title>Klondike</title>

  <para>Written by Jonathan Blandford</para>

          <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


  <informaltable>
    <tgroup cols="2"><tbody>
	<row>
	  <entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
	  <entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Μάνα</entry>
	  <entry>Η στοίβα πάνω αριστερά. Όταν ολοκληρωθεί η μοιρασιά, τα υπόλοιπα φύλλα τοποθετούνται εδώ. Τα φύλλα της μάνας ανοίγουν ένα ένα και τοποθετούνται στο σωρό. Ο παίκτης δύο επιπλέον μοιρασιές.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Σωρός</entry>
	  <entry>Προέρχονται από τη μάνα. Μπορείτε να παίξετε το πάνω φύλλο.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Βάσεις</entry>
	  <entry>Οι τέσσερις στοίβες πάνω δεξιά. Τα φύλλα τοποθετούνται ανά φυλή και σε αύξουσα σειρά, από τον Άσσο στο Ρήγα. Σε κάθε βάση, το πάνω φύλλο μπορεί να παιχθεί στο ταμπλό.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
	  <entry>
	    Seven piles.  Deal card face up in first pile.  Place one
	    card face down on all other piles.  Place one card face up
	    on next pile followed by one card face down on all covered
	    piles.  Repeat until there are seven cards in last pile.
	    Tableau can be built down in alternating colors.  Groups of
	    cards can be moved.  Empty piles can only be filled by Kings
	    or group of cards starting with a King.
	  </entry>
	</row>
      </tbody>
    </tgroup>
  </informaltable>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

  <para>Μετακίνηση όλων των φύλλων στις βάσεις</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

  <para>Μπορείτε να τοποθετείτε φύλλα στο ταμπλό με φθίνουσα σειρά και σε εναλλασσόμενο χρώμα. Μπορείτε να μετακινείτε ομάδες φύλλων. Αν μία στήλη είναι κενή, μπορείτε να τοποθετήσετε μόνο Ρήγα ή ομάδα φύλλων που ξεκινάει με Ρήγα.</para>
  <para>Τα φύλλα της μάνας μοιράζονται ένα ένα και τοποθετούνται στο σωρό. Μπορείτε να παίζετε το πάνω φύλλο στο σωρό. Αν αδειάσει η μάνα, όλα τα φύλλα του σωρού μετακινούνται στη μάνα, χωρίς να αλλάξει η σειρά. Συνολικά επιτρέπονται τρεις μοιρασιές.</para>
  <para>Στις βάσεις τα φύλλα μπαίνουν ανά φυλή και σε αύξουσα σειρά από τον Άσσο στο Ρήγα. Τα φύλλα στις βάσεις δε βγαίνουν από το παιχνίδι. Αν κάνετε διπλό κλικ σε ένα φύλλο, το φύλλο αυτό θα ανέβει στις βάσεις, εφόσον επιτρέπεται η κίνηση.</para>
  <para>
    Double clicking on a foundation card will move all the cards that
    can be moved to the foundation to the foundation. This
    is useful for cleaning up at the end of the game.
  </para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Options</title>

  <para>
    There are three possible ways to play. The difference between them
    is in how the cards are dealt from the stock.
  </para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry><term>Three card deals</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Cards are dealt from the stock three at a time. There is no limit to how many times you can redeal the stock.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry><term>Single card deals</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Cards are dealt from the stock one at a time. However you can only turn the stock over and redeal twice.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry><term>No redeals</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Cards are dealt one at a time from the stock. There is no redeal. Play this way if you want a challenge (and some frustration).</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  
  <para>Most likely you will consider one of the first two methods
  traditional - depending on where you live and who taught you. The no
  redeals option is the one normally found in older sets of rules, but
  the game is rarely played that way.</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

  <para>Κάθε φύλλο που τοποθετείται στις βάσεις αντιστοιχεί σε 1 βαθμό.</para>
  <para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 52</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

  <para>Μην εγκαταλείπετε εύκολα! Αν κινδυνεύετε να χάσετε, δοκιμάστε όλες τις πιθανές κινήσεις με τη σειρά. Ορισμένες φορές μπορείτε να χρησιμοποιήσετε φύλλα από τις βάσεις σε συνδυασμό με την αναδιάταξη φύλλων στο ταμπλό για να αποκαλύψετε επιπλέον κλειστά φύλλα.</para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Labyrinth"><!--<sect1info>
		<copyright>
			<year>2001</year>
			<holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
		</copyright>
		<author>
			<firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
			<surname>Yuen</surname>
		</author>
		<address><email>zana@webwynk.net</email></address>
	</sect1info>-->

	<title>Labyrinth</title>

  <para>Γράφτηκε από τη Rosanna Yuen</para>

          <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


  <informaltable>
    <tgroup cols="2">
      <tbody>
	<row>
	  <entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
	  <entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Μάνα</entry>
	  <entry>
	  	Top left pile.  The rest of the deck is placed here after
	    dealing the Tableau.
	  </entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Βάσεις</entry>
	  <entry>
	  	Four piles top right.  Aces are placed in their
	  	respective Foundation pile prior to shuffling the deck.
	  </entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
	  <entry>
	  	One card is dealt face up in each Tableau pile at the
	  	start of the game.
	  </entry>
	</row>
      </tbody>
    </tgroup>
  </informaltable>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

  <para>Μετακίνηση όλων των φύλλων στις βάσεις</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

  <para>
    Build any cards from the Tableau in suit and sequence on to the
    Foundation.  Spaces are automatically filled from the Stock.
  </para>
  <para>
    Once the eight cards in the Tableau piles cannot be played, click on
    the Stock to deal a card to each pile.  Empty slots in the Tableau
    are no longer filled automatically.
  </para>
  <para>
    Cards at the top and bottom of each Tableau pile is available for
    play on to the Foundation piles.  There is no building on the
    Tableau.  There is no redeal.
  </para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

  <para>Κάθε φύλλο που τοποθετείται στις βάσεις αντιστοιχεί σε 1 βαθμό.</para>
  <para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 48</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

  <para>
    Get plenty of sleep the night before so that you are bright and
    alert when you play this game.  Move any card you possibly can on to
    the Foundation piles.  Have fun!
  </para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Lady_Jane"><!--<sect1info>
		<copyright>
			<year>1999</year>
			<holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
		</copyright>
		<author>
			<firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
			<surname>Yuen</surname>
		</author>
		<address><email>rwsy@mit.edu</email></address>
	</sect1info>-->

	<title>Lady Jane</title>

	<para>Γράφτηκε από τη Rosanna Yuen</para>

	        <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


	<informaltable>
		<tgroup cols="2">
			<tbody>
	<row>
		<entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
		<entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Μάνα</entry>
		<entry>
			Top left pile.  The rest of the deck is placed here after
			dealing.  Cards are turned on to the Reserve one on each pile per deal.
			When there are only two cards left in Stock, they are dealt such that
			both cards are available for play.
		</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Βάσεις</entry>
		<entry>
			Four piles on top right.  Deal one card on to first Foundation pile
			after dealing on to Tableau and Reserve.  This card is now the base
			card.  Built up by suit.
		</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Ρεζέρβα</entry>
		<entry>
			Seven piles on the right.  Top card of each pile is available for play
			on to either the Tableau or the Foundation.  Empty spaces are not filled
			except by a deal from Stock.
		</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
		<entry>
			Seven piles below Stock and Foundation.  Deal card face up in first
			pile.  Place one card face down on all other piles.  Place one card face
			up on next pile followed by one card face down on all covered piles.
			Repeat until there are seven cards in last pile.  Tableau can be built
			down in alternating colors.  Groups of cards can be moved.  Empty piles
			can only be filled by the card whose rank is one lower than the base
			card or group of cards starting with a card of this rank.
		</entry>
	</row>
			</tbody>
		</tgroup>
	</informaltable>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

	<para>
		Move all cards on to Foundation piles.
	</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

	<para>
		Cards in the Tableau are built down by alternating color.  Groups of
		cards can be moved.  An empty pile in the Tableau can be filled with a
		card whose rank is one lower than the base card or with a group of cards
		starting with a card with this rank.
	</para>
	<para>
		Cards are dealt from the Stock to the Reserve.  Each deal places one
		card on each pile of the Reserve.
	</para>
	<para>
		The top card of each Reserve pile is always available for play on to
		either the Tableau or the Foundation.  There is no building on the
		Reserve piles.
	</para>
	<para>
		Foundations are built up in suit from the base card.  New Foundations
		are started when a card of the same rank as the base card is placed on
		empty Foundation piles.  Aces are
		placed on Kings, and twos on Aces.  Cards in Foundations are still in
		play.  Double clicking on a card will move it to the appropriate
		Foundation pile if such a move is possible.
	</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

	<para>Κάθε φύλλο που τοποθετείται στις βάσεις αντιστοιχεί σε 1 βαθμό.</para>
	<para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 52</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

	<para>
		The deeper something is, the harder it is to get to.  Try and move cards
		out of the Reserve whenever possible.
	</para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Maze"><!--<sect1info>
		<copyright>
			<year>2000</year>
			<holder>Telsa Gwynne</holder>
		</copyright>
		<author>
			<firstname>Telsa</firstname>
			<surname>Gwynne</surname>
		</author>
		<address><email>telsa@linuxchix.org</email></address>
	</sect1info>-->

	<title>Maze</title>

  <para>Written by Matthew Wilcox</para>

          <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


	<informaltable>
		<tgroup cols="2">
			<tbody>
	<row>
		<entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
		<entry>48 cards: Standard Deck without the kings</entry>
	</row>

	<row>
		<entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
		<entry>
			Fifty-four spaces in six rows of nine each. Deal cards into
			spaces one to eight. Leave space nine blank. Deal cards into spaces
			ten to seventeen. Leave space eighteen blank. Deal the remaining
			cards similarly. Then remove all the kings (which play no further
			part in the game), so that six empty spaces remain in total. Any
			card can be moved into a space to the left of another card of the
			same suit and face value one higher. Any card can be moved
			into a space to the right of another card of the same suit and
			face value one lower. An ace may be moved to the right of a
			queen or in the top left space. A queen may be moved to the left
			of an ace or in the bottom right space.
		</entry>
	</row>
			</tbody>
		</tgroup>
	</informaltable>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

  <para>
    Put each suit of cards into ascending order, with an ace in the
    top left corner, to create a run of cards: Ace to Queen of one suit,
    Ace to Queen of another, Ace to Queen of the third, Ace to Queen
    of the fourth.
  </para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

  <para>
    Cards are moved singly. Any card can be moved into a space to the
    left of another card of face value one higher in the same suit. Any
    card can be moved into a space to the right of another card of face
    value one lower in the same suit.  An ace may be moved to the right
    of a queen or in the top left space. A queen may be moved to the left
    of an ace or in the bottom right space.
  </para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

  <para>
    Each card placed next to another card of the same suit in the
    correct order scores one point.
  </para>
  <para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 48</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

  <para>
    Multiple adjacent spaces enable you to generate long sequences of
    cards. Beware of getting trapped into a situation where you move
    one card endlessly between two points.
  </para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Monte_Carlo"><!--<sect1info>
		<copyright>
			<year>2001</year>
			<holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
		</copyright>
		<author>
			<firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
			<surname>Yuen</surname>
		</author>
		<address><email>zana@webwynk.net</email></address>
	</sect1info>-->

	<title>Monte Carlo</title>

  <para>Γράφτηκε από τη Rosanna Yuen</para>

          <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


  <informaltable>
    <tgroup cols="2">
      <tbody>
	<row>
	  <entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
	  <entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Μάνα</entry>
	  <entry>
	  	Top left pile.  The rest of the deck is placed here after
	    dealing the Tableau.  Cards are dealt after concatenating
	    the Tableau onto the empty slots.
	  </entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
	  <entry>
	  	Five by five grid, each capable of holding one card.
		  One card dealt to each space at the beginning of game.  Empty
		  spaces can be filled by moving cards from the right to the
		  left, from the leftmost card of the row below to the rightmost
		  space, and from the Stock to all otherwise empty spaces by
		  clicking on the Stock.
		</entry>
	</row>
      </tbody>
    </tgroup>
  </informaltable>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

  <para>Απομάκρυνση όλων των φύλλων.</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

  <para>
    Cards can be removed in pairs that have the same value as long as
    the two cards are touching horizontally, vertically, or diagonally.
  </para>
  <para>
    At any point that there are empty piles in the Tableau, dealing from
    the Stock moves all the cards already in the Tableau from the right
    to left and moving them up a row to the far right if necessary
    making all the empty slots at the end.  The Stock is then dealt on
    to these empty slots.
  </para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

  <para>
    Each pair of cards removed scores two points.
  </para>
  <para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 52</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

  <para>
    Keep an eye out as to how the Tableau will shrink when you deal.
    Sometimes leaving pairs in will allow more pairs to become available
    after a deal.
  </para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Napoleons_Tomb"><!--<sect1info>
		<copyright>
			<year>2007</year>
			<holder>Kimmo Karlsson</holder>
		</copyright>
		<author>
			<firstname>Kimmo</firstname>
			<surname>Karlsson</surname>
		</author>
		<address><email>kimmo.karlsson@gmail.com</email></address>
	</sect1info>-->

	<title>Napoleon's Tomb</title>

  <para>Written by Kimmo Karlsson</para>

          <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


  <informaltable>
    <tgroup cols="2">
      <tbody>
	<row>
		<entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
		<entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Μάνα</entry>
		<entry>
			Top left pile.
		</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Σωρός</entry>
		<entry>
			Next to Stock. 
		</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
		<entry>
			Three by three grid, all face up.
		</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Βάσεις</entry>
		<entry>
		Center pile of the grid is to be built down, 
		corners to be built up.  Suit doesn't count.
		</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Ρεζέρβες</entry>
		<entry>
		Four piles on the grid that are not foundations.
		Each reserve can hold only one card at a time.
		</entry>
	</row>
      </tbody>
    </tgroup>
  </informaltable>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

  <para>
  Move all cards of 6 or smaller to the center pile, 7 or greater to corner piles.
  </para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

  <para>
    Click on the stock to flip over cards.  Move one card at the time to the tableau.  Once placed on a foundation pile, a card cannot be moved.  Each corner pile is built up from 7 to king.  Center pile is built down from 6 to ace.  After ace comes another 6, etc.  Suit doesn't count.
  </para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Options</title>

  <para>
  Deal Three Cards: If you deal three cards at a time from the stock, you get to go through the deck three times. 
  </para>
  <para>
  Autoplay: If autoplay is activated, cards are automatically placed to foundation piles as soon as possible.
  </para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

  <para>Κάθε φύλλο που τοποθετείται στις βάσεις αντιστοιχεί σε 1 βαθμό.</para>

  <para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 52</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

  <para>
  Try to keep reserve. It's not easy to get Napoleon to his tomb, but keep trying.
  </para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Neighbor"><!--<sect1info>
		<copyright>
			<year>1998</year>
			<holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
		</copyright>
		<author>
			<firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
			<surname>Yuen</surname>
		</author>
		<address><email>rwsy@mit.edu</email></address>
	</sect1info>-->

	<title>Neighbor</title>

	<para>Γράφτηκε από τη Rosanna Yuen</para>

	        <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


	<informaltable>
		<tgroup cols="2">
			<tbody>
	<row>
		<entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
		<entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Μάνα</entry>
		<entry>
		  Top left pile.
			Dealt to the Tableau in the manner described below.
		</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
		<entry>
			Five by five grid, each capable of holding one card.  One card dealt to
			each space at the beginning of game.  Empty spaces automatically filled
			by moving cards from the right to the left, from the leftmost card of
			the row below to the rightmost space, and from the Stock to all
			otherwise empty spaces.
		</entry>
	</row>
			</tbody>
		</tgroup>
	</informaltable>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

	<para>Απομάκρυνση όλων των φύλλων.</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

	<para>
		Click on Kings to remove them.  All other cards can be removed in pairs
		that add up to thirteen as long as the two cards are touching
		horizontally, vertically, or diagonally.
	</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Options</title>

	<para>
		None
	</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

	<para>Κάθε φύλλο που απομακρύνεται αντιστοιχεί σε 1 βαθμό.</para>
	<para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 52</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

	<para>
		Remove cards higher up on the table first as this creates more
		movement within the grid.
	</para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Odessa"><!--<sect1info>
		<copyright>
			<year>1998</year>
			<holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
		</copyright>
		<author>
			<firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
			<surname>Yuen</surname>
		</author>
		<address><email>rwsy@mit.edu</email></address>
	</sect1info>-->

	<title>Odessa</title>

	<para>Γράφτηκε από τη Rosanna Yuen</para>

	        <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


	<informaltable>
		<tgroup cols="2">
			<tbody>
	<row>
		<entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
		<entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Βάσεις</entry>
		<entry>
			Four piles on left.  To be built up in suit from Ace to
			King.
		</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
		<entry>
			Seven piles.  Deal three rows face down followed by three rows face
			up.  Then deal two more rows face up in the middle five
			piles.
		</entry>
	</row>
			</tbody>
		</tgroup>
	</informaltable>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

	<para>Μετακίνηση όλων των φύλλων στις βάσεις</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

	<para>
		Cards in the Tableau are built down by suit.  Groups of cards can be
		moved regardless of sequence.  Groups of cards in sequence can be moved
		into an appropriate and receptive Foundation pile.  An empty pile in the
		Tableau can be filled with a King or a group of cards with a King on the
		bottom.
	</para>
	<para>
		Foundations are built up in suit from Ace to King.  Cards in Foundations
		are no longer in play.
	</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Options</title>

	<para>None</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

	<para>
		When game is dealt, any sequence of cards going down in suit is
		awarded one point per card.  Every move within the Tableau will award
		a point for every card in the newly created sequence.  A point is also
		rewarded for every card placed on to the Foundation.
	</para>
	<para>
		Maximum possible score:  412
	</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

	<para>
		The more you can hold on to, the more you will have.  Try to keep cards
		out of Foundations as long as possible.  The larger the sequences, the
		more points are made.
	</para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Osmosis"><!--<sect1info>
		<copyright>
			<year>1998</year>
			<holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
		</copyright>
		<author>
			<firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
			<surname>Yuen</surname>
		</author>
		<address><email>rwsy@mit.edu</email></address>
	</sect1info>-->

	<title>Osmosis</title>

	<para>Γράφτηκε από τη Rosanna Yuen</para>

	        <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


	<informaltable>
		<tgroup cols="2">
			<tbody>
	<row>
		<entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
		<entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Ρεζέρβες</entry>
		<entry>
			Four spread piles on left.  Deal three cards face down and one
			card face up in each Reserve pile.  No building allowed.
		</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Βάσεις</entry>
		<entry>
			Four piles on right.  Deal one card on to first Foundation.
		</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Μάνα</entry>
		<entry>
			Place all remaining cards here.  Cards are turned over one at a
			time to Waste.  Two redeals.
		</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Σωρός</entry>
		<entry>Προέρχονται από τη μάνα. Μπορείτε να παίξετε το πάνω φύλλο.</entry>
	</row>
			</tbody>
		</tgroup>
	</informaltable>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

	<para>Μετακίνηση όλων των φύλλων στις βάσεις</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

	<para>
		Any card of the suit in the first Foundation can be played on to this
		Foundation pile at any time. Each ensuing Foundation can only be
		started with a card of the same rank as this first card.  Once
		started, these latter foundations can be built on in suit as long as a
		card of the same rank already exists in the Foundation directly above
		it.  Play cards from Reserves whenever possible following these rules.
	</para>
	<para>Τα φύλλα της μάνας μοιράζονται ένα ένα και τοποθετούνται στο σωρό. Μπορείτε να παίζετε το πάνω φύλλο στο σωρό. Αν αδειάσει η μάνα, όλα τα φύλλα του σωρού μετακινούνται στη μάνα, χωρίς να αλλάξει η σειρά. Συνολικά επιτρέπονται τρεις μοιρασιές.</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Options</title>

	<para>Three card deals: Deal three cards at a time from Stock to Waste and enable unlimited redeals.</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

	<para>
		One point for every card placed on Foundation.
	</para>
	<para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 52</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

	<para>
		It's no coincidence that solitaire games are also known as "patience
		games". Do not automatically put first available card on the second
		(and third) foundation piles.  Sometimes it is worth using a different
		suit so as to free up more cards in the Reserves.
	</para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Peek"><!--<sect1info>
		<copyright>
			<year>2001</year>
			<holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
		</copyright>
		<author>
			<firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
			<surname>Yuen</surname>
		</author>
		<address><email>zana@webwynk.net</email></address>
	</sect1info>-->

	<title>Peek</title>

	<para>Γράφτηκε από τη Rosanna Yuen</para>

	        <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


	<informaltable>
		<tgroup cols="2">
			<tbody>
	<row>
		<entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
		<entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Ρεζέρβες</entry>
		<entry>
			Four spread piles on left.  Deal four cards face up in each Reserve
			pile.  No building allowed.
		</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Βάσεις</entry>
		<entry>
			Four piles on right.  Deal one card on to first Foundation.
		</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Μάνα</entry>
		<entry>
			Place all remaining cards here.  Cards are turned over one at a
			time to Waste.  Two redeals.
		</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Σωρός</entry>
		<entry>Προέρχονται από τη μάνα. Μπορείτε να παίξετε το πάνω φύλλο.</entry>
	</row>
			</tbody>
		</tgroup>
	</informaltable>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

	<para>Μετακίνηση όλων των φύλλων στις βάσεις</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

	<para>
		Any card of the suit in the first Foundation can be played on to this
		Foundation pile at any time. Each ensuing Foundation can only be
		started with a card of the same rank as this first card.  Once
		started, these latter foundations can be built on in suit as long as a
		card of the same rank already exists in the Foundation directly above
		it.  Play cards from Reserves whenever possible following these rules.
	</para>
	<para>Τα φύλλα της μάνας μοιράζονται ένα ένα και τοποθετούνται στο σωρό. Μπορείτε να παίζετε το πάνω φύλλο στο σωρό. Αν αδειάσει η μάνα, όλα τα φύλλα του σωρού μετακινούνται στη μάνα, χωρίς να αλλάξει η σειρά. Συνολικά επιτρέπονται τρεις μοιρασιές.</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Options</title>

 	<para>Three card deals: Deal three cards at a time from Stock to Waste and enable unlimited redeals.</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

	<para>
		One point for every card placed on Foundation.
	</para>
	<para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 52</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

	<para>
		The Reserves are open for you to see.  Choose your suit order wisely.
	</para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Pileon"><!--<sect1info>
		<copyright>
			<year>1998</year>
			<holder>Nick Lamb</holder>
		</copyright>
		<author>
			<firstname>Nick</firstname>
			<surname>Lamb</surname>
		</author>
		<address><email>njl195@zepler.org.uk</email></address>
	</sect1info>-->

	<title>Pileon</title>

	<para>Written by Nick Lamb</para>

	        <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


	<informaltable>
		<tgroup cols="2">
			<tbody>
	<row>
		<entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
		<entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
		<entry>
			Fifteen piles, arranged in rows of four.  Deal cards four at a time, face
			up onto the first thirteen piles.  Leave the last two spaces empty.
			A pile can hold as many as four cards, and as few as none.
		</entry>
	</row>
			</tbody>
		</tgroup>
	</informaltable>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

	<para>
		Rearrange the cards so that each pile contains all four cards from a single
		value. This should leave two piles empty, but it doesn't matter whether
		they are the same piles which were empty at the start.
	</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

	<para>
		Cards can be moved on top of any other card or cards of the same value
		so long as no pile grows to have more than four cards. Groups of cards
		can be moved if they are of the same value, but it doesn't gain you
		anything. An empty slot can be filled with any card or group of cards
		with the same value.
	</para>
	<para>
		Once a pile contains all four cards of the same value it is frozen, and
		the top card is flipped to indicate that you need do nothing further
		to those cards. They are no longer in play, but it would be useless to
		move them anyway.
	</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

	<para>
		When a pile of four cards is frozen you score 4 points, one for each
		card. There is no other way to score points.
	</para>
	<para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 52</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

	<para>
		Keep one of the piles clear as much as possible. Don't allow a pile of
		three cards to build up on top of a single card, especially if the
		final card from the set is not a bottom card in another pile.
	</para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Plait"><!--<sect1info>
		<copyright>
			<year>1999</year>
			<holder>W. Borgert</holder>
		</copyright>
		<author>
			<firstname>W.</firstname>
			<surname>Borgert</surname>
		</author>
		<address><email>debacle@debian.org</email></address>
	</sect1info>-->

	<title>Plait</title>

	<para>Written by W. Borgert</para>

	        <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


	<informaltable>
		<tgroup cols="2">
			<tbody>
	<row>
		<entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
		<entry>Δύο τράπουλες</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Μάνα</entry>
		<entry>
			Third row from the right side in the middle.  Two redeals are
			allowed.
		</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Σωρός</entry>
		<entry>
			Fourth row from the right in the middle, directly left of the stock.
		</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Βάσεις</entry>
		<entry>
			Right eight piles.  One card is already there at start.  This is the
			base card.  All fields have to be started with this card.
		</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Plait</entry>
		<entry>
			The group of cards in the middle of the table.  Starts with 20
			cards. Only the one top level card can be moved.
		</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Edges</entry>
		<entry>
			The four fields at the top and bottom, left and right of the plait.
			These are automatically refilled from the plait.
		</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
		<entry>
			The eight fields left and right of the plait, between the edge fields.
			Only one card per pile is possible.
		</entry>
	</row>
			</tbody>
		</tgroup>
	</informaltable>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

	<para>
		Move all cards to Foundations.
	</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

	<para>
		All eight Foundations have to be started with the same card value.
		At the beginning you can choose whether to build up or down.
		You can take cards from the plait in the middle of
		the tableau, from the eight free fields left and right of the plait,
		from the four edges around the plait, and from the waste.
	</para>
	<para>
		The game is lost if no available cards can be moved on to the
		Foundation piles and the Stock is empty.
	</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

	<para>
		No scoring. You either win or lose.
	</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

	<para>
		Pick the cards from the plait as soon as possible as they are hard to free.
		Then pick the cards from the tableau as it will give you empty slots
		to temporarily store some cards.
	</para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Poker"><!--<sect1info>
		<copyright>
			<year>2001</year>
			<holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
		</copyright>
		<author>
			<firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
			<surname>Yuen</surname>
		</author>
		<address><email>zana@webwynk.net</email></address>
	</sect1info>-->

	<title>Poker</title>

  <para>Γράφτηκε από τη Rosanna Yuen</para>

          <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


  <informaltable>
    <tgroup cols="2">
      <tbody>
	<row>
		<entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
		<entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Μάνα</entry>
		<entry>
			Top left pile.
		</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Σωρός</entry>
		<entry>
			Next to Stock.  The Waste can only hold one card.
		</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
		<entry>
			Five by five grid.  Each slot can only hold one card.
		</entry>
	</row>
      </tbody>
    </tgroup>
  </informaltable>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

  <para>
    Score as many points as possible using poker hands.  There are
    twelve hands in the board -- 5 rows, 5 columns, and 2 diagonals.
    Scoring 75 points or higher is considered a win.
  </para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

  <para>
    Click on the Stock to flip over cards one at a time.  The card must
    be placed somewhere on to the Tableau before the next card can be
    flipped.  Once placed, a card cannot be moved.
  </para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Options</title>

  <para>
    Shuffle mode: If selected, you can move the cards after they have
    been placed.  You need at least 120 points to win this way.
  </para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

  <para>
    Poker hands are scored using the British point system, which is as follows
  </para>

  <informaltable>
    <tgroup cols="3">
      <tbody>
        <row>
          <entry>Hand</entry>
          <entry>Description</entry>
          <entry>Score</entry>
        </row>
        <row>
          <entry>Straight flush</entry>
          <entry>Cards are all in sequence and are the same suit</entry>
          <entry>30</entry>
        </row>
        <row>
          <entry>Four of a kind</entry>
          <entry>Contains four cards have the same rank</entry>
          <entry>16</entry>
        </row>
        <row>
          <entry>Straight</entry>
          <entry>Cards are all in sequence</entry>
          <entry>12</entry>
        </row>
        <row>
          <entry>Full House</entry>
          <entry>Three of one rank and two of another</entry>
          <entry>10</entry>
        </row>
        <row>
          <entry>Three of a kind</entry>
          <entry>Contains three cards have the same rank</entry>
          <entry>6</entry>
        </row>
        <row>
          <entry>Flush</entry>
          <entry>All five cards are the same suit</entry>
          <entry>5</entry>
        </row>
        <row>
          <entry>Two pair</entry>
          <entry>Contains two sets of two cards of the same rank</entry>
          <entry>3</entry>
        </row>
        <row>
          <entry>One pair</entry>
          <entry>Contains two cards of the same rank</entry>
          <entry>1</entry>
        </row>
      </tbody>
    </tgroup>
  </informaltable>

  <para>
    Maximum possible score:  276
  </para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

  <para>
    Remember you are going to see almost half the deck and plan
    accordingly.  Trying to bluff the computer is not recommended.
  </para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Quatorze"><!--<sect1info>
		<copyright>
			<year>2001</year>
			<holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
		</copyright>
		<author>
			<firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
			<surname>Yuen</surname>
		</author>
		<address><email>zana@webwynk.net</email></address>
	</sect1info>-->

	<title>Quatorze</title>

  <para>Γράφτηκε από τη Rosanna Yuen</para>

          <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


  <informaltable>
    <tgroup cols="2">
      <tbody>
	<row>
	  <entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
	  <entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Μάνα</entry>
	  <entry>
	  	Top left pile.  The rest of the deck is placed here after
	    dealing the Tableau.  Empty spaces in the Tableau are
	    immediately filled in with cards from the Stock.
	  </entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
	  <entry>
	  	Five-by-five grid, each capable of holding one card.
	  	One card dealt to each space at the beginning of the game.
	  	Empty spaces are filled in from the Stock.  Once Stock is
	  	exhausted, spaces are filled by moving cards from the right to
	  	the left, from the leftmost card of the row below to the the
	  	rightmost space, leaving all empty spaces at the end.
	  </entry>
	</row>
      </tbody>
    </tgroup>
  </informaltable>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

  <para>Απομάκρυνση όλων των φύλλων.</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

  <para>
    Cards can be removed in pairs if they add up to fourteen (with Jacks
    being 11, Queens 12, and Kings 13) and are in the same row or column.
  </para>
  <para>
    Empty slots are automatically filled from the Stock.  Once the Stock
    is exhausted, cards to the right of empty piles are automatically
    moved over to fill the space, with empty piles in the right column
    filled in by the cards of the leftmost column in the row below.
  </para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

  <para>
    Each pair of cards removed scores two points.
  </para>
  <para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 52</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

  <para>
    Oftentimes in the middle of this game, there is only one move.  Make
    it.  Once the Stock is exhausted, there is much more movement in the
    Tableau.
  </para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Royal_East"><!--<sect1info>
    <copyright>
      <year>1999</year>
      <holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
    </copyright>
    <author>
      <firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
      <surname>Yuen</surname></author>
    <address><email>zana@webwynk.net</email></address>
  </sect1info>-->

  <title>Royal East</title>

  <para>Γράφτηκε από τη Rosanna Yuen</para>

          <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


  <informaltable>
    <tgroup cols="2">
      <tbody>
	<row>
	  <entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
	  <entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Μάνα</entry>
	  <entry>
	    Top left pile.  The rest of the deck is placed here after
	    dealing the Tableau.  Cards are turned over one at a time to
	    Waste.  No redeals.
	  </entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Σωρός</entry>
	  <entry>Προέρχονται από τη μάνα. Μπορείτε να παίξετε το πάνω φύλλο.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Βάσεις</entry>
	  <entry>
	    Four corner piles of three by three grid.  Deal one card on
	    to first Foundation pile.  This card is now the base card.
	    Build up in suit, playing Aces on Kings as necessary.
	  </entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
	  <entry>
	    Deal one card face up on each of the five Tableau piles.
	    These piles are the ones forming a cross in the three by
	    three grid.
	  </entry>
	</row>
      </tbody>
    </tgroup>
  </informaltable>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

  <para>Μετακίνηση όλων των φύλλων στις βάσεις</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

  <para>
    Cards in Tableau are built down regardless of suit.  Kings can be
    placed on Aces.  Cards can only be moved singly.  Any available card
    can be played on an empty Tableau pile.
  </para>
  <para>
    Each Foundation pile must be started with a card the same rank as
    the base card.  Foundation piles are to be built up in suit from
    base card, playing Aces on top of Kings if necessary.  Cards in
    Foundation piles are no longer in play.
  </para>
  <para>
    Cards are flipped singly from Stock to Waste.  Top card of Waste
    pile is always available for play.  There are no redeals.
  </para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

  <para>Κάθε φύλλο που τοποθετείται στις βάσεις αντιστοιχεί σε 1 βαθμό.</para>
  <para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 52</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

  <para>
    Hidden treasures are wonderful things, but only if you know they are
    there.  Keep track of what cards are in which piles as this
    information will probably come in handy.
  </para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Saratoga">
<!--<sect1info>
    <copyright>
      <year>2001</year>
      <holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
    </copyright>
    <author>
      <firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
      <surname>Yuen</surname>
    </author>
    <address><email>zana@webwynk.net</email></address>
  </sect1info>-->

  <title>Saratoga</title>

  <para>Γράφτηκε από τον Alan Horkan, με βάση το έργο του Jonathan Blandford</para>
  <!-- Also documented by Alan Horkan (2005)
  based on documentation by Rosann Yuen -->

          <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


  <informaltable>
    <tgroup cols="2"><tbody>
	<row>
	  <entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
	  <entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Μάνα</entry>
	  <entry>Η στοίβα πάνω αριστερά. Όταν ολοκληρωθεί η μοιρασιά, τα υπόλοιπα φύλλα τοποθετούνται εδώ. Τα φύλλα της μάνας ανοίγουν ένα ένα και τοποθετούνται στο σωρό. Ο παίκτης δύο επιπλέον μοιρασιές.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Σωρός</entry>
	  <entry>Προέρχονται από τη μάνα. Μπορείτε να παίξετε το πάνω φύλλο.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Βάσεις</entry>
	  <entry>Οι τέσσερις στοίβες πάνω δεξιά. Τα φύλλα τοποθετούνται ανά φυλή και σε αύξουσα σειρά, από τον Άσσο στο Ρήγα. Σε κάθε βάση, το πάνω φύλλο μπορεί να παιχθεί στο ταμπλό.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
	  <entry>
	    Seven piles.  Place one card face up on all piles.  Next row 
	    skip the first pile and place cards on all the other piles.  
	    Continue this process skipping one place to the right each row 
	    until there are seven rows with seven cards in the last pile.  
	    Essentially Saratoga is the same as Klondike only the all 
	    cards are face up to begin with.  Being able to see all cards 
	    reduces the element of risk and makes Saratoga slightly easier 
	    than Klondike.  
	    
	    Tableau can be built down in alternating colors.  Groups of
	    cards can be moved.  Empty piles can only be filled by Kings
	    or group of cards starting with a King.
	  </entry>
	</row>
      </tbody>
    </tgroup>
  </informaltable>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

  <para>Μετακίνηση όλων των φύλλων στις βάσεις</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

  <para>Μπορείτε να τοποθετείτε φύλλα στο ταμπλό με φθίνουσα σειρά και σε εναλλασσόμενο χρώμα. Μπορείτε να μετακινείτε ομάδες φύλλων. Αν μία στήλη είναι κενή, μπορείτε να τοποθετήσετε μόνο Ρήγα ή ομάδα φύλλων που ξεκινάει με Ρήγα.</para>
  <para>Τα φύλλα της μάνας μοιράζονται ένα ένα και τοποθετούνται στο σωρό. Μπορείτε να παίζετε το πάνω φύλλο στο σωρό. Αν αδειάσει η μάνα, όλα τα φύλλα του σωρού μετακινούνται στη μάνα, χωρίς να αλλάξει η σειρά. Συνολικά επιτρέπονται τρεις μοιρασιές.</para>
  <para>Στις βάσεις τα φύλλα μπαίνουν ανά φυλή και σε αύξουσα σειρά από τον Άσσο στο Ρήγα. Τα φύλλα στις βάσεις δε βγαίνουν από το παιχνίδι. Αν κάνετε διπλό κλικ σε ένα φύλλο, το φύλλο αυτό θα ανέβει στις βάσεις, εφόσον επιτρέπεται η κίνηση.</para>

<!-- TODO 
          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Options</title>

  <para>
    Three card deals: If checked, the Stock will deal three each time.
    Otherwise, the Stock will deal singly into the Waste.
  </para>
  <para>
    King Only: If checked empty space may be filled with Kings or 
    groups of cards starting with a King only.  
  </para>
-->

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

  <para>Κάθε φύλλο που τοποθετείται στις βάσεις αντιστοιχεί σε 1 βαθμό.</para>
  <para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 52</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

  <para>Μην εγκαταλείπετε εύκολα! Αν κινδυνεύετε να χάσετε, δοκιμάστε όλες τις πιθανές κινήσεις με τη σειρά. Ορισμένες φορές μπορείτε να χρησιμοποιήσετε φύλλα από τις βάσεις σε συνδυασμό με την αναδιάταξη φύλλων στο ταμπλό για να αποκαλύψετε επιπλέον κλειστά φύλλα.</para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Scorpion"><!--<sect1info>
		<copyright>
			<year>1999</year>
			<holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
		</copyright>
		<author>
			<firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
			<surname>Yuen</surname>
		</author>
		<address><email>rwsy@mit.edu</email></address>
	</sect1info>-->

	<title>Scorpion</title>

	<para>Γράφτηκε από τη Rosanna Yuen</para>

	        <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


	<informaltable>
		<tgroup cols="2">
			<tbody>
	<row>
		<entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
		<entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Μάνα</entry>
		<entry>
			Top left pile.  The last three cards are placed here after the deal.
		</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
		<entry>
			Seven piles to the right of Stock.  * Deal one cards face down on each of
			the first four rows.  Deal one card face up on the last three rows.
			Repeat from * two more times, dealing a total of three rows.  Deal one
			card face up on each pile for four more rows.
		</entry>
	</row>
			</tbody>
		</tgroup>
	</informaltable>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

	<para>
		Create four piles of thirteen cards each, each pile consisting of one
		suit and in rank order.
	</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

	<para>
		Cards in the Tableau are built down by suit.  Groups of cards can be
		moved regardless of sequence.  An empty pile in the Tableau can be
		filled with a King or a group of cards with a King on the bottom.
	</para>
	<para>
		At any point, clicking on the Stock will deal the last three cards, one
		each on the first three piles.
	</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

	<para>
		For every sequence in suit, points given is (length of sequence - 1).
		Each time a sequence of thirteen is created and is in its own slot, four
		extra points are awarded.  Reaching a card that was face down gives
		three points.
	</para>
	<para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 100</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

	<para>
		Unknotting knots is not often easy.  Avoid tangling yourself up with no
		way out.
	</para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Scuffle"><!--<sect1info>
		<copyright>
			<year>2001</year>
			<holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
		</copyright>
		<author>
			<firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
			<surname>Yuen</surname>
		</author>
		<address><email>zana@webwynk.net</email></address>
	</sect1info>-->

	<title>Scuffle</title>

  <para>Γράφτηκε από τη Rosanna Yuen</para>

          <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


  <informaltable>
    <tgroup cols="2">
      <tbody>
	<row>
	  <entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
	  <entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Μάνα</entry>
	  <entry>
			Top left pile.  All cards except the Aces are placed
			here at the start of play.  Clicking on the Stock will deal
			one card to each of the four Reserve piles.  Two redeals allowed.
	  </entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Βάσεις</entry>
	  <entry>Οι τέσσερις στοίβες στο πάνω μέρος, δεξιά από τη μάνα. Τοποθετήστε έναν Άσσο σε καθεμιά από τις βάσεις για να ξεκινήσετε την παρτίδα. Στις βάσεις τα φύλλα τοποθετούνται με αύξουσα σειρά ανεξαρτήτως φυλής.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Ρεζέρβες</entry>
	  <entry>Οι τέσσερις στοίβες κάτω από τις βάσεις. Κάθε φορά που κάνετε κλικ στη μάνα, μοιράζεται ένα φύλλο σε κάθε μία στοίβα της ρεζέρβας. Παίζετε πάντα το πάνω φύλλο κάθε στοίβας. Τα φύλλα της ρεζέρβας επιτρέπεται να τοποθετούνται μόνο στις βάσεις.</entry>
	</row>
      </tbody>
    </tgroup>
  </informaltable>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

  <para>Μετακίνηση όλων των φύλλων στις βάσεις</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

  <para>
    Play begins by dealing four cards face up on to the Reserve.  If
    possible, play cards on to the Foundation from the Reserve.  Continue
    this process until no cards are left in stock and no more moves on
    to the Foundation can be made.
  </para>
  <para>
    Take all cards left over on the Reserve and reshuffle.  Place these
    cards back to the stock for redealing.  There are two redeals.
  </para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

  <para>Κάθε φύλλο που τοποθετείται στις βάσεις αντιστοιχεί σε 1 βαθμό.</para>
  <para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 48</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

  <para>
    Try to keep in mind what is underneath the Reserve piles.  When
    given a choice, it is this knowledge which should help you decide
    which card to play.
  </para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Seahaven"><!--<sect1info>
		<copyright>
			<year>2001</year>
			<holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
		</copyright>
		<author>
			<firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
			<surname>Yuen</surname>
		</author>
		<address><email>zana@webwynk.net</email></address>
	</sect1info>-->

	<title>Seahaven</title>

  <para>Γράφτηκε από τη Rosanna Yuen</para>

          <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


  <informaltable>
    <tgroup cols="2">
      <tbody>
	<row>
	  <entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
	  <entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Βάσεις</entry>
	  <entry>
	  	Four piles -- two top left, two top right.  Built from
		  Ace to King in suit.
		 </entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Ρεζέρβες</entry>
	  <entry>
	  	Four piles at top in the center.  Each reserve can only
		  hold one card.  Two of the reserves are each dealt one card to
		  start.
		 </entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
	  <entry>
	  	Ten piles underneath the Foundation and Reserves.  The
		  other fifty cards are dealt face up here with five in each
		  slot.
		 </entry>
	</row>
      </tbody>
    </tgroup>
  </informaltable>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

  <para>Μετακίνηση όλων των φύλλων στις βάσεις</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

  <para>Τα φύλλα στο ταμπλό τοποθετούνται ανά φυλή και σε φθίνουσα σειρά. Μπορείτε να μετακινείτε μόνο το πάνω φύλλο ή ομάδα φύλλων κάθε στήλης. Για να μετακινηθεί μια ομάδα φύλλων, ο αριθμός των φύλλων της δεν πρέπει να είναι μεγαλύτερος από τον αριθμό των ελεύθερων θέσεων της ρεζέρβας συν ένα. Οι κενές θέσεις του ταμπλό μπορούν να συμπληρωθούν μόνο με Ρήγα ή με ομάδα που ξεκινά με Ρήγα.</para>
  <para>Τα φύλλα στις βάσεις τοποθετούνται ανά φυλή και σε αύξουσα σειρά, από τον Άσσο στο Ρήγα. Αν και τα φύλλα των βάσεων θεωρητικά παραμένουν στο παιχνίδι, η χρήση τους δεν βοηθάει σε κάτι.</para>
  <para>Το πάνω φύλλο κάθε στήλης του ταμπλό μπορεί να τοποθετηθεί σε μια ελεύθερη θέση της ρεζέρβας. Τα φύλλα αυτά παραμένουν διαθέσιμα και μπορούν να μετακινηθούν στο ταμπλό ή τις βάσεις.</para>
  <para>
    As a convenience, sequences of the same suit can be moved onto the
    matching Foundation pile rather than being moved individually. This
    is especially useful at the end of the game.
  </para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

  <para>Κάθε φύλλο που τοποθετείται στις βάσεις αντιστοιχεί σε 1 βαθμό.</para>
  <para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 52</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

  <para>Μετακινήστε τα φύλλα στις βάσεις το συντομότερο δυνατόν. Η διατήρησή τους στο ταμπλό απλά δυσχεραίνει τις κινήσεις σας.</para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Sir_Tommy"><!--<sect1info>
		<copyright>
			<year>2001</year>
			<holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
		</copyright>
		<author>
			<firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
			<surname>Yuen</surname>
		</author>
		<address><email>zana@webwynk.net</email></address>
	</sect1info>-->

	<title>Sir Tommy</title>

  <para>Γράφτηκε από τη Rosanna Yuen</para>

          <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


  <informaltable>
    <tgroup cols="2">
      <tbody>
	<row>
	  <entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
	  <entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Μάνα</entry>
	  <entry>
	    Top left pile.  All cards are placed here at beginning of
	    play.  Cards are dealt singly to Waste.
	  </entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Σωρός</entry>
	  <entry>
	    To the right of the Stock.  Can only hold one card.  Card
	    must immediately be placed on either a Foundation pile or on
	    to the Reserve pile of your choice.
	  </entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Βάσεις</entry>
	  <entry>
	    Four piles on top, to the right of Waste.  To be built in
	    sequence from Ace to King regardless of suit.
	  </entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Ρεζέρβες</entry>
	  <entry>
	      Four piles placed underneath Foundations.  Cards in
	      Reserve can only be played on to Foundation piles.
	  </entry>
	</row>
      </tbody>
    </tgroup>
  </informaltable>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

  <para>
    Move all cards to the Foundations
  </para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

  <para>
    Build on to Foundations in sequence from Ace to King regardless of
    suit.  Cards in Foundations are no longer in play.  Cards are dealt
    singly in to the Waste from the Stock.  However, as the Waste pile
    can only hold one card, this card must immediately be played on to a
    Foundation pile or on to any of the four Reserve piles.  Cards in
    the Reserve piles cannot be rearranged.
  </para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

  <para>
    Each card moved to Foundations scores one point.
  </para>
  <para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 52</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

  <para>
    Try not to place cards of higher rank on to cards of lower rank in
    the Reserve.
  </para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Spider"><!--<sect1info>
		<copyright>
			<year>1998</year>
			<holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
		</copyright>
		<author>
			<firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
			<surname>Yuen</surname>
		</author>
		<address><email>rwsy@mit.edu</email></address>
	</sect1info>-->

	<title>Spider</title>

	<para>Written by Jonathan Blandford</para>

	        <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


	<informaltable>
		<tgroup cols="2">
			<tbody>
	<row>
		<entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
		<entry>Δύο τράπουλες</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Μάνα</entry>
		<entry>
			Top left pile.  Deck placed here after dealing onto Tableau.
			Clicking deals one card face up to every pile.
		</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Βάσεις</entry>
		<entry>
			Top eight piles. Only used to hold sequences of cards going down from King
		down to Ace once completed.
		</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
		<entry>
			Ten piles.  Four piles (piles 1, 4, 7, and 10) get dealt 5
			cards down and one card up while rest of the piles get dealt 4 cards
			down and one card up.  Cards can be built down regardless of suit.
			Sequences of cards in the same suit can be moved as a unit.  Empty piles
			can be filled with any card or movable unit.
		</entry>
	</row>
			</tbody>
		</tgroup>
	</informaltable>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

	<para>
		To have eight sequences of cards going down from King
		down to Ace in the foundation.
	</para>
	<para>
	  If you want an extremely difficult challenge, do not move completed
    sequences of cards to a foundation.
    You can also win by leaving the same eight sequences in the tableau.
    This is harder because there are fewer empty piles available. In fact,
    it is nearly impossible.
	</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

	<para>
		Build down regardless of suit.  Sequences of cards in the same suit can
		be moved as a unit.  Empty piles can be filled with any card or legal
		sequence.
	</para>
	<para>
		Clicking on the Stock pile at any time deals a card face up to every
		pile.  However, all piles must be non-empty.  If an empty pile exists,
		an error message will appear.
	</para>
	<para>
		A sequence of cards going down from King down to Ace can be moved to a foundation pile.  Once
		there, these cards are no longer in play.
	</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Options</title>

  <para>
    There are three possible types of deck. Each deck has 104 cards.
  </para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry><term>One Suit</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The deck is an octuple deck of Spades only. This is the simplest of the spider decks and a good way to learn the basics.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>    
    <varlistentry><term>Two Suits</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The deck is a quadruple deck of Hearts and Spades only. There are four complete sequences of cards for each suit. This is not quite as diabolical as the standard four suit spider deck.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry><term>Four Suits</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The deck is a standard double deck. There are two complete sequences of cards for each suit. This is the standard Spider deck. It is also the most difficult.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  
  <para>Many traditional implementations of Spider do not use a foundation
  and simply remove completed sequences of cards. This has no impact upon game
  play.</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

	<para>
		For every sequence in suit, points given is (length of sequence - 1).
	</para>
	<para>
		Maximum possible score: 96
	</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

	<para>
		If at first you don't succeed, don't become addicted.  Build in suit
		whenever possible, but expose as many cards as you can.
	</para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Spider_Three_Decks"><!--<sect1info>
		<copyright>
			<year>1998</year>
			<holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
		</copyright>
		<author>
			<firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
			<surname>Yuen</surname>
		</author>
		<address><email>rwsy@mit.edu</email></address>
	</sect1info>-->

	<title>Spider Three Decks</title>

	<para>written by Jonathan Blandford, Daniel Werner</para>

	<sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>

	<informaltable>
		<tgroup cols="2">
			<tbody>
	<row>
		<entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
		<entry>Triple Deck</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Μάνα</entry>
		<entry>
			Top left pile.  Deck placed here after dealing onto Tableau.
			Clicking deals one card face up to every pile.
		</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Βάσεις</entry>
		<entry>
			Top twelve piles.  Not part of "official rules".
		</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
		<entry>
			Twelve piles.  The first six piles get dealt 4
			cards down and one card up while rest of the piles get dealt 3 cards
			down and one card up.  Cards can be built down regardless of suit.
			Sequences of cards in the same suit can be moved as a unit.  Empty piles
			can be filled with any card or movable unit.
		</entry>
	</row>
			</tbody>
		</tgroup>
	</informaltable>
	</sect2>

	<sect2><title>Στόχος</title>
	<para>
		To have twelve sequences of cards (three for each suit) going down from King
		down to Ace in the foundation.
	</para>
	<para>
	        If you want an extremely difficult challenge, you can also win by forming the same twelve sequences in the tableau. This is harder because there are fewer empty piles available. In fact, it is nearly impossible.
	</para>
	</sect2>

	<sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>
	<para>
		Build down regardless of suit.  Sequences of cards in the same suit can
		be moved as a unit.  Empty piles can be filled with any card or legal
		sequence.
	</para>
	<para>
		Clicking on the Stock pile at any time deals a card face up to every
		pile.  Unlike in other Spider variants, empty piles are allowed at redeals. 
	</para>
	<para>
		A sequence of thirteen cards can be moved to a foundation pile.  Once
		there, these cards are no longer in play.
	</para>
	</sect2>

	<sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>
	<para>
		For every sequence in suit, points given is (length of sequence - 1).
	</para>
	<para>
		Maximum possible score: 144
	</para>
	</sect2>

	<sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>
	<para>
		If at first you don't succeed, don't become addicted.  Build in suit
		whenever possible, but expose as many cards as you can.
	</para>
	</sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Spiderette"><!--<sect1info>
    <copyright>
      <year>2001</year>
      <holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
    </copyright>
    <author>
      <firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
      <surname>Yuen</surname>
    </author>
    <address><email>zana@webwynk.net</email></address>
  </sect1info>-->

  <title>Spiderette</title>

  <para>Γράφτηκε από τη Rosanna Yuen</para>

          <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


  <informaltable>
    <tgroup cols="2">
      <tbody>
	<row>
	  <entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
	  <entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Μάνα</entry>
	  <entry>
	    Top left pile.  Deals a card to each Tableau pile when
	    clicked.
	  </entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Βάσεις</entry>
	  <entry>
	    Four piles top right.
	  </entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
	  <entry>
	    Seven piles on the bottom.  Deal one card face down on all
	    seven piles, then one on the last six piles, followed by one
	    on the last five piles.  Continue in this manner until you
	    have seven cards in the last pile.  Flip up the top card on
	    every pile.
	  </entry>
	</row>
      </tbody>
    </tgroup>
  </informaltable>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

  <para>
    Create four piles of thirteen cards each built down in suit and sequence.
  </para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

  <para>
    Cards in Tableau can be built down regardless of suit.  Builds of
    cards in sequence and in the same suit can by moved as a unit.
    Empty Tableau piles can be filled with any card or build of cards.
  </para>
  <para>
    Each Tableau pile must be filled before any deal.  Clicking on the
    Stock will deal a card on to every Tableau pile except for the last
    deal which places one card on each of the first three piles.
  </para>
  <para>
    A build of all thirteen cards in a suit may be moved on to a
    Foundation pile.  Cards in the Foundation are no longer in play.
  </para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

  <para>
    Every pair of cards in suit and sequence scores one point.
  </para>
  <para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 48</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

  <para>
    Try to keep a Tableau pile empty whenever possible to create a swap
    space for moving around cards.
  </para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Straight_Up"><!--<sect1info>
		<copyright>
			<year>1999</year>
			<holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
		</copyright>
		<author>
			<firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
			<surname>Yuen</surname>
		</author>
		<address><email>rwsy@mit.edu</email></address>
	</sect1info>-->

	<title>Straight Up</title>

	<para>Γράφτηκε από τη Rosanna Yuen</para>

	        <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


	<informaltable>
		<tgroup cols="2">
			<tbody>
	<row>
		<entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
		<entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Μάνα</entry>
		<entry>
			Top left pile. The rest of the deck is placed here after
			dealing the Tableau. Cards are turned over one at a time to Waste.
			Two	redeals.
		</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Σωρός</entry>
		<entry>Προέρχονται από τη μάνα. Μπορείτε να παίξετε το πάνω φύλλο.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Βάσεις</entry>
		<entry>
			Four piles on top right.  Deal one two on each Foundation pile to
			start.  To be built up in suit to Ace.
		</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Ρεζέρβα</entry>
		<entry>
			Pile under Stock.  Deal thirteen cards here to begin.  Top card available
			for play on to Tableau or Foundation piles.
		</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
		<entry>
			Four piles bottom right.  Deal one card on each pile to start.  Piles
			can be built in suit.  Spaces are automatically filled from Reserve.
			Once Reserve is empty, Tableau spaces can be filled from the Waste at
			your leisure.
		</entry>
	</row>
			</tbody>
		</tgroup>
	</informaltable>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

	<para>
		Move all cards on to Foundation piles.
	</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

	<para>
		Cards in the Tableau are built down in suit.  Groups of cards
		can be moved.  An empty slot in the Tableau is filled automatically from
		the Reserve.  If the Reserve is empty, an empty slot can be filled by the
		top card of the Waste at your leisure.
	</para>
	<para>
		Cards can be flipped singly from the Stock to the Waste.  Top
		card is available for play.  There are two redeals
	</para>
	<para>
		Foundations are built up in suit from twos to aces.  Cards in
		Foundations are no longer in play.  Double clicking on a card will move
		it to the appropriate Foundation pile if such a move is possible.
	</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

	<para>
		Each card moved to Foundation piles scores one point.
	</para>
	<para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 48</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

	<para>
		No point lagging behind!  Move cards to Foundation piles whenever
		possible.
	</para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Streets_And_Alleys"><!--<sect1info>
    <copyright>
      <year>2001</year>
      <holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
    </copyright>
    <author>
      <firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
      <surname>Yuen</surname>
    </author>
    <address><email>zana@webwynk.net</email></address>
  </sect1info>-->

  <title>Streets and Alleys</title>

  <para>Γράφτηκε από τη Rosanna Yuen</para>

          <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


  <informaltable>
    <tgroup cols="2">
      <tbody>
	<row>
	  <entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
	  <entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Βάσεις</entry>
	  <entry>
	    Four piles in the middle column.  To be built from Ace to
	    King.  Topmost card in each Foundation can be played back on
	    to the Tableau.
	  </entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
	  <entry>
	    Eight slots (four to the left and four to the right of
	    Foundations.)  Deal all cards face up and extended on to
	    these eight piles so that there are seven cards in each pile
	    on the left flank and six cards in each pile on the right
	    flank and all cards are showing.
	  </entry>
	</row>
      </tbody>
    </tgroup>
  </informaltable>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

  <para>Μετακίνηση όλων των φύλλων στις βάσεις</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

  <para>Στο ταμπλό μπορείτε να τοποθετείτε φύλλα σε φθίνουσα σειρά ανεξαρτήτως φυλής. Μπορείτε να μετακινείτε μόνο ένα φύλλο κάθε φορά. Αν μία θέση είναι κενή, μπορείτε να την καλύψετε με όποιο φύλλο θέλετε.</para>
  <para>Τα φύλλα στις βάσεις τοποθετούνται ανά φυλή και με αύξουσα σειρά.</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

  <para>Κάθε φύλλο που τοποθετείται στις βάσεις αντιστοιχεί σε 1 βαθμό.</para>
  <para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 52</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

  <para>
    Build evenly on to Foundations if possible.  Try and get an empty
    Tableau slot.
  </para>
  </sect2>
</sect1>



  <sect1 id="Ten_Across"><!--<sect1info>
		<copyright>
			<year>1999</year>
			<holder>James LewisMoss</holder>
		</copyright>
		<author>
			<firstname>James</firstname>
			<surname>LewisMoss</surname>
		</author>
		<address><email>rwsy@mit.edu</email></address>
	</sect1info>-->

	<title>Ten Across</title>

	<para>Written by James LewisMoss</para>

	        <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


	<informaltable>
		<tgroup cols="2">
			<tbody>
	<row>
		<entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
		<entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Temporary Spots</entry>
		<entry>
			Locations to place one card out of play.  The spots begin the game
			filled.  One version of the game does not allow you to put new cards
			into these spots once they are empty.
		</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
		<entry>
			Ten piles across the bottom.  To deal place 10 cards across going from
			left to right with the first and last cards face up.  Continuing you
			place ten cards across the piles from right to left (reversed) with
			the first two and last two cards placed face up.  Continue this
			pattern (reversed and one more card each pass) until 50 cards have
			been placed.  Place the last two cards in the temporary spots at the top.
		</entry>
	</row>
			</tbody>
		</tgroup>
	</informaltable>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

	<para>
		Form four piles in the tableau all of the same suit running from King
		to Ace.
	</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

	<para>
		Only a King may be moved to a blank tableau spot.
	</para>
	<para>
		Cards may be moved only onto other cards if the suit matches and the
		moved card is one less than the moved to. This includes moving a pile
		of cards of different suits as long as the top card of the moved pile
		matches the bottom card of the location moved	to.
	</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Options</title>

	<para>
		Allow temporary spots use: If checked the temporary spots may be reused.
	</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

	<para>
		You win or lose. There is no scoring.
	</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

	<para>
		This game is hard to win (being very influenced by how the cards are
		placed to begin with). Don't forget you have the temporary spots.  Try
		to clear them quickly because they are very useful when you get stuck.
	</para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Terrace"><!--<sect1info>
		<copyright>
			<year>2008</year>
			<holder>David Rogers</holder>
		</copyright>
		<author>
			<firstname>David</firstname>
			<surname>Rogers</surname>
		</author>
		<address><email>ezekiel000@lavabit.com</email></address>
	</sect1info>-->

	<title>Terrace</title>

  <para>Written by David Rogers</para>

          <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


  <informaltable>
    <tgroup cols="2">
      <tbody>
	<row>
	  <entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
	  <entry>Δύο τράπουλες</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Μάνα</entry>
	  <entry>
	  	Top left pile. The rest of the deck is placed here after
		dealing the Reserve and on to the Tableau. Cards are turned
		over one at a time to Waste. Stock cannot be turned.
	  </entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Σωρός</entry>
	  <entry>
	  	To be taken from the Stock. Top card available for play.
	  </entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Ρεζέρβα</entry>
	  <entry>
	  	Eleven cards dealt face up in a pile. All cards are visible
		but only top card is in play.
	  </entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Βάσεις</entry>
	  <entry>
	  	Eight piles in the middle. To be built up in sequence by
		alternating colours from the base card.
	  </entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
    	  <entry>
    		Nine cards dealt face up from the deck once based card is
		selected.
     	  </entry>
	</row>
      </tbody>
    </tgroup>
  </informaltable>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

  <para>Μετακίνηση όλων των φύλλων στις βάσεις</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

  <para>
	Cards in the Tableau are built down in sequence by alternating
	colours building round the corner. Groups of cards can't be moved.
	An empty pile in the Tableau must be filled by the top card in
	Waste or the next card from the Stock. Top cards can be moved to
	the Foundation or other Tableau piles.
  </para>
  <para>
	Foundations are built up in sequence by alternating colours from
	the base card. Empty Foundations must be filled with the base card
	that is selected by the user from four random cards as the first
	move. Cards in Foundations are out of play.
  </para>
  <para>
	Top card of the Reserve is in play and can only be moved to
	Foundations.
  </para>
  <para>
	Cards are flipped from the Stock to the Waste individually as many
	times as you like unless there is a space in the tableau. If there
	is a space in the tableau then only one card may be flipped from
	the stock to the waste until the tableau is filled or the top card
	of the waste is moved to the foundation or tableau. While the
	stock is locked you can still move cards around on the tableau,
	from the reserve and to the foundation. If the Waste is empty a
	card from the Stock is automatically dealt. Top card in Waste is
	in play. Stock cannot be turned.
  </para>
  <para>
	Double clicking on a card will move it to the appropriate
	Foundation pile if such a move is possible.
  </para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Options</title>

  <para>
	There are seven ways to play. The difference between them is in
	number of Reserve cards, Tableau piles or choice of Base Card.
  </para>
  <para>
	Terrace
  </para>
  <para>
	Reserve of 11 cards, 9 Tableau piles. Foundations are built up in
	sequence by alternating colours from the base card. User selection
	of the base card from a choice of four at the start of the game and
	one card is dealt to each Tableau pile. Stock cannot be turned.
  </para>
  <para>
	General Patience
  </para>
  <para>
	Reserve of 13 cards, 9 Tableau piles. Foundations are built up in
	sequence by suit from the base card. User selection of the base
	card from a choice of four at the start of the game and one card is
	dealt to each Tableau pile. Stock can be turned once but the game
	is lost if you cannot play each new card after its turned.
  </para>
  <para>
	Falling Stars
  </para>
  <para>
	Reserve of 11 cards, 9 Tableau piles. Foundations are built up in
	sequence by alternating colours from the base card. At the start of
	the game a base card is selected automatically and one card is
	dealt to each Tableau pile. Stock cannot be turned.
  </para>
  <para>
	Signora
  </para>
  <para>
	Reserve of 11 cards, 9 Tableau piles. Foundations are built up in
	sequence by alternating colours from the base card. At the start of
	the game a base card is selected automatically and one card is
	dealt to each Tableau pile. Spaces in the Tableau are automatically
	filled from the Waste or Stock if the Waste is empty. Stock cannot
	be turned.
  </para>
  <para>
	Redheads
  </para>
  <para>
	Reserve of 21 cards, 8 Tableau piles. Foundations are built up in
	sequence by alternating colours from the base card. At the start of
	the game a base card is selected automatically and one card is
	dealt to each Tableau pile. Spaces in the Tableau are automatically
	filled from the Reserve or any card if the Reserve is empty. Stock
	cannot be turned.
  </para>
  <para>
	Blondes and Brunettes
  </para>
  <para>
	Reserve of 10 cards, 8 Tableau piles. Foundations are built up in
	sequence by alternating colours from the base card. At the start of
	the game a base card is selected automatically and one card is
	dealt to each Tableau pile. Stock cannot be turned.
  </para>
  <para>
	Wood
  </para>
  <para>
	Reserve of 10 cards, 9 Tableau piles. Foundations are built up in
	sequence by alternating colours from the base card. At the start of
	the game a base card is selected automatically and one card is
	dealt to each Tableau pile. Stock cannot be turned.
  </para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

  <para>Κάθε φύλλο που τοποθετείται στις βάσεις αντιστοιχεί σε 1 βαθμό.</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

  <para>
	When the game starts examine the Reserve carefully before choosing
	your base card, avoid base cards that have several buried in the
	Reserve.
  </para>
  <para>
	Watch for reversed sequences in the Stock, Reserve a Foundation to
	remove each reversed sequence.
  </para>
  <para>
	Try to start Tableau piles from the last card needed to complete a
	Foundation.
  </para>
  <para>
	Remember that you can continue to flip cards from the stock while
	it is locked without filling the tableau by using the top card of
	the waste.
  </para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Thieves"><!--<sect1info>
    <copyright>
      <year>1999</year>
      <holder>Robert Brady</holder>
    </copyright>
    <author>
      <firstname>Robert</firstname>
      <surname>Brady</surname>
    </author>
    <address>
      <email>rwb197@ecs.soton.ac.uk</email>
    </address>
  </sect1info>-->

  <title>Thieves</title>

  <para>Written by Robert Brady</para>

          <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


  <informaltable>
    <tgroup cols="2">
      <tbody>
	<row>
	  <entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
	  <entry>Joker Deck</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
	  <entry>
	    Seven piles of five cards each, face up.
	  </entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Μάνα</entry>
	  <entry>
	    Place all remaining cards here.  Cards are turned over one
	    at a time to Waste.  No redeals.
	  </entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Σωρός</entry>
	  <entry>Προέρχονται από τη μάνα. Μπορείτε να παίξετε το πάνω φύλλο.</entry>
	</row>
      </tbody>
    </tgroup>
  </informaltable>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

  <para>
    Move all cards to Waste.
  </para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

  <para>
    The Waste can be built up or down from the available cards on the
    Tableau.  Jokers are wild and can be played on any rank as well as
    be played upon by a card of any rank.
  </para>
  <para>
    At any point, a card can be dealt from the Stock to the Waste.
  </para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

  <para>
    The following table shows the points you receive for each type of card.
    No points are scored for jokers.
  </para>
  <informaltable>
    <tgroup cols="2">
      <thead>
        <row>
          <entry>Card</entry>
          <entry>Points</entry>
        </row>
      </thead>
      <tbody>
	<row>
	  <entry>Ace</entry>
	  <entry>8</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>2, 3</entry>
	  <entry>6</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>4, 5</entry>
	  <entry>4</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>6, 7, 8</entry>
	  <entry>2</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>9, 10</entry>
	  <entry>4</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Queen</entry>
	  <entry>6</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>King</entry>
	  <entry>8</entry>
	</row>
      </tbody>
    </tgroup>
  </informaltable>
          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

  <para>
    Since you can see all the cards on the Tableau, try to engineer
    `runs', to try and get rid of as many cards up there as possible, as
    you only have a finite supply of cards in Stock.
  </para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Thirteen"><!--<sect1info>
    <copyright>
      <year>1999</year>
      <holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
    </copyright>
    <author>
      <firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
      <surname>Yuen</surname></author>
    <address><email>zana@webwynk.net</email></address>
  </sect1info>-->

  <title>Thirteen</title>

  <para>Γράφτηκε από τη Rosanna Yuen</para>

          <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


  <informaltable>
    <tgroup cols="2">
      <tbody>
	<row>
	  <entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
	  <entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Μάνα</entry>
	  <entry>
	    Top left pile.  The rest of the deck is placed here after
	    dealing the Tableau.  Cards are turned over one at a time to
	    Waste.  No redeals.
	  </entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Σωρός</entry>
	  <entry>
	    To be taken from Stock.  The top card is available
	    for play.
	  </entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
	  <entry>
	    Deal face down seven overlapping rows starting with one card
	    on the first row, increasing by one per row and staggering
	    the piles as to achieve a pyramid.  Flip bottom row.
	  </entry>
	</row>
      </tbody>
    </tgroup>
  </informaltable>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

  <para>Απομάκρυνση όλων των φύλλων.</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

  <para>
    All exposed cards in the pyramid are available for play.  Kings can
    be removed singly.  All other cards can be removed in pairs that add
    up to thirteen with Aces equal to 1, Jacks equal to 11, and Queens
    equal to 12.
  </para>
  <para>
    Cards can be flipped singly from the Stock to the Waste.  The top
    card is available for play either with the available cards in the
    pyramid or with the card below.  There is no redeal.
  </para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

  <para>Κάθε φύλλο που απομακρύνεται αντιστοιχεί σε 1 βαθμό.</para>
  <para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 52</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

  <para>
    Every pyramid needs a strong foundation.  Get rid of the lower cards
    first, with an eye out to try to expose as many cards as possible.
  </para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Thumb_And_Pouch"><!--<sect1info>
    <copyright>
      <year>1999</year>
      <holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
    </copyright>
    <author>
      <firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
      <surname>Yuen</surname>
    </author>
    <address><email>zana@webwynk.net</email></address>
  </sect1info>-->

  <title>Thumb and Pouch</title>

  <para>Γράφτηκε από τη Rosanna Yuen</para>

          <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


  <informaltable>
    <tgroup cols="2">
      <tbody>
	<row>
	  <entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
	  <entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Μάνα</entry>
	  <entry>Η στοίβα πάνω αριστερά. Όταν ολοκληρωθεί η μοιρασιά, τα υπόλοιπα φύλλα τοποθετούνται εδώ. Τα φύλλα της μάνας ανοίγουν ένα ένα και τοποθετούνται στο σωρό. Ο παίκτης δύο επιπλέον μοιρασιές.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Σωρός</entry>
	  <entry>Προέρχονται από τη μάνα. Μπορείτε να παίξετε το πάνω φύλλο.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Βάσεις</entry>
	  <entry>Οι τέσσερις στοίβες πάνω δεξιά. Τα φύλλα τοποθετούνται ανά φυλή και σε αύξουσα σειρά, από τον Άσσο στο Ρήγα. Σε κάθε βάση, το πάνω φύλλο μπορεί να παιχθεί στο ταμπλό.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
	  <entry>
	    Seven piles.  Deal card face up in first pile.  Place one
	    card face down on all other piles.  Place one card face up
	    on next pile followed by one card face down on all covered
	    piles.  Repeat until there are seven cards in last pile.
	    Tableau can be built down in any suit but own.  Groups of
	    cards can be moved.  Empty piles can be filled by any legal
	    sequence of cards.
	  </entry>
	</row>
      </tbody>
    </tgroup>
  </informaltable>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

  <para>Μετακίνηση όλων των φύλλων στις βάσεις</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

  <para>
    Cards in the Tableau are built down by any suit but own.  Groups of
    cards can be moved.  An empty pile in the Tableau can be filled with
    a any legal sequence of cards.
  </para>
  <para>
    Cards are flipped from the stock to the Waste individually.  Top
    card in Waste is in play.  When Stock is empty, move all cards in
    Waste back to the Stock, maintaining order. You can go through the
    deck three times.
  </para>
  <para>Στις βάσεις τα φύλλα μπαίνουν ανά φυλή και σε αύξουσα σειρά από τον Άσσο στο Ρήγα. Τα φύλλα στις βάσεις δε βγαίνουν από το παιχνίδι. Αν κάνετε διπλό κλικ σε ένα φύλλο, το φύλλο αυτό θα ανέβει στις βάσεις, εφόσον επιτρέπεται η κίνηση.</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

  <para>Κάθε φύλλο που τοποθετείται στις βάσεις αντιστοιχεί σε 1 βαθμό.</para>
  <para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 52</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

  <para>
    Brute force may not always work, but in this case it probably will.
  </para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Treize"><!--<sect1info>
		<copyright>
			<year>2001</year>
			<holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
		</copyright>
		<author>
			<firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
			<surname>Yuen</surname>
		</author>
		<address><email>zana@webwynk.net</email></address>
	</sect1info>-->

	<title>Treize</title>

	<para>Γράφτηκε από τη Rosanna Yuen</para>

	        <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


	<informaltable>
		<tgroup cols="2">
			<tbody>
	<row>
		<entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
		<entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Μάνα</entry>
		<entry>
			Top left pile.  The rest of the deck is placed here after
			dealing the Tableau.  Cards are turned over one at a time to Waste.  No
			redeals.
		</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Σωρός</entry>
		<entry>
			To be taken from Stock.  Top card and bottom card available for play.
		</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
		<entry>
			Deal cards face up in seven overlapping rows starting with one card on the
			first row, increasing by one per row and staggering the piles as to
			achieve a pyramid.
		</entry>
	</row>
			</tbody>
		</tgroup>
	</informaltable>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

	<para>Απομάκρυνση όλων των φύλλων.</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

	<para>
		All exposed cards in the pyramid are available for play.  Kings can be
		removed singly.  All other cards can be removed in pairs that add up to
		treize with Aces equal to 1, Jacks equal to 11, and Queens equal to 12.
	</para>
	<para>
		Cards can be flipped singly from the Stock to the Waste.  Top and bottom
		cards are available for play either by themselves or with the available
		cards in the pyramid.  The top card of the Waste can also be played with
		the second card on the Waste.  There is no redeal.
	</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

	<para>Κάθε φύλλο που απομακρύνεται αντιστοιχεί σε 1 βαθμό.</para>
	<para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 52</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

	<para>
		This game is easier to win than Thirteen.  This is because you can plan
		ahead and avoid blocks by strategic play.
	</para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Triple_Peaks"><!--<sect1info>
		<copyright>
			<year>2005</year>
			<holder>Richard Hoelscher</holder>
		</copyright>
		<author>
			<firstname>Richard</firstname>
			<surname>Hoelscher</surname>
		</author>
		<address><email>rah@rahga.com</email></address>
	</sect1info>-->

	<title>Triple Peaks</title>

	<para>Written by Richard Hoelscher</para>

	        <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


	<informaltable>
		<tgroup cols="2">
			<tbody>
	<row>
		<entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
		<entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Μάνα</entry>
		<entry>
			Top left pile.  The rest of the deck is placed here after
			dealing the Tableau.  Cards are turned over one at a time to Waste.
			No redeals.
		</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Σωρός</entry>
		<entry>
			All play is on the Waste pile.  Cards faced down are not part of 
			the current scoring run.
		</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
		<entry>
			Deal 18 cards face down in the form of three triangles, with three
			rows in each triangle, increasing with one card in the first row 
			to three in the last. Connect the triangles by dealing another 10 
			cards face up in the bottom row. End cards of each row should overlap
			the end cards of the row above, and interior cards should overlap
			two adjacent cards of that row.
		</entry>
	</row>
			</tbody>
		</tgroup>
	</informaltable>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

	<para>
		Remove all cards from the Tableau.
	</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

	<para>
		Exposed cards in the Tableau are available for play. Build on the top card of
		Waste with cards ranked immediately above or below it from the Tableau, 
		regardless of suit. Aces are ranked both above Kings and below Deuces.
	</para>
	<para>
		Tableau cards are made available when not covered by other cards.
	</para>
	<para>
		Cards can be flipped singly from Stock to the top of Waste.
	</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Options</title>

	<para>
		Multiplier Scoring: Points double for every card played in a run. A run
		of five cards will score 1, 2, 4, 16, and 32 points, for a total of 55 
		points. Bonuses are worth 25 points. No points are deducted for playing
		a card from the stock to the waste.
	</para>
	<para>
		Progressive Rounds: After all cards have been cleared from the tableu, 
		a new round begins. The score from the last round carries over into the
		new round.
	</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

	<para>
		The score for each card played is equal to the number of cards your have
		played since the last card flipped from the Stock to the Waste. The longer
		the run, the higher your score.
	</para>
	<para>
		5 points are deducted when you flip a card from Stock to Waste. Each 
		triangle peak cleared will give a 15 point bonus, and an additional 15
		points are awarded when all the cards have been cleared from the Tableau. 
	</para>
	<para>
		Maximum possible score for a single round: 466
	</para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Union_Square"><!--<sect1info>
		<copyright>
			<year>1999</year>
			<holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
		</copyright>
		<author>
			<firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
			<surname>Yuen</surname>
		</author>
		<address><email>rwsy@mit.edu</email></address>
	</sect1info>-->

	<title>Union Square</title>

	<para>Γράφτηκε από τη Rosanna Yuen</para>

	        <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


	<informaltable>
		<tgroup cols="2">
			<tbody>
	<row>
		<entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
		<entry>Δύο τράπουλες</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Μάνα</entry>
		<entry>
			Top left pile.  The rest of the deck is placed here after
			dealing the Tableau.  Cards are turned over one at a time to Waste.  No
			redeals.
		</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Σωρός</entry>
		<entry>Προέρχονται από τη μάνα. Μπορείτε να παίξετε το πάνω φύλλο.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
		<entry>
			Deal face up a four by four grid for the Tableau, making sixteen piles.
			Top card of each pile available for play.
		</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Βάσεις</entry>
		<entry>
			Four piles on the right.  Foundation piles are built by suit from Ace to
			King, then King back to Ace.
		</entry>
	</row>
			</tbody>
		</tgroup>
	</informaltable>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

	<para>
		Move all cards to Foundations.
	</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

	<para>
		Cards in Tableau can be built either up or down in suit.  However, each
		pile must follow only one of these rules.  For example, if a Tableau
		pile has a three of clubs over a two of clubs, one can only play a four
		of clubs on this pile.  Any available card can be played on to an empty
		Tableau pile.
	</para>
	<para>
		Foundation piles are to be built in suit from Ace to King, followed by
		another King, then back down to Ace, giving 26 cards per pile when game
		is won.  Cards in Foundation piles are no longer in play.
	</para>
	<para>
		Cards can be flipped singly from the Stock to the Waste.  Top card of
		Waste is available for play.  There is no redeal.
	</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

	<para>
		Each card moved to Foundations scores one point.
	</para>
	<para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 104</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

	<para>
		A string of beads can be added to from both ends, and so should your
		piles.  Make good use of any empty slots to append cards.  With a little
		perseverance, this game can be a lot of fun!
	</para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Valentine"><!--<sect1info>
		<copyright>
			<year>2001</year>
			<holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
		</copyright>
		<author>
			<firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
			<surname>Yuen</surname>
		</author>
		<address><email>zana@webwynk.net</email></address>
	</sect1info>-->

	<title>Valentine</title>

  <para>Γράφτηκε από τη Rosanna Yuen</para>

          <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


  <informaltable>
    <tgroup cols="2">
      <tbody>
	<row>
		<entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
		<entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Μάνα</entry>
		<entry>Η στοίβα πάνω αριστερά. Εδώ τοποθετούνται τα χαρτιά που απομένουν μετά το μοίρασμα.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Σωρός</entry>
		<entry>
			Top right pile. Can only hold one card.
		</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
		<entry>
			Four piles. One card is dealt in each slot at the beginning
			of the game. Redealing from the stock moves all cards
			currently in the Tableau to the bottom of the Stock
			slot.
		</entry>
	</row>
      </tbody>
    </tgroup>
  </informaltable>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

  <para>
    Have all the cards in the Tableau, each slot containing Ace to King
    of one suit. Avoid going crazy achieving this.
  </para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

  <para>
    If any two cards dealt on to the Tableau are the same suit and in
    sequence, place the lower card on to the higher. Aces are low,
    Kings are high and sequence does not wrap.  Click on the Stock
    to fill in the empty slots that are made.
  </para>
  <para>
    When no plays can be made in the Tableau, click on the Stock to
    deal a card on to the Waste. If this card can be played on to any
    of the Tableau piles, do so. Repeat this process until there are no
    more moves in the Tableau or from the Waste.
  </para>
  <para>
    At this point, clicking on the Foundation again moves all the cards
    in the Tableau back to the bottom of the Stock.  The card in the
    Waste is put in the first Tableau pile and the rest of the Tableau
    is filled with one card to each pile from the Stock.
  </para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

  <para>
    There is no scoring in this game.
  </para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

  <para>
    A great game for killing time, Valentine really has no strategy,
    unless the strategy is to play it instead of doing other, more
    important things, like going to bed.
  </para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Westhaven"><!--<sect1info>
		<copyright>
			<year>1999</year>
			<holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
		</copyright>
		<author>
			<firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
			<surname>Yuen</surname>
		</author>
		<address><email>rwsy@mit.edu</email></address></sect1info>-->

	<title>Westhaven</title>

	<para>Γράφτηκε από τη Rosanna Yuen</para>

	        <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


	<informaltable>
		<tgroup cols="2">
			<tbody>
	<row>
		<entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
		<entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Μάνα</entry>
		<entry>
			Top left pile.  The rest of the deck is placed here after
			dealing the Tableau.  Cards are turned over one at a time to Waste.  No
			redeals.
		</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Σωρός</entry>
		<entry>Προέρχονται από τη μάνα. Μπορείτε να παίξετε το πάνω φύλλο.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Βάσεις</entry>
		<entry>
			Four piles on top row.  To be built up in suit from Ace to King.
		</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
		<entry>
			Ten piles of three cards each, with the last row of cards face up.
		</entry>
	</row>
			</tbody>
		</tgroup>
	</informaltable>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

	<para>Μετακίνηση όλων των φύλλων στις βάσεις</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

	<para>
		Cards in Tableau are built down by alternate color.  The top card or the
		complete face up portion of each pile is available for play.  Empty
		piles can be filled with any available card or group of cards.
	</para>
	<para>
		Foundation piles are to be built up in suit from Ace to King.  Cards in
		Foundation are no longer in play.
	</para>
	<para>
		Cards are flipped singly from Stock to Waste.  Top card of Waste pile is
		always available for play.  There are no redeals.
	</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

	<para>
		Each card moved to Foundation scores one point.
	</para>
	<para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 52</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

	<para>
		Caution is for those who actually have money at stake.  Live
		dangerously.  Make any moves you can, as chance is on your side.
	</para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Whitehead"><!--<sect1info>
    <copyright>
      <year>2001</year>
      <holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
    </copyright>
    <author>
      <firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
      <surname>Yuen</surname>
    </author>
    <address><email>zana@webwynk.net</email></address>
  </sect1info>-->

  <title>Whitehead</title>

  <para>Γράφτηκε από τη Rosanna Yuen</para>

          <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


  <informaltable>
    <tgroup cols="2">
      <tbody>
	<row>
	  <entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
	  <entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Μάνα</entry>
	  <entry>
	    Top left pile.  The rest of the deck is placed here after
	    dealing on to the Tableau.  Cards are turned over one at a
	    time to Waste.  No redeals.
	  </entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Σωρός</entry>
	  <entry>Προέρχονται από τη μάνα. Μπορείτε να παίξετε το πάνω φύλλο.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Βάσεις</entry>
	  <entry>Οι τέσσερις στοίβες πάνω δεξιά. Τα φύλλα τοποθετούνται ανά φυλή και σε αύξουσα σειρά, από τον Άσσο στο Ρήγα. Σε κάθε βάση, το πάνω φύλλο μπορεί να παιχθεί στο ταμπλό.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
	  <entry>
	    Seven piles.  Deal all cards face up such that there is one
	    card in the first pile, two in the second pile, ending with
	    seven in the seventh pile.
	  </entry>
	</row>
      </tbody>
    </tgroup>
  </informaltable>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

  <para>Μετακίνηση όλων των φύλλων στις βάσεις</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

  <para>
    Cards in the Tableau are built down by same color.  Builds of cards
    that are the same suit and in sequence can be moved as a unit.
    Empty Tableau slots can be filled with any card or build of cards.
  </para>
  <para>Η μάνα ανοίγει τα φύλλα της ένα ένα και τα τοποθετεί στο σωρό. Μπορείτε να παίξετε το πρώτο φύλλο του σωρού. Αν τελειώσουν τα φύλλα της μάνας, δεν μπορεί να γίνει νέα μοιρασιά.</para>
  <para>Στις βάσεις τα φύλλα μπαίνουν ανά φυλή και σε αύξουσα σειρά από τον Άσσο στο Ρήγα. Τα φύλλα στις βάσεις δε βγαίνουν από το παιχνίδι. Αν κάνετε διπλό κλικ σε ένα φύλλο, το φύλλο αυτό θα ανέβει στις βάσεις, εφόσον επιτρέπεται η κίνηση.</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

  <para>Κάθε φύλλο που τοποθετείται στις βάσεις αντιστοιχεί σε 1 βαθμό.</para>
  <para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 52</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

  <para>
    Empty Tableau slots are a prized commodity in this game.  Sometimes
    keeping them around until you need them is a very good idea.
  </para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Will_O_The_Wisp"><!--<sect1info>
    <copyright>
      <year>2001</year>
      <holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
    </copyright>
    <author>
      <firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
      <surname>Yuen</surname>
    </author>
    <address><email>zana@webwynk.net</email></address>
  </sect1info>-->

  <title>Will o' the Wisp</title>

  <para>Γράφτηκε από τη Rosanna Yuen</para>

          <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


  <informaltable>
    <tgroup cols="2">
      <tbody>
	<row>
	  <entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
	  <entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Μάνα</entry>
	  <entry>
	    Top left pile.
	    When clicked, deal a card on to every Tableau pile except for the last
      deal which places one card on each of the first three piles.
	  </entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Βάσεις</entry>
	  <entry>
	    Four piles top right.
	  </entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
	  <entry>
	    Seven piles on the bottom.  Deal two cards face down and one
	    card face up on every pile.
	  </entry>
	</row>
      </tbody>
    </tgroup>
  </informaltable>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

  <para>
    Create four piles of thirteen cards each built down in suit and sequence.
  </para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

  <para>
    Tableau piles can be built down regardless of suit.  Builds of
    cards in sequence and in the same suit can by moved as a unit.
    Empty Tableau piles can be filled with any card or build of cards.
  </para>
  <para>
    Each Tableau pile must be filled before any deal.  Clicking on the
    Stock will deal a card on to every Tableau pile except for the last
    deal which places one card on each of the first three piles.
  </para>
  <para>
    A build of all thirteen cards in a suit may be moved on to a
    Foundation pile.  Cards in the Foundation are no longer in play.
  </para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

  <para>
    Every pair of cards in suit and sequence scores one point.
  </para>
  <para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 48</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

  <para>
    Try to keep a Tableau pile empty whenever possible to create a swap
    space for moving around cards.
  </para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Yield"><!--<sect1info>
		<copyright>
			<year>2001</year>
			<holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
		</copyright>
		<author>
			<firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
			<surname>Yuen</surname>
		</author>
		<address><email>zana@webwynk.net</email></address>
	</sect1info>-->

	<title>Yield</title>

	<para>Γράφτηκε από τη Rosanna Yuen</para>

	        <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


	<informaltable>
		<tgroup cols="2">
			<tbody>
	<row>
		<entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
		<entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Μάνα</entry>
		<entry>
			Top left pile.  The rest of the deck is placed here after
			dealing the Tableau.  Cards are turned over one at a time to Waste.  No
			redeals.
		</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Σωρός</entry>
		<entry>
			To be taken from Stock.  Top card and bottom card available for play.
		</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
		<entry>
			Deal cards face up in seven overlapping rows starting with seven cards on the
			first row, decreasing by one per row and staggering the piles as to
			achieve an inverted pyramid.
		</entry>
	</row>
			</tbody>
		</tgroup>
	</informaltable>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

	<para>Απομάκρυνση όλων των φύλλων.</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

	<para>
		All exposed cards in the pyramid are available for play.  Kings can be
		removed singly.  All other cards can be removed in pairs that add up to
		treize with Aces equal to 1, Jacks equal to 11, and Queens equal to 12.
	</para>
	<para>
		Cards can be flipped singly from the Stock to the Waste.  Top and bottom
		cards are available for play either by themselves or with the available
		cards in the pyramid.  The top card of the Waste can also be played with
		the second card on the Waste.  There is no redeal.
	</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

	<para>Κάθε φύλλο που απομακρύνεται αντιστοιχεί σε 1 βαθμό.</para>
	<para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 52</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

	<para>
		Removing the bottom of the inverted pyramid is the hard part.  Once that
		is achieved, it is sometimes better to remove cards from the Waste than
		the inverted pyramid, as there are more cards in play there.
	</para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Yukon"><!--<sect1info>
		<copyright>
			<year>1998</year>
			<holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
		</copyright>
		<author>
			<firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
			<surname>Yuen</surname>
		</author>
		<address><email>rwsy@mit.edu</email></address>
	</sect1info>-->

	<title>Yukon</title>

	<para>Γράφτηκε από τη Rosanna Yuen</para>

	        <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


	<informaltable>
		<tgroup cols="2">
			<tbody>
	<row>
		<entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
		<entry>Απλή τράπουλα</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Βάσεις</entry>
		<entry>
			Four piles on left.  To be built up in suit from Ace to King.
		</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
		<entry>
			Seven piles.  Deal card face up in first pile.  Place one
			card face down on all other piles.  Place one card face up on next
			pile followed by one card face down on all covered piles.  Repeat
			until there are seven cards in last pile.  Deal the rest of the cards
			face up on the second to seventh piles.  To be built down in opposite
			color.
		</entry>
	</row>
			</tbody>
		</tgroup>
	</informaltable>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

	<para>Μετακίνηση όλων των φύλλων στις βάσεις</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

	<para>
		Cards in Tableau are built down in opposite color.  Groups of cards
		can be moved regardless of sequence.  A faced-down card is flipped
		when it is unburied.  An empty pile in the Tableau can be filled with
		a King or a group of cards with a King on the bottom.
	</para>
	<para>
		Foundations are built up in suit from Ace to King.  Cards in
		Foundations are no longer in play.
	</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

	<para>Κάθε φύλλο που τοποθετείται στις βάσεις αντιστοιχεί σε 1 βαθμό.</para>
	<para>Μέγιστη δυνατή βαθμολογία: 52</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

	<para>
		Try and uncover as many cards as early on as possible.  Doing so will
		greatly aid your quest to conquer yukon.
	</para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="Zebra"><!--<sect1info>
		<copyright>
			<year>1999</year>
			<holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
		</copyright>
		<author>
			<firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
			<surname>Yuen</surname>
		</author>
		<address><email>rwsy@mit.edu</email></address>
	</sect1info>-->

	<title>Zebra</title>

	<para>Γράφτηκε από τη Rosanna Yuen</para>

	        <sect2><title>Διάταξη</title>


	<informaltable>
		<tgroup cols="2">
			<tbody>
	<row>
		<entry>Τύπος τράπουλας</entry>
		<entry>Δύο τράπουλες</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Μάνα</entry>
		<entry>
			Top left pile.  The rest of the deck is placed here after
			dealing the Tableau.  Cards are turned over one at a time to Waste.  One
			redeal.
		</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Σωρός</entry>
		<entry>Προέρχονται από τη μάνα. Μπορείτε να παίξετε το πάνω φύλλο.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Βάσεις</entry>
		<entry>
			Eight piles on top right.  Place the eight Aces on to these piles to
			begin the Foundations.  The Foundations are to be built up in alternate
			color up to Kings.  Cards in Foundations are no longer in play.
		</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Ταμπλό</entry>
		<entry>
			Eight piles below Foundations.  Deal a card to each Tableau pile to
			start.  Tableau piles are to be built down by alternate color.  Only the
			top card of each pile is available for play.  Empty spaces are
			immediately filled from the Waste, or if the Waste is empty, from the
			Stock.
		</entry>
	</row>
			</tbody>
		</tgroup>
	</informaltable>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στόχος</title>

	<para>
		Move all cards on to Foundation piles.
	</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Κανόνες</title>

	<para>
		Cards in Tableau are built down by alternate color.  Only the top card
		of each pile is in play.  However, to facilitate play, a whole pile can
		be moved to an appropriate Foundation with one drag.  Double clicking on
		a pile will move the top card to an appropriate Foundation pile if
		possible.
	</para>
	<para>
		Spaces in Tableau are automatically filled from the Waste, or if Waste
		is empty, from the Stock.
	</para>
	<para>
		Stock is dealt on to Waste singly.  Top card of Waste is available for
		play.  There is one redeal.
	</para>
	<para>
		Foundations are built up by alternate color from Aces to Kings.  Cards
		in Foundation piles are no longer in play.
	</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Βαθμολογία</title>

	<para>Κάθε φύλλο που τοποθετείται στις βάσεις αντιστοιχεί σε 1 βαθμό.</para>
	<para>
		Maximum possible score:  96
	</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Στρατηγική</title>

	<para>
		There are very few second chances in the real world, so use them when
		you find them.  Chances are you will need to use the second deal to win
		this game.  Remember where the key cards are and you'll be glad you
		did.
	</para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>

</chapter>

<chapter id="glossary">
	<title>Glossary</title>

	<para>
		Author's note:  These definitions are meant as a guideline only.  See
		individual game rules as any game has the right to redefine or modify
		the rules to make it fun.
	</para>

	<variablelist>
		<varlistentry id="basecard"><term>Base card</term>
			<listitem><para>
				The first card dealt into a foundation pile. Other foundations usually
				have to start with a card of this rank.  See: Foundation
			</para></listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry id="buildbyaltcolor"><term>Build by alternate color</term>
			<listitem><para>
				Building by placing a card on to another card of the opposite color is
				permitted.  Example: Placing a Diamond on a Spade is good, but placing a
				Diamond on a Heart is not.
			</para></listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry id="buildbysuitbutown"><term>Build by any suit but own</term>
			<listitem><para>
				Building by placing a card on to another card of any suit but the suit
				of the original card is permitted.  Example: Placing a Diamond on a
				Heart is good, but placing a Heart on a Heart is not.
			</para></listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry id="buildbycolor"><term>Build by color</term>
			<listitem><para>
				Building by placing a card on to another card of the same color is
				permitted.  Example: Placing a Diamond on a Heart is good, but Placing a
				Diamond on a Club is not.
			</para></listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry id="buildregardlessofsuit"><term>Build regardless of suit</term>
			<listitem><para>
				It's all good.
			</para></listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry id="buildbysuit"><term>Build by suit</term>
			<listitem><para>
				Building by placing a card on to another card of the same suit is
				permitted.  Example: Placing a Spade on a Spade is good, but placing a
				Spade on a Club is not.
			</para></listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry id="builddown"><term>Build down</term>
			<listitem><para>
				Building by placing a card of a lower rank on to a card of a higher
				rank is permitted.  Usually implies a difference of only one ranking
				between the two cards.  Example: Placing a 10 on a Jack is good, but
				placing a 10 on a 9 is not.
			</para></listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry id="builddownbystar"><term>Build down by *</term>
			<listitem><para>
				Building by placing a card of a lower rank on to a card of a higher rank
				by * is permitted.  Example: If * is 2, placing a 10 on a Queen is good,
				but placing a 10 on a Jack is not.
			</para></listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry id="buildup"><term>Build up</term>
			<listitem><para>
				Building by placing a card of a higher rank on to a card of a lower
				rank is permitted.  Usually implies a difference of only one ranking
				between the two cards.  Example: Placing a Queen on a Jack is good, but
				placing a Queen on a King is not.
			</para></listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry id="buildupbystar"><term>Build up by *</term>
			<listitem><para>
				Building by placing a card of a higher rank on to a card of a lower rank
				by * is permitted.  Example: If * is 2, placing a 10 on an 8 is good,
				but placing a 10 on a 9 is not.
			</para></listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry id="buildupordown"><term>Build up or down</term>
			<listitem><para>
				Building by placing a card on to a card of one higher or one lower rank
				is permitted.  Example: Placing a Jack on a Queen or a 10 is good, but
				placing a 10 on a Queen is not.
			</para></listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry id="building"><term>Building</term>
			<listitem><para>
				The ability to place a card (or group of cards) on another card.  In
				regards to rank, you can build up, build down, or build up/down by *.
				In regards to suit/color, you can build by suit, build by color, build
				by alternate color, build by any suit but own, or build regardless of
				suit.  Note that all games that build will follow two of these rules,
				one from each list.
			</para></listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry id="deck"><term>Deck</term>
			<listitem><para>
				The set of cards used.  Most games use a Standard deck, but games that
				use a Double deck, a Joker deck, or a Stripped deck are not uncommon.
			</para></listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry id="doubledeck"><term>Double deck</term>
			<listitem><para>
				A deck of cards consisting of two Standard decks making a total of 104 cards.
			</para></listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry id="foudation"><term>Βάσεις</term>
			<listitem><para>
				If a game has a foundation, the game is usually won by placing all the
				cards in the foundation pile(s).
			</para></listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry id="jokerdeck"><term>Joker deck</term>
			<listitem><para>
				A deck of cards consisting of a Standard deck and two jokers making a
				total of 54 cards.
			</para></listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry id="pile"><term>Pile</term>
			<listitem><para>
				A designated area where cards can exist.
			</para></listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry id="rank"><term>Rank</term>
			<listitem><para>
				The value of the card. Numbered cards usually have the rank of the
				associated number.  Aces can either be high or low.  If high, aces are
				ranked 1.  If low, aces are ranked as 14.  J, Q, and K are usually
				ranked 11, 12, and 13 respectively.  However, some games may rank these
				cards as 10.  In such a case, a high ace might be ranked as 11.
			</para></listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry id="reserve"><term>Ρεζέρβα</term>
			<listitem><para>
				Cards in the reserve are usually available to play anywhere.  Usually
				cannot be built on.
			</para></listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry id="slot"><term>Slot</term>
			<listitem><para>
				See Pile.
			</para></listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry id="standarddeck"><term>Standard deck</term>
			<listitem><para>
				A 52 card poker deck. There are four suits of thirteen cards each.  Each
				suit contains an Ace, 2 through 10, Jack, Queen, and King.  These suits
				are usually Clubs, Spades, Hearts and Diamonds.  These suits can be
				grouped into two colors, usually black and red.  The Clubs and the
				Spaces are black while the Hearts and the Diamonds are red.  AisleRiot
				allows the possibility of using different decks.  In this case, the new
				colors and/or suits are substituted into this paradigm.
			</para></listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry id="stock"><term>Μάνα</term>
			<listitem><para>
				The remainder of the deck after all the original cards have been
				dealt and are usually kept faced down.
			</para></listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry id="suit"><term>Suit</term>
			<listitem><para>
				Four different kinds in a Standard deck. Usually Clubs, Spades, Hearts,
				and Diamonds.
			</para></listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry id="tableau"><term>Ταμπλό</term>
			<listitem><para>
				The playing field, where the main action occurs. Usually allows building.
			</para></listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry id="waste"><term>Σωρός</term>
			<listitem><para>
				A stack of cards face up, usually next to the Stock.  Top card usually in play.
			</para></listitem>
		</varlistentry>
	</variablelist>
</chapter>


</book>
